<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<galaw><metadata><coretitle>Acts of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</coretitle><creator>Georgia</creator><subject>Law, Georgia</subject><description>Georgia. Acts and resolutions of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</description><publisher>LOUISVILLE.</publisher><contributors><contributor /></contributors><date>18060600</date><type /><format /><identifier /><source /><language>English</language><relation /><coverage /><rights /></metadata>
<document initial.page="(4)">
<page id="GA1806.2.P1" />

<titlepage><title><b>ACTS</b><br set="CENTER"><b>OF THE</b><br set="CENTER"><i>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</i><br set="CENTER"><b>OF THE</b><br set="CENTER"><b>STATE OF GEORGIA</b><br set="CENTER"><b><i>[Illegible Text] AT LOUISVILLEAT AN EXTRA</i></b><br set="CENTER"><b><i>SESSION IN</i> <i>JUNE</i>, 1806.</b><br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></br></br></br></title><sessiondate>18060600</sessiondate><pubinfo><p><i>LOUISVILLE.</i> <i>Printed by</i> [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text]</p><p>PRINTER TO THE STATE.</p><p>1806.</p></pubinfo></titlepage>

<page id="GA1806.2.P2" />

<body><part><title><b>ACTS</b><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><i>STATE OF GEORGIA.</i><br set="CENTER" /></br></br></title><law id="L1806V2N001" initial.page="(4)"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To dispose of, and distribute the late cession of Lands, obtained from the Creek Nation, by the United States, in a treaty concluded at the City of Washington, on the fourteenth day of November, in the year one thousand eight hundred and five.</fulltitle><p>SEC. 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same it is hereby enacted,</i> That the Territory lately acquired from the Creek Nation, as described by the articles of convention made between Henry Dearborn, on the part of the United States, and Uche Hargo, William M`Intosh, Tuskenehau Chapco, Tuskenehau Enchau Thlucco, of the Creek Nation of Indians, duly authorized and empowered by the said Nation, shall be laid off in the following manner, viz.The dividing line between the counties of Baldwin and Wilkinson, shall be extended south forty-five degrees west to the Ocmulgee river; and all that part of the lately acquired Territory lying above said line

<page id="GA1806.2.P3" no="GA1806.2.(4)" />

shall be attached to, and considered [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] part of the county of Baldwin; and all that part lying below said line, shall be attached to, and considered a part of the county of Wilkinson, except the reserve made in the aforesaid articles of convention.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the said Territory shall be divided into thirty-eight districts, as nearly equal as they can be conveniently made by running parallel lines south forty-five degrees west, and others intersecting them at right angles. Which said lines shall be run by such person or persons as the Surveyor General may appoint, not being a District Surveyor.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the land contained in the several districts, shall be divided by lines running parallel with the dividing lines of districts, and by others crossing them at right angles, so as to form tracts of forty-five chains square, containing two hundred two and an half [Illegible Text] each, plainly and distinctly marked in a manner different from the mode heretofore prescribed for marking lines in this state, to be pointed out by the Surveyor-General.</p><p>SEC. 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the fractional parts of surveys, which may be created by the natural or artificial boundaries of said Territory, shall be set [Illegible Text]

<page id="GA1806.2.P4" no="GA1806.2.(5)" />

for the redemption of the public debt under the direction of a future Legislature.</p><p>SEC. 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That a number of Surveyors equal to the number of districts, shall be appointed by joint ballot of the Legislature, in one general ticket; and the person having the highest number of votes shall be entitled to first choice of districts, and in that order agreeably to the number of votes each Surveyor so appointed, may [Illegible Text]</p><p>SEC. 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That if two or more persons shall have an equal number of votes, then and in that case it shall be determined by [Illegible Text] under the super-intendence of the Surveyor-General, which person or persons shall be entitled to choice of districts.</p><p>SEC. 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That no ticket shall be counted, unless it be filled with the number of names from among the candidates, equal to the number of districts.</p><p>SEC. 8. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That if any person shall offer and be elected a surveyor, who shall hereafter be found deficient in the qualification necessary to a due execution of the duties required by this act, it shall be deemed a forfeiture of his [Illegible Text] and himself and securities immediately liable therefor.</p><p>SEC. 9. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the respective [Illegible Text] shall give bond in the penalty of ten

<page id="GA1806.2.P5" no="GA1806.2.(6)" />

thousand dollars, to his Excellency the Governor, and his successors in office, with such security as he, or a majority of the Justices of the Inferior Courts of the respective counties where the said surveyors may reside, shall approve of, for the faithful discharge of the trust reposed in them, and duties required of them by this act, which bond shall be taken by the Governor or the [Illegible Text] Justices, and deposited in the Executive Office.</p><p>SEC. 10. <i>And be it further enacted, by the authority aforesaid,</i> That it shall be the duty of the surveyors appointed in pursuance of this act, to make the surveys of the districts to which they may be appointed in their own proper person, to mark or cause to be marked, plainly and distinctly upon trees, if practicable, otherwise stakes may suffice, all lines which he may be required to run, for the purpose of making the surveys in their respective districts immediately after the boundary and district lines shall have been run by the proper authority, to cause all such lines to be measured with all possible exactness, with a half chain, containing two perches of sixteen feet and one half each, consisting of fifty equal links, which shall be adjusted by a standard to be kept for that purpose in the Surveyor General's Officeto take as accurately as possible the meanders of all water courses, which shall form natural boundaries to any of the surveysto note in field books

<page id="GA1806.2.P6" no="GA1806.2.(7)" />

to be kept by them respectively, the [Illegible Text] of the corner and other station trees, which shall be marked and numbered in such manner as the Surveyor-General shall direct; also all rivers, creeks, and other water courses, which may be touched upon or crossed, in running or measuring any of the lines aforesaidtranscripts of which field books after being examined with the originals by the Surveyor-General, and certified and signed on every page by the district surveyor returning the same, shall be deposited in the Surveyor General's Office, there to be preserved as a recordto make a return within ninety days after the running the boundary and district lines as aforesaid, of a map of the district to which they may respectively be appointed, in which shall be correctly delineated, represented and numbered in such order as the Surveyor-General shall prescribe; all surveys within such district, and also, return at the same time, a detached plat of every such survey of land, certified and signed by themwhich plat shall be filed among the other records in the Surveyor-General's Office, and from which a copy shall be made to be annexed to grants, and to conform to such instructions as they may receive from the Surveyor General, from time to time during their continuance in office, and progress in the duties thereof, not militating with this act.</p><p>SEC. 11. <i>And be it further enacted by the</i>

<page id="GA1806.2.P7" no="GA1806.2.(8)" />

<i>authority aforesaid,</i> That the surveyors shall receive two dollars and seventy-five cents for every mile that shall be actually run or surveyed, as a full compensation for all the duty required of them by this act, out of which sum they shall defray the expenses of chain-men, axe-men, and every other expense incidental to the said business; and his Excellency the Governor is hereby authorized and required to issue his warrant on the Treasurer in favour of each and every surveyor, immediately after the boundary and district lines are completed, to the amount of one hundred and fifty dollars, to enable them to proceed without delay to the execution of their duties; for the balance of which by this law they may be entitled, they shall receive a warrant in like manner, on producing to his Excellency the Governor a certificate from the Surveyor-General, setting forth that such surveyor has completed the duties assigned him, and made his return conformably to this act.</p><p>SEC. 12. A<i>nd be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the surveyor or surveyors, who may be employed in dividing the said territory into counties and districts, shall receive the same compensation for each mile run and surveyed, as is allowed by this law for other surveyors, out of which all expenses incidental thereto must be paid, without any additional charge on the state; and his Excellency the Governor is required to grant

<page id="GA1806.2.P8" no="GA1806.2.(9)" />

his warrant on the Treasurer for [Illegible Text] that service, so soon as he shall be advised by the Surveyor-General of its completion.</p><p>SEC. 13. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the said land shall be distributed by lot in the manner following, to wit:After the surveying is completed, and the returns made to the Surveyor-General, his Excellency the Governor shall cause tickets to be made out, whereby all the numbers of surveys in the different districts shall be represented, which tickets shall be put into a box to constitute [Illegible Text], with others to be denominated blanks; of which blanks the number or amount shall be determined by subtracting the number of prizes from the whole number of draws to which the said lottery shall be subject, upon the following principles, that is to say:Every free male white person, twenty-one years of age and upwards, being a citizen of the United States, and an inhabitant of this state, three years immediately preceding the passage of this act, and paid a tax towards the support of Government, (including such as may be absent on lawful business) shall be entitled to one drawevery free male person of like description, having a wife or legitimate child or children under the age of twenty one years, shall be entitled to two drawsall widows with like residence shall be entitled to one drawall free female white persons, [Illegible Text]

<page id="GA1806.2.P9" no="GA1806.2.(10)" />

have arrived to the age of twenty-one years or upwards, who have resided in this state as above, and are unmarried shall be entitled to one drawand all families of orphans residents as aforesaid, under the age of twenty one years, whose father is dead, shall be entitled to one drawand all families of orphans consisting of more than one, who have neither father nor mother living, shall have two draws; but if only one, then such orphan shall be entitled to one draw, which shall be given, in the county and district where the eldest of said orphans or orphan resides:<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That the person or persons who drew a prize or prizes in the late Land Lottery, shall be excluded from any participation in the present Lottery.</p><p>SEC. 14. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That lists of persons entitled to draw in conformity to the provisions of this act, shall be taken and made out within three months from the passing of this act, by such fit and proper person or persons, as the Inferior Court of each county in this State, shall or may appoint for that purpose, not exceeding two to each battalion district, and it is hereby declared to be the duty of the said Inferior Courts respectively, to make such appointments for the purposes aforesaid, to attend at the place of holding Justices Courts in each captain's district, on as many several days as the said Inferior Courts may deem necessary, and appoint for that purposeand

<page id="GA1806.2.P10" no="GA1806.2.(11)" />

it shall be the duty of such person or persons, so appointed, to take and make out such lists, and to give at least ten days notice of such attendance, in the aforesaid captains districts, and the names of persons so entitled to draws, with the number of draws to which they may be entitled, shall be entered in alphabetical order, in a book to be provided for that purpose, which lists or books shall, immediately after the same shall be completed, and transcripts thereof deposited in the office of the clerks of the Superior Courts, be transmitted by the said person or persons to his Excellency the Governor. And the said persons, thus appointed by the Inferior Courts, shall, before they enter upon the execution of the duty required of them by this act, take and subscribe the following oathto wit: I, A. B. do solemnly swear or affirm, (as the case may be) that I will not receive or register any name, except the person giving in, shall first take the oath prescribed by this actSo help me God. Which oath any Justice of the Inferior Court is hereby required to administerand the said person or persons appointed to take the lists as aforesaid, shall administer to all applicants for draws, other than widows, the following oathto wit: I, A. B. do solemnnly swear or affirm, (as the case may be) that I am a citizen of the United States, and have resided in this state three years, immediately preceding the passing of

<page id="GA1806.2.P11" no="GA1806.2.(12)" />

this act; and am now an inhabitant of this district, that I am twenty-one years of age, that I have a wife, child, or children (as the case may be) that I have not given in my name for any draw or draws, in the present contemplated Lottery, in any other part of this state, that I have not drawn a tract of land in the former Lottery, and that the orphan or family of orphans whom I now return, is, or are entitled to a draw or draws, under this act, to the best of my knowledgeSo help me God. And to all widows the following oath: I, A. B. do solemnly swear or affirm, (as the case may be) that I am a widow, that I have resided the three last years in this state, and am now resident in this district, that I have not put in my name for a draw in the present Lottery in any other part of this state, and that I have not drawn land in the former Lottery, to the best of my knowledge and beliefSo help me God.</p><p>SEC. 15. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the person or persons appointed by the Inferior Court to receive and enter the names of applicants entitled to draws in the present Lottery, shall receive for each draw so entered, twelve and an half cents. And his Excellency the Governor is hereby authorized and required forthwith to issue his proclamation, and cause the same to be published in one of the Gazettes of the Cities of Savannah and Augusta, and in those of

<page id="GA1806.2.P12" no="GA1806.2.(13)" />

Louisville, [Illegible Text], Washington and [Illegible Text], setting forth the outlines of this act, and requiring all persons interested therein to exhibit their claims in the counties of their respective residence.</p><p>SEC. 16. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That as soon as the lists of persons entitled to draws in the lottery as aforesaid, shall have been received at the Executive Department, his Excellency the Governor shall cause tickets to be made out for carrying the said lottery into effect, in the following manner, that is to say:Blank pieces of paper, equal in number to the whole number of draws to which the lottery may be subject, and as equal in size as possible, shall be prepared, and on them shall be written separately, the names of the several persons entitled to draws as aforesaid, and the designatory remarks which may appear against each name; and the pieces of paper so written on, shall be deposited in one wheel, and the blanks and prizes on pieces of paper, also as equal in size as possible, shall be deposited in another wheel; and from each wheel, as nearly at the same time as can be, one ticket shall be taken and delivered to the managers appointed to superintend the drawing of said lottery; whose duty it shall be to have the name, if a prize should be drawn against it, entered in a book to be provided for that purpose, and opposite thereto the number of the lot so drawn, and the number of the district,

<page id="GA1806.2.P13" no="GA1806.2.(14)" />

and the name of the county in which the same may be. And that his Excellency the Governor shall cause one month's notice of the day the drawing of the lottery will commence, to be given in the several Gazettes aforesaid.</p><p>SEC. 17. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That where vacancies may happen by death, resignation or otherwise, of any district surveyor or surveyors appointed in pursuance of this act, the Governor is authorized and required to fill up such vacancy or vacancies. And in case any surveyor shall fail to execute the trust reposed in him, either from inattention or otherwise, in such manner as in the opinion of the Governor may render doubtful the finishing the surveys within the time limitted, he shall have power to declare such appointment vacant, and to fill up the same as in case of other vacancies.</p><p>SEC. 18. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the surveyors to be appointed in pursuance of this act, shall before they proceed to the duties of their appointments, take and subscribe the following oath or affirmation, to wit: I, do solemnly swear or affirm, (as the case may be) that I will well and faithfully to the utmost of my skill and abilities discharge the duties of Surveyor for district No., agreeably to the requisitions of this actso help me God. Which oath the Surveyor General is authorized and required to administer. And all chain-men to be employed

<page id="GA1806.2.P14" no="GA1806.2.(15)" />

in pursuance of this act, shall before they enter severally upon their duty, take the following oath or affirmation, to wit: I, do solemnly swear or affirm (as the case may be) that I will to the utmost of my skill and judgment, measure all lines which I shall, or may be employed on as a chain-carrier, as accurately, and with as little deviation from the courses pointed out by the surveyor as possible, and give a true account of the same to the said surveyorSo help me God. Which oath the District-Surveyors are hereby empowered and required to administer.</p><p>SEC. 19. <i>And whereas,</i> it may so happen that persons may have surveyed lands in the aforesaid cession contrary to law, and on which grants may have issued:</p><p><i>Be it therefore enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all such surveys or grants, are hereby declared to be null and void, to all intents and purposes, as though the same had never been made or issued; nor shall any survey or grant in the aforesaid cession, be admitted to a Jury, as evidence of the title to the lands in this act described, except those obtained by virtue and under the authority of this act, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>SEC. 20. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all persons against whose names lands may be drawn in pursuance of this act, shall be entitled to receive grants for the same, vesting in them fee simple titles, on paying into the Treasury of this state, the sum of six

<page id="GA1806.2.P15" no="GA1806.2.(16)" />

dollars per hundred acres, in lieu of all fees of office and other charges for surveying and granting the said lands.<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> that if any person or persons entitled to such grant or grants, shall fail to pay the aforesaid sum, and take out such grant or grants, within twelve months from the completion of the lottery, the same shall revert to, and be vested in this state, and appropriated for the redemption of the public debt.</p><p>SEC. 21. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all returns made contrary to the true intent and meaning of this act, are declared to be fraudulent; and all grants issued in consequence of any draw made in the contemplated lottery, on such fraudulent return, is hereby declared to be null and void, and the land so granted shall revert to, and become the property of this state.</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1806V2N002" initial.page="(16)"><lawtype>An Act</lawtype><fulltitle>To amend an act, entitled An act to organize the Counties of Baldwin and Wilkinson.</fulltitle><p>SEC. 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same it is hereby enacted,</i> That

<page id="GA1806.2.P16" no="GA1806.2.(17)" />

an election shall be held in the county of Baldwin, at the house of George Hill, commonly called Hillsborough, on the second Monday in July next, for the election of Clerks, Sheriff, Coroner and County Surveyor, for the said county; at which election all free white male citizens who have arrived to the age of twenty-one years, who were resident in, and citizens of the said county, on the first day of June, one thousand eight hundred and six, shall be entitled to a vote; which election shall be opened and conducted in the manner prescribed by the act regulating elections in this State.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That it shall be the duty of the Justices of the Inferior Court, Sheriff and Clerk of the Superior Courts of Baldwin and Wilkinson counties, as soon as possible after the said officers are commissioned, to proceed to select the Grand and Petit Jurors for the counties aforesaid; and shall also proceed to draw the said jurors for the next term of the said courts, and cause them to be subp[oelig]naed, at least four days before the meeting of the said courts, anything in the act entitled An act for the better selection and drawing of Grand Jurors for the several counties in this state; or any law usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That this act shall continue and be in force until the

<page id="GA1806.2.P17" no="GA1806.2.(18)" />

first Monday in June next, and no longer,</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1806V2N003" initial.page="(18)"><lawtype>An Act</lawtype><fulltitle>Securing upon certain conditions to Joseph Hill, his heirs, or assigns, the exclusive right to erect a bridge over Ogechee river, at, or near the place where a bridge was heretofore erected, by Wade Hampton and James Gunn.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS by an ordinance passed the sixth day of December, one thousand seven hundred and ninety, the exclusive right to erect a bridge over Great Ogechee river, in the County of Chatham, at the place where the ferry was then kept, was vested in Wade Hampton and James Gunn, Esquires, in which it was also provided, that the said bridge be completed on or before the last day of December, one thousand seven hundred and ninety-two, and re-build when necessary and keep the said bridge in good and sufficient repair: And whereas the said bridge, although built agreeably to the directions of the aforesaid in part recited ordinance, has been suffered to decay, and has long since been entirely insufficient for the purposes intended, and the parties interested therein have wholly neglected to repair the same, by which the intention

<page id="GA1806.2.P18" no="GA1806.2.(19)" />

of the Legislature hath not been carried into effect, and the right intended to be secured to the said Wade Hampton and James Gunn, and their heirs and assigns become void:</p><p>SEC. 1. <i>Be it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That all rights and emoluments vested by the aforesaid ordinance, of the sixth day of December, one thousand seven hundred and ninety, in Wade Hampton and James Gunn, and their heirs or assigns so far as respects the said bridge on Great Ogechee river, in the County of Chatham, and the emoluments arising therefrom, be, and the same are hereby declared to be null and void.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the exclusive privilege of erecting a bridge over the Great Ogechee river, at or near the place where the ferry is now kept, in Chatham county, is hereby fully and absolutely vested in Joseph Hill, who at present resides at, and keeps the said ferry, his heirs and assigns, with the right of building the same either with wood or stone, on the following terms and conditions, viz.That the said Joseph Hill, his heirs or assigns, shall erect the said bridge in a complete and substantial manner, at least sixteen feet in width, and capable of sustaining and passing all carriages in common use,

<page id="GA1806.2.P19" no="GA1806.2.(20)" />

within three years from the date hereof, and re-build the same when necessary, and keep the said bridge in good and sufficient repair forever: To hold the same and all emoluments arising therefrom, to the said Joseph Hill, his heirs and assigns.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said Joseph Hill shall also have to him, his heirs and assigns, one quarter of an acre of the public land, on the south side of the said ferry, to be put and kept in good order and repair, by the said Joseph Hill, within three months after the date hereof, and at all times thereafter, and also one acre of the high land, on the North side, not to include the building called the ferry houseand that the said lots of land shall be allotted and marked off by the surveyor of Chatham county, when required by the said Joseph Hill, his heirs, executors, administrators or assigns, and after ten days notice of the time of making such survey being given to the Inferior Court of Chatham county.</p><p>SEC. 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said Joseph Hill, his heirs, executors, administrators or assigns, be entitled to receive, and may legally demand, during the continuation of the said bridge, a toll equal to that heretofore granted to the said Wade Hampton and James Gunn, and shall and may at all such times as the said bridge may be impassable from accident or decay have the

<page id="GA1806.2.P20" no="GA1806.2.(21)" />

free and quiet enjoyment of the ferry on the same conditions as that of the bridge.</p><p>SEC. 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That it shall not be lawful for any person or persons, at any time or times, to build any bridge or keep any ferry on the said river Great Ogechee, within five miles, either above or below the said bridge, which is hereby exclusively vested in the said Joseph Hill, his heirs, and assigns: <i>Provided,</i> That such bridge shall not be so constructed as to impede the navigation of said riverbut that it shall be a draw-bridge, so as to admit vessels that are usually employed in the said river to pass and re-pass the same.</p><p>SEC. 6. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That this act shall be deemed, adjudged and taken to be a public act, and shall be judicially taken notice of as such, by all Judges, Justices and other persons whatsoever without specially pleading the same.</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1806V2N004" initial.page="(21)"><lawtype>An Act</lawtype><fulltitle>For amending an act, entitled An act to regulate the wharves and shipping in the several ports of this province, and ascertaining the rates of wharfage of shipping and storage, and also the duty of an Harbor-Master for the port of Savannah; and to authorizethe said Harbor-Master to put in force an act, entitled An act to amend an act to prevent persons throwing ballast or rubbish, or falling trees into the rivers and navigable creeks within this province, and for keeping clear the channels of the same.</fulltitle>

<page id="GA1806.2.P21" no="GA1806.2.(22)" />

<p>WHEREAS the increase of the trade of the city of Savannah, and the increased number of shipping entering the port of Savannah, render it necessary to extend the provisions of the second section of the act, entitled An act to regulate the wharves and shipping in the several ports of this province, and ascertaining the rates of wharfage of shipping and storage, and also the duty of an Harbor-Master for the port of Savannah; and to authorize the said Harbor-Master to put in force an act, entitled An act to amend an act to prevent persons throwing ballast or rubbish, or falling trees into the rivers and navigable creeks within this province, and for keeping clear the channels of the same; passed the 12th day of March, 1774:</p><p>SEC. 1. <i>Be it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, all and every vessel lying in the river Savannah, above four mile point, and not loading at any wharf, shall be properly moored, head and stern, as near the north side of the river as possible; and that no vessel not loaded shall

<page id="GA1806.2.P22" no="GA1806.2.(23)" />

be permitted to be, for the purpose of unlading or taking in their loading in the middle of the said river on any pretence whatever; but that whilst taking in her loading, or whilst unloading as aforesaid, in any part of the said river Savannah, above four mile point as aforesaid, all and every vessel shall do the same at some one of the wharves of the said city of Savannah, or five fathom hole, or at any other which may be hereafter built or erected between the said four mile point and the said city of Savannah, as the case may be; and shall be subject to, and liable for the usual and customary rates of wharfage therefor.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that all and every master or commander of any vessel, who shall neglect or refuse to comply with the provisions of this act, shall forfeit and pay the sum of four hundred dollars, to be sued for and recovered by action of debt, in the name of the person choosing to prosecute for the same, in any of the courts of this state having competent jurisdiction; one half whereof shall be applied to the use of the informer, and the other half to be paid to the Commissioners of Pilotage of the port of Savannah, to be applied to the purpose of improving the navigation of the river Savannah.</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1806.2.P23" no="GA1806.2.(24)" />

<law id="L1806V2N005" initial.page="(24)"><lawtype>An Act</lawtype><fulltitle>Entitled an act to make permanent the site for the public buildings in the county of Tattnall, and to appoint commissioners for that purpose.</fulltitle><p>SEC. 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met,</i> That Clement Bryan, William Williams, Shadrack Standley, Jesse Bird, sen. and John Watts, be, and they are hereby appointed Commissioners for fixing on the site of the Court House and Jail in the county of Tattnall; and that they or a majority of them, shall within twelve months after the passing of this act, meet at the present temporary Court House of said county, and fix upon the place for the permanent seat of the public buildings of said county, which shall be as near the centre of said county, as shall be expedient.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the said commissioners or a majority of them, after having agreed upon the permanent site for the public buildings of the county aforesaid, shall have full power and authority to purchase or otherwise procure titles in fee simple, in trust for the aforesaid county, not less than six, or more than one hundred acres of land; and after having made choice of so much of said land as

<page id="GA1806.2.P24" no="GA1806.2.(25)" />

may be thought necessary for the public buildings, to lay off in lots and dispose of the same, as in the judgment of the said commissioners or a majority of them shall think will be most conducive to the interest of said county; and the said commissioners or a majority of them are hereby authorized and requested to contract for, and cause to be built, a Court-House and Jail of such dimension and on such plan as they shall deem most convenient to answer the end proposed, of which said contract for erecting said buildings the said commissioners or a majority of them shall give at least thirty days public notice thereof.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the justices of the Inferior Court of said county shall be, and they are hereby authorized and empowered to lay a tax on the inhabitants and taxable property of the same, which tax shall not exceed one fifth of the general tax, and the monies arising therefrom, or so much thereof as will be sufficient to defray the expense of the public buildings, shall be paid into the hands of the commissioners of the same, to be applied to, and for that express purpose.</p><p>SEC. 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Superior and Inferior Courts shall be held in the two story house at Cox's old mills, in the county aforesaid, until the aforesaid public building shall be completed, and no longer.</p>

<page id="GA1806.2.P25" no="GA1806.2.(26)" />

<p>SEC. 5. <i>Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all laws and parts of Laws, heretofore passed, which militate against this law, be and they are hereby repealed.</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1806V2N006" initial.page="(26)"><lawtype>An Act</lawtype><fulltitle>Entitled an act, to amend an act, entitled an act to amend and continue in force an act to raise a tax for the support of Government, for the year 1805, until the meeting of the next General Assembly, and from thence until the same shall be repealedpassed at Louisville, the 4th of December, 1805.</fulltitle><p>SEC. 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority aforesaid it is hereby enacted,</i> That the tax imposed by the aforesaid act upon the Branch Bank of the United States, at Savannah, be reduced to thirty-one and one quarter cents per hundred dollars, upon the amount of capital of said Bank, on the first day of January last.</p><p><i>Provided,</i> The directors or cashier of the said Bank shall render on oath to the receiver of tax returns a true account of the capital of the said Branch Bank on the said first day of January last, within sixty days from the passing

<page id="GA1806.2.P26" no="GA1806.2.(27)" />

of this act, and in default of making such return, the tax imposed by the above recited act, shall be levied and collected as directed therein.</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>EDWARD TELFAIR, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1806V2N007" initial.page="(27)"><lawtype>An Act</lawtype><fulltitle>To pardon Sally Nelson.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS at a Superior Court held in and for the County of Jackson, for April Term, in the year of our Lord, one thousand eight hundred and six, a certain Sally Nelson was convicted of the crime of <i>Murder,</i> and received sentence of death, to be executed on the Nineteenth day of May, in the said year of our Lord, one thousand eight hundred and sixbut, on the petition of sundry persons, inhabitants of said County, and others, to his Excellency the Governor, praying a respite for the said Sally Nelson, which was granted until the Nineteenth day of December next.</p><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act, the said Sally Nelson, be,

<page id="GA1806.2.P27" no="GA1806.2.(28)" />

and she is hereby declared to be fully, and entirely pardoned, exonerated, and discharged from the pains and penalties of her said conviction.</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1806V2N008" initial.page="(28)"><lawtype>An Act</lawtype><fulltitle>Entitled an act to alter and repeal an act to authorize the Justices of the Inferior Court of Franklin County to levy an extra tax for the purpose of building a Court-House and Jail in said county, and making permanent the seat of the public buildings in said county.</fulltitle><p>SEC. 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior Court for the county of Franklin, are hereby authorized to impose a proportionate extra tax on the inhabitants of said county annually, equal to one half of the general tax, until they shall have collected a sum of money sufficient to defray the expenses of building a Court-House and Jail in said county; which said tax shall be collected in the same manner as the general tax; out of which sum the Tax Collector shall be entitled to receive two and one half per centum for his services; which said tax

<page id="GA1806.2.P28" no="GA1806.2.(29)" />

when collected shall be set apart for the special purposes above mentioned.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the justices aforesaid, shall within four months from the passing of this act, let the said buildings to the lowest bidder, at the place contemplated for the erection of said buildings, which shall be at the town of Carnesville, or the nearest adjacent situation thereto, to which sufficient titles can be obtained.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the law heretofore passed on that subject, be, and the same is hereby repealed</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1806V2N009" initial.page="(29)"><lawtype>An Act</lawtype><fulltitle>To alter and repeal certain parts of an act, entitled An act for the limitation of actions, and for avoiding suits of law, and to repeal the act passed on that subject the 26th of March, 1767, for the better and more effectually quieting men's possessions and estates, and for avoiding suits at law; passed the 7th of December, 1805.</fulltitle><p>SEC. 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same it is hereby enacted,</i> That when any action shall be instituted within the

<page id="GA1806.2.P29" no="GA1806.2.(30)" />

time limitted in the said receited act, and the plaintiff be non-suited, or shall discontinue the same after the term of limitation is expired, that he shall be permitted to renew his action within six months thereafter, for one time only, and not after. And so much of the second section of the said act as is repugnant hereto, be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the above recited act passed in one thousand seven hundred and sixty seven, be, and the same is hereby declared in full force, as to all actions and causes of actions which originated under it. And that the fifth section of the recited act passed in 1805, be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p>ABRAHAM JACKSON, <i>Speaker of</i></p><p><i>the House of Representatives.</i></p><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President</i></p><p><i>of the Senate.</i></p><p>JOHN MILLEDGE, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to June 26, 1806.</approvaldate></law></part></body></document></galaw>
