<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<galaw><metadata><coretitle>Acts of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</coretitle><creator>Georgia</creator><subject>Law, Georgia</subject><description>Georgia. Acts and resolutions of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</description><publisher>Milledgeville:: D. L. RYAN</publisher><contributors><contributor /></contributors><date>18080000</date><type /><format /><identifier /><source /><language>English</language><relation /><coverage /><rights /></metadata>
<document initial.page="1" type="INFERRED">
<page id="GA1808.2.P1" />

<titlepage><title><b>ACTS</b><br set="CENTER"><i>PASSED AT AN EXTRA SESSION</i><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><b><i>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</i></b><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><i>STATE OF</i><br set="CENTER"><b>GEORGIA,</b><br set="CENTER"><i>BEGUN AT MILLEDGEVILLE,</i><br set="CENTER">ON THE 9TH OF MAY;<br set="CENTER">1808.<br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></title><sessiondate>18080000</sessiondate><pubinfo><p><b>ACTS</b></p><p>Passed at an Extra Session of the</p><p>General Assembly of Georgia,</p><p>BEGUN ON THE 9TH MAY,</p><p>1808.</p><p>RYAN, <i>Print.</i></p><p><i>Milledgeville:</i></p><p>PRINTED BY D. L. RYAN</p><p>JUNE 1808</p></pubinfo></titlepage>

<page id="GA1808.2.P2" no="GA1808.2.1" type="INFERRED" />

<toc><title><b>CONTENTS.</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><tocdiv><parttitle /><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to [Illegible Text] the [Illegible Text] of [Illegible Text], and afford them temporary relief.</lawdivtitle><pagenbr>1</pagenbr><lawdivtitle>[Illegible Text] to amend an a[UNK]ct entitled an a[UNK]ct to [Illegible Text] end and consolidate the several [Illegible Text] laws of this state, and to adapt the [Illegible Text] to the a[UNK]ct of the Congress of the [Illegible Text] State.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P4">3</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to authorise the [Illegible Text] and [Illegible Text] of Christ Church in Savannah, to raise by Lotter a certain sum of money, towards rebuilding the said Church, and for other purposes [Illegible Text] thereto.</lawdivtitle><pagenbr>7</pagenbr><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to admit Edwin L. Harris, John B. Posey, Francis D. Cummins. William H. Jackson and Thomas W. [Illegible Text] to plead and pra[UNK]ctice in the several courts of law and equity in this state.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P9">8</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to authorise Aaron Lipham and Thompson Coleman to ere[UNK]ct a bridge over Little river in the county of Wilkes.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P10">9</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to authorise an extra [Illegible Text] of the superior court in Oglethorpe county.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P11">10</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to give further time to the clerks of the superior and inferior courts, and the clerks of the courts of ordinary in this state to remove their offices to the court house in their respe[UNK]ctive counties, or within one mile thereof.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P12">11</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to alter the time for the sitting of the mayor's court of the city of Savannah.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P13">12</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to alter the mode of ele[UNK]cting the city officers of the city of Savannah.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P13">12</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to establish and make permanent that part of the public road leading from the Seat of Government to the town of Darien, beginning at or near the bridge on Cobb's creek, running [Illegible Text] to the house of Richard Cooper, and thence to the cow [Illegible Text] on the Ohopie.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P14">13</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to alter and amend an act entitled an a[UNK]ct to dispose of and distribute the late cession of lands obtained from the Creek nation, by the United States, in a treaty concluded at the city of Washington, on the 14th day of November, 1805.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P15">14</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to render valid certain proceedings had in the court of ordinary of Chatham county, since the order of said court for the removal of Edward White, as the clerk of said court.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P16">15</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to authorise the inferior courts of the [Illegible Text] counties in the Ocmulgee [Illegible Text] to draw jurors to serve at the next superior courts to be holden for the respective counties where no juries were drawn at the last superior courts.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P17">16</pagenbrref><lawdivtitle>An a[UNK]ct to cede to the United States jurisdi[UNK]ction over five acres of land, on the southern extremity of Sapelo island, for the purpose of ere[UNK]cting a light-house.</lawdivtitle><pagenbrref refid="GA1808.2.P18">17</pagenbrref></tocdiv></toc>

<page id="GA1808.2.P3" no="GA1808.2.2" type="INFERRED" />

<body><part><title><br set="CENTER" /></title><law id="L1808V2N1" initial.page="2" type="INFERRED"><p>on such security making oath that they are worth the amount of the judgment over and above the payment of their just debts.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted, by the authority [Illegible Text],</i> That no Sheriff, Deputy Sheriff, Marshal or deputy Marshal, Coroner or Constable, shall make sale of any property which has heretofore been or may hereafter be levied on by virtue of any <i>fiera facias</i> issuing out of any court within this State: <i>Provided,</i> That the defendant or defendants, his, her or their attorney, shall give security as aforesaid, to the Clerk, Justice or Justices as aforesaid.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That neither of the aforesaid Courts shall issue out any civil procets, or try any civil case which has heretofore been issued out, except for the trial of the right of property real or personal and in cases of attachment and then and in that case where it shall satisfactorily be made appear on oath, to any Judge of the Superior Court, Justice of the Inferior Court, or Justice of the peace that his, her or their debtor is about to remove out of the limits of this State, that then and in that case it shall be the duty of the Judge or Justices as aforesaid to issue an attachment against the property and body of the defendant or defendants, and cause him, her or them to be brought before him or either of them and give security as aforesaid for the amount of the debt and cost and on failure thereof, the attachment law now in force shall be [Illegible Text] as heretofore practised so far as respects the property of the said defendant, and commit the body of the said defendant to jail, there to remain until the amount claimed be paid or he be diseharged under the insolvant laws of this State: <i>Provided [Illegible Text],</i> that nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to [Illegible Text] persons to give security where they have heretofore given security on appeals but the same security shall be held and considered sufficient.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all open accounts, where the party refuses to liquidate the same, shall bear [Illegible Text] during the continuation of this act.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That this law shall not be considered to extend to cases for the recovery of taxes,

<page id="GA1808.2.P4" no="GA1808.2.3" />

to [Illegible Text] to the State for [Illegible Text] and wrongs [Illegible Text] against the State, or to any fines inflicted by proper authority for neglect of duty or otherwise.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Act of [Illegible Text] now in force in this State shall [Illegible Text] to run for and during the time this act shall continue in force.</p><p> 8. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That this Act shall continue and be in full force until the [Illegible Text] of December next.</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives:</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d MAY, 1808.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1808V2N2" initial.page="3"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To amend an act entitled an act to revise, amend and consolidate the several Militia laws of this State, and to adapt the same to the act of the Congress of the United States.</b></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That Field Officers shall be elected by the Captains and Subalterns, who will become subject to the command of such Field [Illegible Text] when elected.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That where any commissioned, non commissioned Officer or private has been regularly fined for misconduct or neglect of duty, and no goods and chattels can be found whereon to levy the said fine, that then it shall be lawful to imprison the said [Illegible Text] one day for each dollar to the amount of his fine;

<page id="GA1808.2.P5" no="GA1808.2.4" />

and that it shall be the duty of the keeper of such Goal to receive such offender or defaulter and to keep him or them in close custody for the term in such warrant expressed, and until such offender or [Illegible Text] shall have satisfied [Illegible Text] keeper for his fees on his [Illegible Text]: <i>Provided</i> [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] shall detain such person or persons more than one day for his fees.</p><p> 3. A<i>nd be it further enacted,</i> That the Commander in Chief in the State, upon [Illegible Text] for misconduct or neglect of duty, lodged in writing in the Executive Office by five or more Commissioned Officers, may at his [Illegible Text] cause to be arrested any Major General, Brigadier General, the Adjutant or Quarter Master Generals, and order a [Illegible Text] Martial of all the Generals, Field [Illegible Text] and [Illegible Text] or so many of them (having a regard to seniority) as shall amount to thirteen, which Court Martial shall proceed in the same way [Illegible Text] under the same restrictions as is hereafter provided for the trial of Field Officers: <i>Provided,</i> the charges and [Illegible Text] contained in such application shall, in the [Illegible Text] of the Commander in Chief, be sufficient to authorise such arrest or enquiry; and any Major General or Brigadier General, for misconduct within their own knowledge, or upon complaint lodged in [Illegible Text] by two Commissioned Officers, shall have power to arrest any [Illegible Text] Colonel, Major of Battalion, Major of Brigade or Inspector, and the Commanding Officer of the [Illegible Text] shall order a Court Martial for the trial of such Lieutenant Colonel, Major of [Illegible Text], Major of Brigade or Inspector, to be composed of one Brigadier General and as many [Illegible Text] Colonels, Majors and Captains, as shall make up a number of not less than thirteen and such Court Martial shall proceed to hear and determine on offences against military order and [Illegible Text] and may censure, fine or cashier such officer, which [Illegible Text] shall be final, when approved by the commander in chief of the state. And any Brigadier General, Lieutenant [Illegible Text] or Major, for misconduct in any captain, [Illegible Text] or [Illegible Text] staff officer, within his own knowledge, or upon complaint lodged in writing by any [Illegible Text] officer, may arrest such captain subaltern or regimental shall officer, and the Brigadier, or commanding

<page id="GA1808.2.P6" no="GA1808.2.5" />

officer of the Brigade, shall order a Brigade Court Martial for the trial of any such offender, to be [Illegible Text] of one or more field officers and as many [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] as will make up a number of not less than thirteenand such Courts Martial shall proceed to hear and determine on all offences against military order and decorum and may [Illegible Text] fine and cashier, any officer so tried which sentence shall be final when approved by the Major General or commanding officer of the divison. And before any court Martial shall proceed to hear and determine on any case, they shall take the following oath, to be administered by the presiding officer to every other member and then by the officer next in rank to him (to wit:) I do solemny swear, that I will well and truly try the case now before me, according to the evidence and the opinion I entertain of the spirit and intention of the [Illegible Text] law of this State, and of the United States, and that I will not [Illegible Text] the vote or opinion of any member of this court, [Illegible Text] required to give evidence there of in a court of justice in a due course of law, until the sentence shall be approved by the proper authority, so help me God. And for obtaining the necessary evidences for the trials aforesaid, the commander in chief of the State or the presiding officer of the court martial, shall issue his summons, and every person so summoned, [Illegible Text] to attend and give evidence, shall he subject to be tried by a court martial, and if an officer, may at the discretion of such court, be cashiered or fined not exceeding fix months pay, as by the law of the United States allowed to such officer when in service; and if a non-commissioned officer or soldier, or person not enrolled, to be reported to to the Court of Enquiry of the regimental district in whose bounds he shall reside and be then subject to such fines  penalties as they may think proper to inflict, not exceeding twenty dollars. And all persons summoned, or called to give evidence before any Court martial, shall take the following oath, to be administered by the president or judge advocate, to wit: I do swear, that the evidence I will give in the case now in hearing, shall be the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth, so help me God. And when any Militia Officer shall be cashiered, he shall not be eligible to hold any commission for the term of three years thereafter.</p>

<page id="GA1808.2.P7" no="GA1808.2.6" />

<p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all Officers [Illegible Text] on duty and any Militia called to musters or parades or to Courts Martial or Courts of Enquirey having to pass over toll bridges, ferries, or through turnpike gates shall pass toll free, going to and returning from such muster, or parades or Courts as aforesaid.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Brigade-majors shall receive two dollars per day while in actual service, to be paid out of the contingent fund<i>Provided,</i> the services which are to be performed shall not exceed thirty days in any one year, and shall be certified by the commanding officers of Regiments and Battalions, in the Brigade where such services are performed.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That Company Courts of Enquirey shall be held at the most convenient place near or at the usual [Illegible Text] ground in each Captain's district, within ten days after each and every muster of such company; and the deliquents and [Illegible Text] shall in all cases be notified thereof, by a Sergeant of such company at least five days previous to the meeting of such Court.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the 26th section of the militia law be, and the same is hereby repealed, and all other parts of said law which [Illegible Text] against this act.</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d May, 1808.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1808.2.P8" no="GA1808.2.7" type="INFERRED" />

<law id="L1808V2N3" initial.page="7" type="INFERRED"><fulltitle><b>To authorise the Wardens and Vestry of Christ Church in Savannah, to raise by Lottery a certain sum of money, towards rebuilding the said Curch and for other purposes relating thereto.</b></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it appears by the petition and memorial of the Wardens and Vestry of the Episcopal Church called Christ Church in Savannah, that from a variety of casulties and unforseen events, the members of the said Church, are at present unable to finish rebuilding the said Church without resorting to the expedient of a Lottery, sanctioned by Legislative concurrence.</p><p> 1. <i>BE it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives, of the State of Georgia,</i> That William Steavens, James B. Read, WardensJohn Irvine, Peter Deveaux, William B. Bulloch, Nicol Turnbull, James Hunter, Thomas Mendenhall, sen. and Wm. H. Spencer, vestrymen of said Church and their successors in office, be, and they are hereby authorised, and impowered to make such scheme, project, or plan as they may agree upon, to raise by Lottery a sum not exceeding ten thousand dollars, with power to sell and appoint Commissioners to [Illegible Text], dispose of, exchange or barter, any ticket or share in the said Lottery, as may in their opinion answer the end proposed, to aid in rebuilding the said Church, by raising the said sum of ten thousand dollars.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if the said Wardens and Vestry, or their successors, may deem it expedient or advisable to sell the trust lot, attached to their Church called the parsonage lot, situateeast on Reynolds square, south on Duke street, west on Drayton street and north on St. Julian street, and known by the letter T. they or a majority of them, or their successors in office are hereby fully authorised and empowered

<page id="GA1808.2.P9" no="GA1808.2.8" />

to make such sale and convey the same, in see simple [Illegible Text] the purchaser, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d MAY, 1808.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1808V2N4" initial.page="8"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To admit Edwin L. Harris, John B. Posey, Francis D. Cummins, William H. Jackson and Thomas W. Farrar to plead and practice in the several Courts of Law and Equity in this State.</b></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General</i> A<i>ssembly met, and by the authority of the same.</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act, Edwin L. Harris, John B. Posey, Francis D. Cummins, William H. Jackson and Thomas W. Farrar, be and they are hereby admitted to plead and practice in the several Courts of Law and Equity in this State, upon their taking the usual oath in such case made and provided.</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d May, 1808.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1808.2.P10" no="GA1808.2.9" />

<law id="L1808V2N5" initial.page="9"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To authorise Aaron Lipham and Thompson Coleman to erect a bridge over Little river in the county of Wilkes.</b></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General</i> A<i>ssembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That Aaron Lipham and Thompson Coleman be authorised to erect a toll bridge over Little river, at the place usually called the Fish Dam Ford, in the county of Wilkes, and be also permitted to receive as toll, for every loaded waggon twenty-five centsfor every empty waggon, eighteen and three quarter cents, and all four wheel pleasure carriages, twenty-five centsfor every two wheel carriage eighteen and three quarter centsfor every rolling [Illegible Text] twelve and a half centsfor every man and horse six  one quarter centsfor every led or drove horse six and one quarter centsfor each head of nett cattle one centfor every drove of hogs one cent each, and for every flock of sheep one cent each.</p><p> 2. A<i>nd be it further enacted,</i> That the said Aaron Lipham and Thompson Coleman, their heirs and assigns, shall use, exercise and enjoy all the benefits and emoluments belonging, or in any wise appertaining to the said bridge, for the term of twenty years from the completing of the same: <i>Provided,</i> The said bridge shall be ready for use in one year from the passage of this act,</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d MAY, 1808.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1808.2.P11" no="GA1808.2.10" />

<law id="L1808V2N6" initial.page="10"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To authorise an extra session of the superior court in Oglethorpe county.</b></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS, from indisposition of the Honorable Judge Tait, no Superior Court was holden in the county of Oglethorpe for March term last, and as great inconvenience and expence to the citizens of said county, have arisen, and will continue, on account of such failure, for remedy of which evil,</p><p> 1. <i>BE it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General</i> A<i>ssembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the Judge of the Superior Courts for the Western District, is hereby authorised and required, to hold an Extra Session of the Superior Court in said county, to commence on the third Monday in June next.</p><p> 2. A<i>nd be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all Grand [Illegible Text] Pettit Jurors, who were drawn and summoned to attend at March term last, to serve as jurors, and all suitors and witnesses in any case, or cases, now depending in said court, are hereby required to attend the said Extra Session of the said Superior Court, as though the same were at the said Superior Court of March term last without any further noticel and all cases returnable to the said last term, are hereby made returnable to the said Extra Session of said Superior Court, without any alteration or delay, in matters of form; any law usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding<i>Provided,</i> That ten days previous notice of the meeting of the said Court, at its Extra Session, be given by advertisement in three of the most public places in the said county of Oglethorpe.</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives:</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d MAY, 1808.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1808.2.P12" no="GA1808.2.11" />

<law id="L1808V2N7" initial.page="11"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To give further time to the clerks of the superior and inferior courts, and the clerks of the courts of ordinary in this state, to remove their offices of the court-house in their respective counties or within one mile thereof.</b></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS by an act of the General Affembly passed at [Illegible Text], on the 7th day of December, 1807, it was enacted, that from and after the [Illegible Text] day of June next thereafter, it should be the duty of the clerks of the superior and inferior courts and clerks of the courts of ordinary, to keep their offices, books and other papers at the court house of their respective counties or within one mile thereof; <i>and whereas</i> the short-space allotted them render it almost imposlible for some of [Illegible Text] to [Illegible Text] lots or purchase lands, and [Illegible Text] offices and remove their papers.</p><p><i>BE it therefore [Illegible Text] by the Senate and House of Representatives, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the time allowed said clerk for the removal of their said offices and fixing them at the court houses in their respective counties, or within one mile thereof, [Illegible Text] be extended until the twenty fifth day of October next, any section, clause or part of the before recited act to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d May, 1808.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1808.2.P13" no="GA1808.2.12" />

<law id="L1808V2N8" initial.page="12"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To alter the time for the sitting of the Mayor's Court of the city of savannah.</b></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act the Mayor's Court of the city of Savannah [Illegible Text] be held monthly, on the third [Illegible Text] in each and every month.</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That any former act or acts, so far as the same shall militate with this act, be and the fame is hereby repealed.</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of [Illegible Text],</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, Governor.</b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 28d May, 1808,</approvaldate></law><law id="L1808V2N9" initial.page="12"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To alter the mode of electing the city officers of the city of Savannah.</b></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives, of the State of Georgia, in General [Illegible Text] met, and it is [Illegible Text] by the authority of the same,</i> That the Mayor and Aldermen of the city of Savannah shall, at their first regular meeting in the month of October next, and at their [Illegible Text] regular meeting in the month of October in each sueceeding year, proceed by ballot to elect a City [Illegible Text], City Marshall, Clerk of the Mayor's Court and Clerk of Council.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it fuether [Illegible Text] by the authority [Illegible Text],</i> That the said Mayor and Aldermen shall give public notice by

<page id="GA1808.2.P14" no="GA1808.2.13" type="INFERRED" />

[Illegible Text] in two or more of the [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] in the said city of Savannah, for the space of [Illegible Text], of the time it [Illegible Text] the election for the officers aforesaid will take place.</p><p> 3. A<i>nd be it further enacted by the authority [Illegible Text],</i> That all acts, or parts of acts, heretofore [Illegible Text] on this [Illegible Text] which shall militate against the [Illegible Text] of this act, shall be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p><b>Benjamin [Illegible Text],</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d May, 1808.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1808V2N10" initial.page="13" type="INFERRED"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To establish and make permanentthat part of the public road leading from the seat of Government to the town of Darien, begining at or near the bridge on Cobbs creekruning thence to the house of Richard Cooper and thence to the cow ford on the Ohopie.</b></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act the public road leading from the Seat of Government, to the town of Darien, shall run from the bridge on Cobbs creek to the house of Richard Cooper and from thence to the cow ford on the Ohopie riverand all persons liable to work on public roads agreeable the requifitions of an act pasied by

<page id="GA1808.2.P15" no="GA1808.2.14" />

the General Assembly the fourth day of December, seventeen hundred and ninety nine, are hereby made liable to perform their labour on that part of said road, any law or usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>ROBERT WALTON</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>Jared Irwin, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d MAY, 1808.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1808V2N11" initial.page="14"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To alter and amend an act entitled an act to dispose of and distribute the late cession of lands obtained from the Creek Nation, by the United States, in a treaty concluded at the <i>City of Washington,</i> on the 14th day of November, 1805.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS many persons who have been fortunate draw [Illegible Text] may not have it in their power to take out Grants within the time [Illegible Text] by the said law, for remedy thereof:</p><p><i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same, That the time allowed for receiving monies on Grants in lieu of office fees, in pursuance of the afforesaid act, shall be and the same is hereby continuedand extended to the [Illegible Text]th day of December next, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</i></p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>ROBERT WALTON,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d May, 1808.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1808.2.P16" no="GA1808.2.15" />

<law id="L1808V2N12" initial.page="15"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To render valid certain proceedings had in thecourt of ordinary of Chatham county, since the order of said court for the removal of <i>Edward White,</i> as the clerk of said court.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS, many injuries and inconveniencies will result to individuals concerned in the proceedings of the said court, without legislative [Illegible Text], for remedy whereof,</p><p><i>BE it enacted by the Senate and house of Representatives of the state of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and by the authority [Illegible Text] the same,</i> That all letters testamentary, letters of administration, marriage licences, exemplifications, and all other documents bearing the attestation of Thomas [Illegible Text], as clerk of said court, granted, given or issued since the order of said court for the removal of Edward White, or the 4th of May 1807, until the first day of June next, unless the said Edward White shall before that time be reinstated in his office of Clerk of the court of ordinary, and in that case until the time at which he shall be so reinstated as clerk of the said court, shall be received, taken and held in any court where the same shall be necessary to any party, [Illegible Text] or defendant, in any [Illegible Text] pending, or which may hereafter pend, as valid and effectual, as though the same had been issued, given or granted by the said Edward White, or as though the said Thomas Bourke had been duly commissioned.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>ROBERT WALTON,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>Jared Irwin, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d May, 1808.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1808.2.P17" no="GA1808.2.16" />

<law id="L1808V2N13" initial.page="16"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the inferior courts of the several counties in the Ocmulgee circuit, to draw jurors to serve at the next superior courts to be holden for the respective counties where no juries were at the last superior courts.</fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and house of Representatives,</i> That the [Illegible Text] of the Inferior Courts for the feveral counties in the Ocmulgee Circuit, in which here are not Juries drawn to serve at the next Superior Courts, shall on the first Monday in July next, make a selection from among the persons liable to serve as Grand and Petit [Illegible Text] and that on the said first Monday in July next, shall severally draw a Grand and Petit Jury for the said several counties as aforesaid and then seal up the said selection agreeable to said act and return the same to the Clerk of the Superior Court, which said Jurors shall be duly [Illegible Text] by the Sheriff, and serve at the [Illegible Text] term of the Superior Courts in the said several counties; and the foregoing clause to continue in force until the next Superior Courts of said circuit and no longer.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>ROBERT WALTON,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>Jared Irwin, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d May, 1808.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1808.2.P18" no="GA1808.2.17" type="INFERRED" />

<law id="L1808V2N14" initial.page="17" type="INFERRED"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><b>To cede to the United States jurisdiction over five acres of land, on the southern extremity of Sapelo island, for the purpose of erecting a Light House.</b></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and [Illegible Text] of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met,</i> That front and immediately after the passing of this a[UNK]ct, the jurisdi[UNK]ction to and over five acres of land on the southern extremity of Sapelo island, in the county of [Illegible Text], for the purpose of ere[UNK]cting a Light House, in and for the port of Darien, be, and the same is hereby [Illegible Text] in the said United States of America<i>Provided,</i> That the said United States shall ere[UNK]ct a Light House on the same.</p><p><b>Benjamin Whitaker,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>Robert Walton,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>Jared Irwin, <i>Governor.</i></b></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d MAY, 1808.</approvaldate></law></part></body>

<page id="GA1808.2.P19" no="GA1808.2.20" type="INFERRED" />

<backmatter><index><title><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexentry>Bourke, Thomas <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Bullock, William B. <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Coleman, Thompson <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Cooper, Richard <pagenbr>13</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Cummins, Francis D. <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Devereux, Peter <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Farrar, Thomas W. <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Harris, Edwin L. <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Hunter, James <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Irwin, Jared <pagenbr>3</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>6</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>7</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>9</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>10</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>11</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>12</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>13</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>14</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>15</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>16</pagenbr> <pagenbr>17</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Irwine, John <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Jackson, William H. <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Lipha m, Aaron <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Mendenhall, Thomas <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Posey, John B. <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Read, James B. <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Spencer, Wm. H. <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Stevens, William <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Turnbull, Nicol <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Walton, Robert <pagenbr>3</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>6</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>7</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>9</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>10</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>11</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>12</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>13</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>14</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>15</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>16</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>17</pagenbr>,</indexentry><indexentry>White, Edward <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Whitaker, Benjamin <pagenbr>3</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>6</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>7</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>9</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>10</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>11</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>12</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>13</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>14</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry></index>

<page id="GA1808.2.P20" no="GA1808.2.21" type="INFERRED" />

<index><title><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexentry><u>Debtors Relief</u> <pagenbr>1</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Lottery for <u>Christ Church</u> <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To alter mode of electing <u>city</u> officers <pagenbr>12</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To <u>draw</u> jurors <pagenbr>16</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><u>Erect</u> a bridge <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><u>Lands</u> obtained from Creek Nation <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To cede land to erect a <u>Light House</u> <pagenbr>17</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To alter time of <u>Mayors</u> Court <pagenbr>12</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><u>Militia</u> laws <pagenbr>3</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><u>Movement</u> of court clerks to a new building <pagenbr>11</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><u>Removal</u> of clerk Edward White <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><u>Right</u> to practice law and equity <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To establish and make permanent part of <u>road</u> to seat of government <pagenbr>13</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Extra Session <u>Superior Court</u> <pagenbr>10</pagenbr></indexentry></index>

<page id="GA1808.2.P21" no="GA1808.2.22" type="INFERRED" />

<index><title><u>PLACE OR TOWN</u><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexentry>Chatham Co., Ga. <pagenbr>Page 15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Darien, Ga. <pagenbr>13</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Milledgeville, Ga. <pagenbr>11</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Ocmulgee Circuit <pagenbr>16</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Oglethorpe Co. <pagenbr>10</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Sapelo Island <pagenbr>17</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Savannah, Ga. <pagenbr>7</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>12</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Washington, City of, Ga. <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Wilkes Co. <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry></index></backmatter></document></galaw>
