<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<galaw><metadata><coretitle>Acts of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</coretitle><creator>Georgia</creator><subject>Law, Georgia</subject><description>Georgia. Acts and resolutions of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</description><publisher>MILLEDGEVILLE:: S.  F. GRANTLAND,</publisher><contributors><contributor /></contributors><date>18131100</date><type /><format /><identifier /><source /><language>English</language><relation /><coverage /><rights /></metadata>
<document initial.page="1" type="INFERRED">
<page id="GA1813.1.P1" no="GA1813.1.1" type="INFERRED" />

<titlepage><title><b>ACTS</b><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><b>General Assembly</b><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><b>STATE <i>OF</i> GEORGIA,</b><br set="CENTER">PASSED AT MILLEDGEVILLE,<br set="CENTER"><b>At an Annual Session,</b><br set="CENTER">IN NOVEMBER AND DECEMBER, 1813.<br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></title><sessiondate>18131100</sessiondate><sessiondate>18131200</sessiondate><pubinfo><p>Published by Authority.</p><p>MILLEDGEVILLE:</p><p><i>Printed by</i> <i>S.  F. GRANTLAND,</i></p><p>PRINTERS TO THE STATES</p><p>1813.</p></pubinfo></titlepage>

<page id="GA1813.1.P2" no="GA1813.1.3" type="INFERRED" />

<body><part><title>ACTS<br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><i>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</i><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER">STATE OF GEORGIA;<br set="CENTER"><i>Passed in November  December,</i> 1813.<br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></br></br></title><law id="L1813V1N001" initial.page="3" type="INFERRED"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>Supplementary to, and amendatory of an act, entitled an act to alleviate the condition of debtors, passed the 27th November, 1812.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That nothing in the before recited act, shall operate to prevent the President and Directors of the Planters' Bank of the state of Georgia, or the Bank of Augusta, from instituting suit, or suits, and enforcing all contracts made with them, or either of them, in their corporate capacity in the same manner, that they were authorised to do, before the passing of said act.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That actions upon the case for words

<page id="GA1813.1.P3" no="GA1813.1.4" />

may in all cases be brought in the same manner as if the before recited act had not been passed, or had never had existence.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That in all cases of judgments heretofore obtained, or which may hereafter be obtainedor executions heretofore issued, it shall and may be lawful for the plaintiff or plaintiffs in such judgments or executions, their agent or attorney, upon affidavit made that his debtor is removing or about to remove, or has removed his, her or their property out of this state or any county thereof, to compel such debtor to give good and sufficient freehold security to such plaintiff in a sum equal to the amount due on such judgment or execution; and on failure of such debtor to give such security, it shall be lawful for the plaintiff in those executions heretofore issued to proceed therewith, and to cause the same to be levied on the property of such defendantand in cases of judgments where executions shall not have issued, the Clerk of the Court where such judgment was obtained, or in cases of judgments before Justices of the Peace, for such Justice to issue execution against such debtor, which may be levied on the property of such debtor in the same manner as if the before recited act had not been passed<i>Provided,</i> that nothing herein contained shall operate to prevent the giving such security to the officer having such execution at any time before the sale shall have actually taken place in virtue thereof; and upon giving such security the Sheriff or officer holding such execution, shall stop further proceedings, and shall return to the defendant or defendants all such property

<page id="GA1813.1.P4" no="GA1813.1.5" />

as shall have been levied on by virtue of any such execution.</p><p> 4 <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the provisions of this act or the one to which this is amendatory, shall not extend to any executor or executrix, administrator, administratrix or guardian, who has actually in his or her hands any money belonging to any legatees, distributees or orphans and withholds the same from the proper benefit and use of said legatees, distributees or orphans, or where he, she or they have applied said money to his, her or their own individual use, and not to the use of said legatees, distributees or orphans<i>provided nevertheless,</i> that nothing in this act, or the one to which this is amendatory, shall be so construed as to prevent the issuing of subp[oelig]nas, summonses and commissions for taking depositions of witnesses, and summoning jurors and witnesses, where the same may be necessary for the hearing and determining of cases which this act, and the one to which this is a supplement, the courts of this state are authorized to hear and determine.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That nothing contained in this act, or the act to which this is amendatory, shall go to prevent the commencement and trial of suits on bonds, and obligations or other instruments in writing, given for titles to land.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That nothing in the before recited act, shall operate to prevent the foreclosure of mortgages on personal estate<i>provided,</i> that any person seeking to foreclose his mortgage, shall at the time of making application for foreclosure, make oath that the mortgager is

<page id="GA1813.1.P5" no="GA1813.1.6" />

about to remove the property out of the state, or any county of the state.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all persons holding open accounts, such creditor before he shall call on his debtor for the liquidation of said accounts, in terms of the 4th section of an act to which this is an amendment, shall fairly draw off his account, prove the same before a Justice of the Peace, or some other officer of the Peace.</p><p> 8. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That so much of the before recited act as militates against this act be, and the same is hereby [Illegible Text]</p><p> 9. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That this act, and so much of the act to which this is amendatory as be not repugnant to this act, shall be and continue in force until the 25th of December, 1814, and no longer.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N002" initial.page="6"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the mustering of a portion of the militia of Camden county at the town of St. Mary's in said county.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the Court-house in Camden county

<page id="GA1813.1.P6" no="GA1813.1.7" />

is situated more than twenty-two miles from the town of St. Mary's, known to be the most populous part of said county, and past experience hath evinced that very few of the militia of said district have heretofore attended the general musters in said county at the court-house; And whereas, it would be impolitic at this momentous crisis for the active force of the militia to leave the said town unprotected; And it is desirable that every citizen capable of bearing arms should be allowed an opportunity to gain instruction in military discipline;</p><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, the militia of the town of St. Mary's, as well as all those who reside South of Crooked river, now commanded by Capt. Thomas H. Miller, shall not be required nor compeled to attend any musters beyond the limits of the town of St. Mary's (the Company musters of Captain Thomas H. Miller's men only excepted). But the militia of said town and those under the command of Thomas H. Miller liable to perform militia duty, shall be bound to obey the orders of the Adjutant General or the Major General of the Division to muster within the limits of said town, at such times as either of the said officers may direct; where defaulters will be subject to such fines and penalties, as by the militia law of this state are imposed in similar cases</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all laws or parts of laws that

<page id="GA1813.1.P7" no="GA1813.1.8" />

can be construed to militate against this act, shall be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 2d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N003" initial.page="8"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To raise a tax for the support of government for the political year one thousand eight hundred and fourteen, and to revive, alter and amend an act, entitled an act, to raise a tax for the support of government for the political year one thousand eight hundred and thirteen.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That from and after the passage of this act, the Receivers of Returns of taxable property shall continue to receive the returns aforesaid, of all persons liable to pay tax until the first day of August in each year.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the Receiver of Returns of [Illegible Text] property, shall on or before the first Monday in November in each year deliver the several digests,

<page id="GA1813.1.P8" no="GA1813.1.9" />

and perform all other duties required of them according to the requisitions of the before recited act; <i>provided,</i> said requisitions be not repugnant to this act.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all persons who may have incurred the penalty of a four fold tax under the before recited act, shall be exonerated from the payment of the same, on payment of one third part of the same; and it shall be the duty of the several Tax Collectors in the several counties to receive one third part of the tax which may be on their books charged against defaulters, and on receiving the same, to give receipts in full, and in their settlements with the Comptroller General be entitled to a credit for the whole of the said four fold tax on paying one third thereof; and in case any such defaulter shall neglect to pay the one third as aforesaid, the Collector shall not be at liberty to issue his execution against such defaulter for more than the one third of the said four fold tax.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the passage of this act, the Receivers of Tax Returns shall give at least twenty days notice at the muster ground in each Captain's district of the time of expiration for receiving of said lists, together with the names of persons who have not then given in their lists, and immediately after said time has expired, they shall make out a fair list of the persons in default, and advertise the same at each Captain's muster ground, which shall supercede the necessity of advertising defaulters in the public Gazettes</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the provisions

<page id="GA1813.1.P9" no="GA1813.1.10" />

in the before [Illegible Text] act, so far as respects the Receivers assessing a fou fold tax in cases of default, be and the same are hereby repealed,  that the Receivers of [Illegible Text] R [Illegible Text] do proceed to assses a double tax in cases of default as prescribed by the tax law [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] December, 1812, raising a tax for the political year [Illegible Text].</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all Bank Stock shall pay for each and every hundred dollars, thirty one and a quarter cents in this state.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That nothing in the before recited act, authorizing the Inferior Courts to remit four feld tax on defaulters shall be so construed as to authorize them to remit more than three fourths of the tax charged on the Receiver's books, or any greater part of said tax than shall reduce the same to a less sum than his, her or their ordinary annual tax.</p><p> 8. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in all cases where the Inferior court has heretofore remitted the whole of the four feld tax of any defaulters, the said defaulters shall be and they are hereby required to give in their return for the year 1813, as well as for the year 1814, to the Receiver for the year 1814; and the Receiver shall make return of the same to the Collector for the year 1814, and shall be collected by him in the same manner as pointed out by this act for the collection of taxes; and in case any such defaulter shall neglect to make his return for the year 1813 to the Receiver for the year 1814, they shall be subject to pay a double tax for the said year 1813, as pointed out in this [Illegible Text] in other cases of default.</p><p> 9. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Receivers of Returns of taxable property and Collectors

<page id="GA1813.1.P10" no="GA1813.1.11" />

of Taxes who may hereafter be appointed and qualified agreeably to law, be and they are hereby authorized and required to receive the returns of taxable property and to collect the taxes thereon for all former years since 1 00 inclusive, where any county is in default for not having made their returns as required by law- <i>provided,</i> that the taxes shall be assessed in conformity to the tax laws in force at the time such default happened.</p><p> 10. <i>And be it further enacted.</i> That the tax for the support of government for the political year 1814 shall be assessed, levied and collected in the manner pointed out by the act to raise a tax for the political year [Illegible Text], passed the 10th December 1812, and the other acts on this subject therein referred to; <i>provided,</i> the same do not contravene the amendments and alterations in this act contained; and the Receivers of Tax Returns and Collectors of tax for the year 1814, shall be governed by the provisions of the aforesaid acts, so far as they are compatible with this act.</p><p> 11. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the before recited act (except such parts as militate against this act be, and the same is hereby revived, and declared to be in force until repealed by law.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P11" no="GA1813.1.12" />

<law id="L1813V1N004" initial.page="12"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To amend an act, entitled an act for the limitation of actions and for avoiding suits in law.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS divers persons during the time this state was a British Province, obtained grants for lands within the same, and during the revolutionary war, and at the expiration thereof, fled from this state, or who never resided therein; And whereas divers persons, good citizens of this state, have since the revolution unknowingly surveyed and obtained grants for all or a large part of many of the aforesaid old surveys, or who have become purchasers and have settled, cultivated and greatly improved the same, defending and supporting this state; and reason and justice require that they should not be disturbed in their possessions at this late periodfor remedy wereof;</p><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of he state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That no person or persons claiming any lands, tenements or hereditaments by virtue of any grant or grants prior to the revolutionary war, and who never resided in said Province, or who fled from this state during that struggle, and who did not return to this state within twenty one years after the treaty of peace with Great-Britain, which was in the year seventeen hundred and eighty three, to make their entry thereon, settle or cultivate the same, or any part thereof, shall either, he, she or they, or any person or persons claim. [Illegible Text] under him, her or them, hereafter recover any such parts thereof as may have been since

<page id="GA1813.1.P12" no="GA1813.1.13" />

granted, from any person or persons, who has or have since the revelution obtained a grant or grants, settled or cultivated the same, or any part thereof, for the term of seven years in peaceable possession; nor from any person or persons claiming under such young title as aforesaid, where there has been an adverse possession for the aforesaid term of seven years</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That no saving or exception in any statute of limitations in this state, providing for the claims of persons resident beyond seas, shall operate or be so construed as to benefit any persons whose grants have issued prior to the revolutionary war, and who are [Illegible Text] subjects of the Crown of Great-Britain or other foreign nations.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That nothing in this act contained shall effect or be construed to effect any lands belonging to, or that ever did belong to any person or persons, named in the act of confiscation and banishment or bill of attainder, or any right which this state has to confiscated lands, or any right which any citizen of the United States or citizen of this state, may have to any of said lands.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 2d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P13" no="GA1813.1.14" />

<law id="L1813V1N005" initial.page="14"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize William Scott, sen. of Camden county to establish a toll on the road leading from Bull town Swamp to Fort Barrington on the Altamaha, through M'Intosh county.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly [Illegible Text] and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same.</i> That William Scott, [Illegible Text] of Camden county is hereby authorised to lay out a road leading from Bull Town-Swamp to Samuel Jones's in M'Intosh county; from thence the nearest, best and most direct way to [Illegible Text] Barrington on the Altamaha river, and to open the same; and the said William Scott, [Illegible Text] his heirs, executors, administrators or assigns shall be bound to put the said road in good and complete repair, to raise it not exceeding five feet above the common surface wherever it may be necessary, and to make it twenty feet wide; to enable him to perform which, he is hereby authorised to take [Illegible Text] and earth the most convenient; and the said W. Scott, [Illegible Text] shall be answerable for every damage or injury occasioned by the badness or want of repair of the said road during the period hereafter mentioned.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the said W. Scott, sen shall bind himself, his heirs, executors, administrators and assigns, together with two other good and sufficient securities to be approved of by the commissioners

<page id="GA1813.1.P14" no="GA1813.1.15" />

hereafter named, to the said commissioners and their successors in office, in the penal sum of five thousand dollars for the performance of the aforesaid contract.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That for and in consideration of the laying out, opening and keeping in repair the said road leading from Bull-Town-Swamp to Samuel Jones's in [Illegible Text] county, from thence to Fort Barrington the nearest, best and most direct way, the said W. Scott, sen, his heirs, executors, administrators and assigns shall be entitled to receive for the term of thirty years, the following rates and tollage, to be collected on the said road at any place that may be deemed the most convenient by the said W. Scott, sen. to wiffor every four wheeled pleasure carriage, one dollar; for every two wheel ditto, fifty cents; for every waggon and team, seventy five cents; for every cart and horse, thirty-seven and a half cents; for every man and horse, twenty five cents; and for all black cattle and horses per head, six and a quarter cents.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That Samuel Jones, Samuel Owens  Moses Way be, and they are hereby declared to be Commissioners appointed under this act, and in case of vacancy by death, resignation or otherwise, of any of the aforesaid commissioners, that then His Excellency the Governor is hereby authorized  required to fill up said vacancy,  they or a majority of the said Commissioners are authorised to declare at what time the said road is completed, according to the first section of this act,

<page id="GA1813.1.P15" no="GA1813.1.16" />

when and not before, the toll or charges as aforesaid shall and may be demanded.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N006" initial.page="16"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To legalize and make valid the acts and proceedings of Sheriffs and Clerks in this state in certain cases therein expressed.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the forty-sixth section of the Judiciary law of this state, passed in the year seventeen hundred and ninety-nine requires that before any Sheriff shall enter upon the duties of his appointment and being commissioned by the Governor, he shall be bound for the faithful performance of his duty by himself and his deputies before any of the said judges to the Governor of the State for the time being, and to his successors in office, jointly and severally, with two good and sufficient securities, inhabitants and freeholders of the county, to be approved of by the Justices of the Inferior court, or any three of them, in the sum of twenty thousand dollars;</p><p>And whereas a custom has heretofore [Illegible Text]

<page id="GA1813.1.P16" no="GA1813.1.17" />

with the Executive Department of this state in issuing the didimus protestatum, to qualify the Sheriff to direct the same only to two or [Illegible Text] Justices of the Inferior courts of the several counties in consequence of which the bond in many cases given by the Sheriffs and their securities do not appear to have been attested by or approved by more than two Justices of the Inferior courts; and as doubts and difficulties may, and probably will at some future day, arise respecting the legality of the acts and proceedings of [Illegible Text] when their bonds do not appear to have been approved by more than two Justices as aforesaid, and the proceedings of the courts in the several counties may be called into questionFor remedy whereof;</p><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That in all cases where persons have been elected Sheriffs in the several counties in this state, and have been commissioned by the Governor, taken the oath of office and have given bond and security which has been approved by any one or more of the Justices of the Inferior courts in the county in which such person shall have been elected and commissioned, and the person so commissioned and qualified has acted as Sheriff, that then and in that case, all official acts done and performed by him or his deputies, and all judicial proceedings in the courts in the several counties during the time such person acted as Sheriff shall be taken, held and deemed as legal and valid as if the aforesaid act of seventeen hundred and ninety-nine had been fully complied

<page id="GA1813.1.P17" no="GA1813.1.18" />

with in taking the bond and otherwise qualifying the Sheriffs aforesaidany law, usage or custom to the contrary [Illegible Text]</p><p>And whereas some doubts exist with regard to the legality of the official acts of the several Clerks and Sheriffs of the different counties in this state which have been transacted since the 18th day of October last;</p><p> 2. <i>Be it therefore enacted,</i> That all official acts of any or all Sheriffs and Clerks in this state since the aforesaid eighteenth day of October last, shall be deemed, held and considered as legal and valid in law, as it such doubts had not, or did not exist; and they shall continue to act in their several official capacities until their successors are elected, commissioned and qualified.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N007" initial.page="18"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize His Excellency the Governor, to settle with the United States the amount of the Direct Tax due by the State of Georgia, and to point out the method of reimbursing the state the said sum in part.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives</i>

<page id="GA1813.1.P18" no="GA1813.1.19" />

<i>of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby fully authorized  directed to pay into the Treasury of the United States the amount of the Direct Tax due by Georgia, deducting from the amount of the same the fifteen per centum which is allowed by the United States for prompt payment.</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That for the purpose of His Excellency the Governor meeting the aforesaid amount of Direct Tax, he is hereby authorized to draw out of the Treasury of the United States, whatever monies may be due to Georgia.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That for the purpose of carrying this act into effect. His Excellency is hereby fully authorized to appoint an agent or agents, and to execute receipts, and to do all other things that may be necessary for the purpose of carrying this act fully into effect.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That for the purpose of [Illegible Text] the state in part) the sum directed to be paid by this act, that each citizen of this state, and all other persons holding taxable property, real  personal in said state is, and are hereby made liable and required to pay a tax of fifty per centum on the amount of the state tax required of him, her or them for the support of the Government of this state for the political year, 1813, which shall be collected on or before the first day of January 1815, under the same laws and regulations, as are pointed out for the collection of the state tax for the year aforesaid; and it shall be the duty of the Tax Collectors in

<page id="GA1813.1.P19" no="GA1813.1.20" />

this state to collect the tax herein levied and assessed, agreeably to the requisitions of the before recited act; for which services they shall be entitled to receive two and a half per centum, <i>provided,</i> said collectors shall first give bond and security, agreeably to the requisitions of the before recited act, for the faithful performance of the duties herein required of them.</p><p> 5 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in case any of the Collectors aforesaid, shall refuse to collect the tax aforesaid upon the terms herein before directed, that then and in that case, the Justices of the Inferior courts in counties where such refusal shall be made, shall proceed to appoint one fit and proper person in each county, to receive and collect said tax agreeably to the requisitions  laws herein before pointed out; and the said collectors shall be commissioned by the Governor, and give bond and security in conformity to the before recited act, for the faithful performance of their duty as collectors aforesaid; and for the purpose of ascertaining the amount of tax required by this act, it shall be the duty of the Clerks of the Inferior courts to deliver to Collectors appointed in conformity to this section, the Digests deposited in their offices.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That where any person has heretofore paid, or may hereafter pay his or her general tax for the year 1813, and who has not paid the additional sum of fifty per cent. as contemplated by this act, the Collector of the county where such person resides, shall, and he is hereby authorized to collect the fifty per cent, as he would have been authorized to do by this act, provided the said general tax had not been paid.</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P20" no="GA1813.1.21" />

<p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Collectors aforesaid shall signify their acceptance or refusal to do the duties hereby required, to the Justices of the Inferior courts aforesaid, on or before the first day of March next, and shall give bond and security in terms of this act.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N008" initial.page="21"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>Vesting in Richard Montgomery Dimond, certain property therein mentioned.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it hath been represented to the General Assembly of this state, that Augusta [Illegible Text] Widow (late of the county of Chatham,) did depart this life intestate and without will, leaving no heirs; And whereas it appears that it was the intention of the said Augusta Fisher to have vested in the aforesaid Richard Montgomery Dimond, all her property, real and personal, but died without carrying her intention fully into effectFor remedy whereof;</p><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority</i>

<page id="GA1813.1.P21" no="GA1813.1.22" />

<i>of the same.</i> That all the property real and personal which did belong to the said Augusta Fisher at the time of her death, be, and the same is hereby vested in the said Richard Montgomery Dimond<i>provided nevertheless,</i> that nothing in this act shall be construed so as to prevent the recovery of any just demand which may hereafter be brought against said estate<i>And provided,</i> that nothing herein before enacted shall be so construed as to bar the right of any lawful heir or heirs, if such should hereafter claim, the said estate.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 2d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N009" initial.page="22"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To appropriate monies for the political year, one thousand eight hundred and fourteen.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That for the support of Government for the political year, one thousand eight hundred and fourteen, the following sums of money be, and the same are hereby appropriated, vizthe salary of

<page id="GA1813.1.P22" no="GA1813.1.23" />

the Governor shall be two thousand dollars per annum; Secretaries of the Executive Department, not exceeding two, five hundred dollars each; the Secretary of State, two hundred dollars; the Treasurer, twelve hundred dollars; the Surveyor General two hundred dollars; the Comptroller General, six hundred dollars; the Clerk of the House of Representatives, three hundred dollars; the Secretary of the Senate, three hundred dollars; the Judges of the Superior courts, fourteen hundred dollars each; the Attorney General and three Solicitors General, one hundred and fifty dollars each; which said several sums shall be, and the same are hereby appropriated for their use to be paid quarter yearly by warrant from the Governor on the Treasurer, out of any money not specially otherwise appropriated.</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of sixteen thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated as a contingent fund, subject to the orders of the Governor.</p><p> 3 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That for the compensation of the members of the Legislature, three dollars each per day, during their attendance be appropriated, and the sum of three dollars for every twenty miles in coming to, and returning from the seat of Government; and the sum of four dollars each per day to the President of the Senate and Speaker of the House of Representatives during their attendance; and the sum of three dollars each for every twenty miles their coming to, and returning from the seat of Government; to the Clerk of the House of Representatives and Secretary of the Senate during the sitting

<page id="GA1813.1.P23" no="GA1813.1.24" />

of the Legislature, four dollars each per day, and the sum of sixty dollars for contingent expences, c., to the two engrossing Clerks and one Assistant Clerk to the House of Representatives  two engrossing Clerks to the Senate, four dollars per day each, to the Clerk to the Committee on Finance, and to the Clerk of the Committee on the State of the Republic, sixty dollars each; to the Messengers and Door keepers of the Legislature, three dollars per day each during the session; to the Adjurant General, one thousand dollars per annum to be paid quarter yearly; the sum of fifty thousand dollars to be set apart as a fund for military disbursements, to be drawn for by His Excellency the Governor as he may think the public safety and expendiency may require; to Gen Frederick Beall, the sum of fifty-six dollars and twenty-five cents; to Col. Mager Henderson, the sum of thirty seven dollars and eighty cents agreeable to a concurred resolution of both [Illegible Text]; to Alexander Greene, eighty dollars for airing, scouring and taking care of the State-house, the desks and carpets in the recess of the Legislature  making fires on wet days; to Peter Farr, sixty dollars for winding up the clock, keeping clean the stair cases, passages, c.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of twenty thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the payment of the sum which the Governor has been authorised to borrow, by a concurred resolution of the present Legislature<i>provided,</i> the said sum has been, or should be borrowed.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorised,

<page id="GA1813.1.P24" no="GA1813.1.25" />

should he find it necessary, to negotiate a loan with either the Bank of Augusta, or the Planters' Bank for a sum not exceeding fifty thousand dollars and that the faith of the state be pledged for the repayment of this sum with interest thereon.</p><p> 6 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of six thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated, toward the rearing and completing the Penitentiary building, to be drawn for by His Excellency as he may find necessary; to the Mayor and Aldermen of the City of Savannah, the sum of three thousand and ninety-five dollars and seventy cents, agreeably to a concurred resolution.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N010" initial.page="25"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To quiet and confirm the titles of persons who have purchased lots from, and under the Commissioners of the town or Academy of Waynesborough, in the county of Burke, and for other purposes.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it has been represented to this General

<page id="GA1813.1.P25" no="GA1813.1.26" />

Assembly that the lot holders  persons owning lots in the town of Waynesboro' in the county of Burke, are likely to be disturbed in their titles to and possession of lots in the said town, by reason of there being no grant in existence from the state of Georgia for the land whereon the said town of Waynesborough is situate: And whereas it appears by the 11th section of an act of the General Assembly of this state, passed at Augusta the 31st July, 1783, entitled an act for laying out the reserve land in the town of Augusta into acre lots, the erecting of an Academy or Seminary of Learning, and for other purposes therein mentionedThat Thomas Lewis, Sen. Thomas Lewis, Jr. John Duhart, Edward Telfair and John Jones were appointed Commissioners for laying out a town in the reserve of public land in the county of Burke into acre lots, and disposing of the same at public outcry, and the monies arising therefrom to be applied to the purpose of erecting the necessary public buildings in said town, to be known by the name of Waynesborough: And it being represented that the said Commissioners, or their successors in office, did lay out a town in pursuance of the before recited section, on a tract of land belonging to the public in the county of Burke, which tract of land was at that time bounded East and South East by lands of John Thomas and Josiah Allday, North West by land of John Robinson, and Westwardly in part by Robert Miller, and did proceed to sell lots accordingly: And it appearing manifestly unjust and oppressive that persons purchasing of those Commissioners, or their successors in office, or

<page id="GA1813.1.P26" no="GA1813.1.27" />

those claiming under such purchasers, should at this late day be disturbed in their titles to the lots in said townFor remedy whereof,</p><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That all titles to lots in the said town of Waynesborough in the county of Burke, derived from and under the Commissioners of said town, or the Commissioners of the Waynesborough Academy in the county of Burke be, and the same are hereby declared to be as good and valid in law and equity, as if the land upon which the said town is situate had been regularly granted by the state of Georgia; and the persons claiming or to claim under or by virtue of any sale from the Commissioners aforesaid shall have, and they are hereby declared to have as good right and title to the lots in the said town of Waynesborough, as if the said land had been granted as aforesaid<i>Provided,</i> nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to defeat the title or claim of any person or persons who shall have fairly and regularly obtained a grant from the state of Georgia for any lot or lots in the said town of Waynes-borough prior to any sale by the Commissioners of said town as aforesaid.</p><p>And to prevent all future disputes in relation to the title of the Commissioners of the said town or the Academy of Waynesborough in the county of Burke, or persons claiming or to claim under them, or their successors in office</p><p> 2 <i>Be it enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all that tract of land herein before described, and whereon the town of Waynesborough is situate,

<page id="GA1813.1.P27" no="GA1813.1.28" />

which has not heretofore been disposed of by the Commissioners of the town of Waynesborough or Commissioners of the Academy of Burke county be, and the same is hereby declared to be vested in the present Commissioners of the town or Academy of Waynesborough in the county of Burke, and their successors in office, for public purposes, and for carrying into effect so much of the before recited act as appertains to the town of Waynesborough and the public buildings in said town according to the true intent and meaning of said act, as fully and completely as if a grant had been regularly obtained therefor<i>Provided,</i> nothing herein contained shall operate or be so construed as to effect the claim of any person or persons having a fair and regular title derived under a grant from the state of Georgia, for any of the before described tract of land.</p><p> 3 <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all title deeds for lots in the said town of Waynesborough derived from the Commissioners of the said town, or Trustees of the Academy of Burke county, shall be admited as evidence in the Superior Courts of this state, without requiring the production of a grant from the state for the land described in such deeds, any law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P28" no="GA1813.1.29" />

<law id="L1813V1N011" initial.page="29"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To add a part of Clarke county to Oglethorpe county.</fulltitle><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act, all that part of the tract of land whereon Thomas M'Coy now resides, lying on the East side of Big creek be, and the same is hereby added to the county of Oglethorpe.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 20th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N012" initial.page="29"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To legalize and make valid certain acts of Angus M'Donald, as Deputy Clerk of the Superior court of the county of Wayne.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That all acts or parts of acts of the said Angus M'Donald as Deputy-Clerk of the Superior court of the county of Wayne, up to the first day of November, eighteen hundred and thirteen, shall be held, deemed and considered

<page id="GA1813.1.P29" no="GA1813.1.30" />

valid in law, as if such acts had been done and performed by the Clerk of the Superior court of the county of Wayne, had he continued in office.</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all acts and parts of acts militating with this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N013" initial.page="30"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To amend an act, entitled An act to amend an act, to make permanent the scite of the public buildings in the town of Hartford in the county of Pulaski.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the above recited act does not authorize the Justices of the Inferior court to appropriate any part of the county funds, arising from the sale of lots in the town of Hartford, to any other use than paying for the court-house and jail of said countyFor remedy whereof.</p><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior

<page id="GA1813.1.P30" no="GA1813.1.31" />

court of the county of Pulaski, or a majority of them, shall be and they are hereby authorized and empowered, to appropriate all monies which have arisen, or may hereafter arise, from the sale of the lots in the town of Hartford in the county of Pulaski, after paying for building the court-house and jail of said county to other county purposes, as they may deem expedient, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 30th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N014" initial.page="31"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To alter and amend an act, passed the Fifteenth day of December, one thousand eight hundred and ten, entitled An act to regulate the town of Monticello in the county of Randolph.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That from and after the passage of this act, the day for electing Commissioners for the town of Monticello shall be on the last Saturday in December in each year, under the same rules and regulations as are pointed out in the above recited act.</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P31" no="GA1813.1.32" />

<p> 2. <i>And be it enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That so much of said act as militates against this act be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N015" initial.page="32"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To repeal an act compeling the clerks of this state to keep their offices within one mile of their respective court-houses, so far as respects the county of Emanuel; and to make permanent the line dividing the counties of Bulloch and Emanuel; and to repeal the third section, and to alter and amend other sections of an act entitled, an act to lay out a new county out of the counties of Montgomery and Bulloch, passed the tenth day of December, one thousand eight hundred and twelve, and for other purposes.</fulltitle><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House [Illegible Text] Representatives of the state of Georgia in General</i>

<page id="GA1813.1.P32" no="GA1813.1.33" />

<i>Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the act entitled an act, to compel the Clerks of this state to keep their offices within one mile of their respective Court-houses, passed the day of, be, and the same is hereby repealed, so far as respects the county of Emanuel.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the dividing line between the counties of Bulloch and Emanuel shall be, and the same is hereby declared to be as followsbeginning at the mouth of Skull's creek, thence up said creek to the head of the south-east fork, thence a marked line going Dorrity's trail, thence to Tatnall county line, being the line lately run and marked by Isham Corbitt, David Johnson, Hute Studsill, John Lanier and Allen Lanier.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the third section of the act, entitled an act, to lay out a new county out of the counties of Montgomery and Bulloch, passed the 10th day of December 1812, be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That Joshua Wood, Travis Thigpen, Jesse Price, John Wolf and Gideon Hose be, and they are hereby appointed Commissioners, who, [or a majority of them] shall have power and authority to fix on the scite of the public buildings for the said county of Emanuel, and to purchase in behalf of said county, a tract of land, which shall contain not less than fifty, nor more than one hundred acres, and which shall be as near the centre of said county as practicable, on which the public buildings of said county shall be erected;

<page id="GA1813.1.P33" no="GA1813.1.34" />

 the said commissioners are also authorized to lay off the said tract of land in lots at their discretion, and after reserving to the county a sufficient number thereof for county purposes, may sell and dispose of the remainder upon such terms,  in such manner as they may think most conducive to the public interest; and the monies arising therefrom shall, after paying for said tract of land, be applied towards the building of a Court-house and Jail for said county, which buildings the Commissioners are also authorized to let to the lowest bidder at public outcry, giving at least thirty days notice of the time and place of letting the same, taking bond and security from the person contracting for the faithful performance of the contract<i>provided,</i> that until the Court-house shall be erected, the courts shall be holden, and elections held at the house of Stephen Rich in the said county of Emanuel.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That if the above Commissioners, or a majority of them, cannot or do not agree on the place for the public scite, then and in that case, the Justices of the Inferior court of said county are authorized to appoint some fit and proper person to ascertain the centre of said county, and the Justices of said court are authorised to allow him reasonable compensation for his services, to be paid out of the county fund; AND IT IS ALSO ENACTED, that the above commissioners, or a majority of them, shall fix the public scite thereat, or as near as conveniency will admit of.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court for the county of Emanuel be, and they are hereby

<page id="GA1813.1.P34" no="GA1813.1.35" />

authorized and required to lay an extra tax upon the inhabitants of Emanuel county, which shall not exceed one fourth part of the general tax, for the purpose of building a Court-house and Jail in said county, and for other county purposes.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Tax Collector for the county of Emanuel be, and he is hereby required to collect the said extra tax at the same time, and upon the same terms that he collects the general tax; and when collected, he shall pay over the same to the Clerk of the Inferior court to be applied to the purposes contemplated by this act.</p><p> 8. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That so much of the act entitled an act, to lay out a new county out of the counties of Montgomery and Bulloch, passed the 10th December, 1812, as militates against this act be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N016" initial.page="35"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>For the relief of persons who now are in the service of the United States from this state.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it may so happen that persons now

<page id="GA1813.1.P35" no="GA1813.1.36" />

in the service of the United States from this state may be elected as Sheriff, Clerk, Tax Collector, County Surveyor or Coroner, and the time prescribed by law for them to qualify may expire previous to their term of serviceFor remedy whereof;</p><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That where any person or persons now in the service of the United States from this state shall be elected as Tax Receiver, Tax Collector, County Surveyor, Clerk or Sheriff of any court or Coroner, or any other appointment which by law, they or either of them would be required to give security and qualify at any certain period, such person or persons shall be at liberty, and it shall be lawful for him or them to qualify and give such security at any time previous to the first day of April nextany law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N017" initial.page="36"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>For the relief of John Boog.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it appears that John Boog became

<page id="GA1813.1.P36" no="GA1813.1.37" />

security for the appearance of one Adam Walsby, and it appearing that the said Walsby did appear at the first term of the court to which he was bound, and from unavoidable circumstances was unable to attend afterwardsFor remedy whereof;</p><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court of Camden county be, and they are hereby directed to remit the penalty incurred by the said Adam Walsby's failing to attend.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 2d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N018" initial.page="37"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To amend an act, regulating roads in this state, so far as respects the county of Glynn.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That immediately after the passing of this act, the Justices of the Inferior court of Glynn county shall be authorized and hereby required to appoint three Commissioners for each

<page id="GA1813.1.P37" no="GA1813.1.38" />

road of a public nature in the county of Glynn, who are to direct and superintend the labor to be performed on said road or roads, and that the said Justices shall also have power and authority to fill all vacancies in the board of Commissioners that may be occasioned by death or otherwise, and that the power and authority of the Commissioners previously appointed to the passing of this act, shall henceforth cease and be determined.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court of Glynn county, or a majority of them, are hereby empowered at their discretion to reject or confirm all county roads heretofore laidout; also, to grant the prayer of petitions for county roads; also, to appoint superintendants for the same at all times when requested, and to apportion the hands for the said roads as they may think most proper.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court aforesaid, shall have full power to regulate and direct all things regarding the public roads, so far as relates to the road upon the Island of St. Simon's in the said county, any thing in any other law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That when any person shall be a defaulter on any of said roads, it shall be the duty of the Commissioners of the roads to which he or they may belong, to give twenty days notice by advertisement in one or more of the most public places in the county aforesaid, of the time and place of their meeting, and a majority of them on the day pointed out, shall determine on the excuse of any such delinquent,

<page id="GA1813.1.P38" no="GA1813.1.39" />

and shall within ten days thereafter issue execution against such person or persons as shall not have rendered to them a sufficient excuse.</p><p> 5 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all laws and parts of laws militating against the provisions of this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 30th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N019" initial.page="39"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To extend the powers of the Commissioners of the town of Milledgeville.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the Commissioners of the town of Milledgeville shall have power to let or lease to any of the lot holders of said town, any part of the Commons of said town where the timber is exhausted, for a term in their discretion not exceeding three years, for the purpose of having the same cleared of the under growth and put in a state of cultivation, to be delivered over to the said Commissioners, or their successors in office, under a

<page id="GA1813.1.P39" no="GA1813.1.40" />

good enclosure at the expiration of the time for which the same may have been let or leased.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Commissioners aforesaid shall have power to make and establish any bye-laws or ordinances which they may deem necessary to prevent the extravagant waste of timber on the Commons of the town aforesaid<i>provided,</i> such bye-laws or ordinances shall not be repugnant to the Constitution and laws of this state.</p><p> 3 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all laws and parts of laws which militate against this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N020" initial.page="40"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the Judges of the Superior courts to grant writs of <i>ne [Illegible Text]</i> in certain cases therein mentioned.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS great evils have, and do yet exist in this state, in consequence of the law of England regulating writs of <i>ne exeat,</i> not having provided for cases where the demand set forth by the complainant is not due; and whereas no provision is made for cases of joint obligors or

<page id="GA1813.1.P40" no="GA1813.1.41" />

joint and several obligors when a part of them remove, or are about removing without the jurisdictional limits of this state, without making satisfaction to the obligee or to the other obligor or obligors, by reason whereof, the payment of the debt devolves on the obligor or obligors who remain within the state, and that too without the possibility of compelling the obligors or obligor removing, to pay or secure the payment of their proportionable part to the obligee or the complaining obligorsFor remedy whereof;</p><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passage of this act, the Judges of the Superior courts shall, and are hereby authorized to grant writs of <i>ne exeat</i> as well in cases where the debt or demand is not actually due, but exist fairly and bona fide in expectancy at the time of making application, as in cases where the demand is due; and all the proceedings shall be as heretofore practised in this state in restraining the person and property of the defendant until he secures to the complainant the payment of the demand, or shew good cause to the court why he should not pay the sameall other proceedings to be in the same way as is practised under this writ in other cases.</p><p> 2. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That in case of joint or joint and several obligors if any one or more of them are about to remove without the jurisdictional limits of this state, and are carrying off their property, leaving one or more fellow obligors bound with them for the payment of any debt, penalty, or for the delivery of property at a certain

<page id="GA1813.1.P41" no="GA1813.1.42" />

time, which time has not arrived at the time of such removal, such obligor or obligors who remain, shall have the benefit of the writ of <i>ne exeat</i> to compel the removing obligor to secure the payment of his part of the debt, penalty, or of the delivery of the property; and also in cases of security, the security shall have all the benefit of the writ of <i>ne exeat</i> against his principal or fellow security where the obligation or debt is not yet due, and the principal or either of the securities are about removing without the state<i>provided nevertheless,</i> that in all cases arising under this act, the party complaining shall pursue the legal form and course of law as heretofore practised in this stateany thing herein contained to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N021" initial.page="42"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To amend an act, for the regulation and government of the town and commons of Brunswick.</fulltitle><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the Commissioners of the town and commons of Brunswick be, and

<page id="GA1813.1.P42" no="GA1813.1.43" />

the same are hereby nominated and appointed Commissioners of the Academy of the said county, and are fully authorized to sue and to be sued,  to do all things that may be necessary to recover such monies as may be due for rent or otherwise to the former Commissioners of the aforesaid town and commons.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That William Page, Henry Dubignon, Gee Dupree, Leighton Willson and William Huston be, and the same are hereby declared to be Commissioners for the town and commons and Academy aforesaid.</p><p> 3. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That from  after the passing of this act, that not more than one fourth of the future rent of said commons shall be appropriated to the Court house and Jailany law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 3d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N022" initial.page="43"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize Constables to open and attend elections in certain cases.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of oresaid,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, it shall

<page id="GA1813.1.P43" no="GA1813.1.44" />

be lawful for Constables to open and attend all elections which may be held in this state, in cases where a Sheriff cannot be obtained to perform said duties.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 3d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N023" initial.page="44"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To make permanent the scite of the public buildings in the county of Montgomery, and to authorize the Justices of the Inferior court of said county to select and draw Grand and Petit Jurors for Spring Term, 1814.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That the scite lately fixed on by the Commissioners heretofore appointed for that purpose in the county of Montgomery, and their proceedings in relation thereto, be, and the same are hereby confirmed, and that the scite fixed on by said commissioners be known and called by the name of Mount Vernon.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it also enacted,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court of Montgomery county, or a majority of them be, and they are hereby authorized

<page id="GA1813.1.P44" no="GA1813.1.45" />

to select and draw Grand and Petit Jurors for Spring Term, 1814.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 30th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N024" initial.page="45"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To legalize a certain description of Grants which have heretofore or may hereafter be issued by the proper authority in this state.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it has so happened in the course of Divine Providence, that a number of persons after having performed valuable services to the state,  were entitled to bounties of land for their services, have departed this life before grants have issued for the same, and whereas several persons since drawing lands in the late Land Lottery, have died before the issuing of grants for the land; and whereas a number of grants have been issued by the Governor of this state to persons after death, and as doubts exist as to the validity of such grants;</p><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the</i>

<page id="GA1813.1.P45" no="GA1813.1.46" />

<i>same,</i> That all grants which have, or may be issued by the Governor of this state to persons who have or may be dead before the issuing or signing of the same, shall be deemed, held and considered as valid and legal in law, as if the said grantee or grantees had been alive at the time of the issuing and signing of said grant or grants, and as such submitted to the juryany law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all grants which have, or may be issued by the Governor of this state to females who have intermarried, or may hereafter intermarry previous to the issuing and signing of the same, shall be deemed, held and considered as valid and legal in law, as if the said grantee or grantees had remained unmarried at the time of issuing and signing said grant or grants, and as such submitted to the jury, any law to the contrary notwithstanding; <i>provided,</i> nothing in this act contained, shall be so construed as to authorize the admission of any grant or grants in courts issued for lands on the south side of the Oconee river prior to the late land lotteries.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P46" no="GA1813.1.47" />

<law id="L1813V1N025" initial.page="47"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the Commissioners of the Academy and town of Washington in Wilkes county to open and keep open the streets of the said town, and to extend the corporation of the same.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, the Commissioners of the Academy and town of Washington, or a majority of them, shall have full power to open, and keep open the streets of the said town, agreeable to the original plan for laying off the aforesaid town;  the said Commissioners, or a majority of them, are hereby authorized  vested with full and complete power to remove, or cause to be removed, all obstructions or encroachments which now are, or shall hereafter be put in the streets of the said town<i>provided,</i> nothing herein contained shall authorize the said Commissioners to remove or cause to be removed any dwelling house, store house, shop, or gin house, chimneys, piazzas, sheds or porches, as the case may be, which is now erected.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if the original plan of the said town of Washington shall have been lost or so [Illegible Text] that the Commissioners of the said town cannot procure the same, then and in that case, they, or a majority of them, are authorized to employ a Surveyor or Surveyors, who may proceed to run and lay off the streets of the said town as

<page id="GA1813.1.P47" no="GA1813.1.48" />

nearly as possible in conformity with the original plan of the said town, from the best information in their power; <i>provided,</i> such Surveyor or Surveyors in running and laying off said streets, shall in no instance interfere with any dwelling house, store house, shop, or gin house, chimneys, piazzas, sheds or porches, as the case may be, already erected.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the town corporation of the town of Washington in the county of Wilkes is hereby extended around said town one half mile distance; any law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N026" initial.page="48"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the Justices of the Inferior court for the counties of Tatnall and Emanuel to draw grand and petit jurors.</fulltitle><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That it shall  may be lawful for the Justices of the Inferior court for the counties of

<page id="GA1813.1.P48" no="GA1813.1.49" />

Tatnall and Emanuel, or a majority of them to meet at the Court-house or place [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] holding courts in the said counties, on a day to be fixed on by them, and shall then and there [Illegible Text] to draw Grand and Petit Jurors to serve [Illegible Text] the ensuing Spring Term of the courts in said countiesany law, usage or custom to the contrary [Illegible Text].</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 20th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N027" initial.page="49"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To amend the Militia laws of this state.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS by the militia laws of this state, it is made the duty of the respective Regimental Courts to proceed to lay off any new Regimental Battalion or company district, or to make alteration in any that has been heretofore laid off, and when so laid off or altered, to be designated by certain lines and bounds, and recorded by the Clerk of the Regimental Court of EnquiryAnd whereas there is no provision made by law, to regulate the proceedings of Battalion Courts of Enquiry where such Battalions are not included within the lines and bounds of any Regiment heretofore laid off and designated, and which lines and bounds have been recorded by the Clerk of the Regimental Court of Enquiry, or in counties containing but one Battalion, and not attached to any RegimentFor remedy whereof;</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P49" no="GA1813.1.50" />

<p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That in any Battalion in this state, not included within the bounds of any Regimental district heretofore laid out, and recorded by the Clerk of the Regimental Court of Enquiry, or in counties containing but one Battalion which is not attached to any Regiment, any such Battalion shall have power and authority to hold Battalion Courts of Enquiry, and shall have and exercise the same powers as are allowed by law to Regimental Courts of Enquiry, and shall be entitled to a Clerk, to be stiled the Clerk of the Battalion Court of Enquiry, and may proceed to record the lines and bounds of their respective company districts, and shall have power to create any new company district, or make alteration in any such as have heretofore been laid off, under the same rules and restrictions as are prescribed by law to Regimental Courts of Enquiry.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That when any defaulting officer or soldier shall have been fined for default of duty by any Company Court of Enquiry, an appeal may be had to the next Battalion Court of Enquiry that may be held in the Battalion to which such delinquent officer, or soldier may belong, and the decision of such Battalion Court of Enquiry shall be final and conclusive; and before such appeal shall be granted, the delinquent shall first make oath in writing before the presiding officer of the court under which such delinquent was fined, setting forth the excuse of such delinquent, and the officer before whom such affidavit shall be made, shall lay the same before

<page id="GA1813.1.P50" no="GA1813.1.51" />

the next Battalion Court of Enquiry as aforesaid.</p><p> 3 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That any Lieutenant Colonel or commanding officer of a Regiment, or Major or commanding officer of a Battalion not attached to any Regiment, shall be authorized to assemble the officers of his Regiment or Battalion at least one, and not exceeding two days, at any one time to hold drill musters, and that the officers shall be liable to be fined as prescribed by law for delinquents in like cases.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if any person or persons shall in future be drafted or volunteer in this state, and such drafted or volunteer person or persons shall employ a substitute, who shall be accepted by the commanding officer of such drafted or volunteer corps, the person or persons employing such substitute shall forthwith return unto the line of the militia of this state, and in cases of emergency shall be subject to all the duties which said substitute would have been liable during the period for which such substitute was employed, or during the period he may be in service.</p><p> 5 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That when the Adjutant General shall neglect to order a convention of officers within any Regiment agreeable to the fifteenth section of the militia law, passed the tenth day of December, 1807, that it shall be the duty of the Lieutenant Colonels commanding any such Regiment to order a convention of the field, staff, company and non-commissioned officers, under such rules and regulations as are prescribed by the aforesaid section; and within Regiments composed of two or more counties, it shall be the duty of the Lieutenant Colonel commanding such

<page id="GA1813.1.P51" no="GA1813.1.52" />

Regiment, to order one muster in each year by Battalion.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That it shall not be lawful for any captain or commanding officer of a company in this state to enrol any free negro or mulatto, or suffer them to stand in ranks, whereby they may be instructed in military tactics or arts of warfaresuch captain or commanding officer so offending as aforesaid, shall forfeit and pay for every such offence, a sum not exceeding twenty dollars, to be recovered before a Regimental Court of Enquiry, and moreover be subject to be cashiered by a Court Martial.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the money collected by virtue of fines imposed upon defaulters at company musters, be retained by the commanding officers of companies, to be by them appropriated to the use of the company in purchasing drums, fifes and repairing the same, and for payment and encouragement of musicians.</p><p> <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That no Regimental, Brigade or Division officer shall appoint any person to a staff office, who does not reside within the Division, Brigade or Regimental district.</p><p> 9. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all Regimental, Brigade or Division staff officers shall be bound to attend all musters or reviews of Regiments, Brigades or Divisions, and shall in case of neglect, be liable to be fined or cashiered by a Court Martial.</p><p> 10. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all officers in this State shall be permitted to uniform in blue homespun; any law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p> 11. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all acts militating

<page id="GA1813.1.P52" no="GA1813.1.53" />

with this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p><i>BENHAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N028" initial.page="53"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To point out the mode for the collection of rents, and the recovery of possession of property within the City of Savannah, and the precincts thereof.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That from and after the passage of this act, it shall and may be lawful for any person who may hereafter have rent due by any person or persons within the City of Savannah, or the precincts thereof, where the sum does not exceed thirty dollars, to make application to any Justice of the Peace within the said City of Savannah or its precincts, and obtain from the said Justice a distress warrant for the sum claimed to be due, on oath in writing for the said rent, and the same may be levied by any Constable duly qualified, on any property belonging to the said tenant or tenants; and the said Constable shall advertise and sell the same, under the same rules and regulations as other sales under execution; and if the rent due shall exceed thirty dollars, it shall

<page id="GA1813.1.P53" no="GA1813.1.54" />

and may be lawful for the Judge of the Superior court or any one of the Justices of the Inferior court of Chatham county to issue a warrant, authorizing the Sheriff or any lawful Constable of the said City, or the precincts thereof, to distrain on any property belonging to the said tenant or tenants, and advertise and sell the same as in cases of execution issuing under, and by virtue of the Judiciary act<i>provided nevertheless,</i> that the said tenant or tenants shall be entitled to replevy the goods so distrained, by making oath that the same or some part thereof distrained for, is not due, and give security for the eventual condemnation money; and in that case, it shall be the duty of such officer to return the same to the court having cognizance of the same, and the same shall be determined by a jury, as practised in other cases of claims.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That where any property may be distrained and claimed by a third person, the same shall be claimed on oath, and shall be returned and determined in like manner, and under the same rules and regulations as are by law pointed out for the trial of the right of property.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in no case a preference shall be given to persons distraining for rent, where there are any judgments against the person or property so distrained.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if any person or persons leasing or renting any lot or lots, tenement or tenements within the City of Savannah or the precincts thereof, shall fail to pay the rent at the time the same shall become due, and shall refuse to deliver possession

<page id="GA1813.1.P54" no="GA1813.1.55" />

to the lessor at the expiration of his lease, it shall  may be lawful for the Judge of the Superior court, or any one of the Justices of the Inferior court of the county of Chatham to issue a writ of possession, directed to the Sheriff or any lawful Constable of the City of Savannah or the precincts thereof, commanding the said Sheriff or Constable to deliver possession of the said lot or lots, tenement or tenements to the said lessor, which shall be by the said Sheriff or Constable forthwith executed and returned.</p><p> 5 <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all contracts for rents, whether verbal or in writing, shall bear interest from the time the same shall become due, any law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstandingand all actions commenced in any of the courts within the city of Savannah or the precincts thereof, for the recovery of rent in arrear, shall be tried at the term to which the same shall be returnable, unless good cause shall be shewn for the continuance thereof; nor shall any such action be continued more than one term at the instance of either partyany law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all laws militating against this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P55" no="GA1813.1.56" />

<law id="L1813V1N029" initial.page="56"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To amend and repeal the second and third sections of an act, entitled an act, to authorize the Clerks of the Superior and Inferior courts, Clerks of the Courts of Ordinary, Sheriffs, Coroners and Surveyors to hold their offices during the intervention between the election and commissioning of their successors, and to regulate the transfer of papers and monies, passed the thirteenth of December, 1809.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, that so much of the second and third sections of the before recited act as compels Clerks of the Superior, Clerks of the Inferior and Clerks of the Courts of Ordinary to make and return a schedule of all the papers appertaining to their, offices, thirty days before the election of county officers to the Inferior courts of their counties, be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That it shall be the duty of the Clerks aforesaid, to deliver over to their successors in office rspectively, all the books and papers appertaining to their respective offices within five days after their successors are qualified<i>provided,</i> that the said Clerks shall make out and deliver to their successors in office respectively upon oath, a fair and correct schedule

<page id="GA1813.1.P56" no="GA1813.1.57" />

[Illegible Text] all the papers relative to any unfinished business in their said offices respectively in term bundles, and all other papers and books appertaining to said office in good order.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all Sheriffs, Coroners and Clerks of any of the courts of this state, shall at any and all times be subject to the order and rule of said courts, after they have retired from their respective offices, in such cases and in like manner as they would have been, had they remained in office.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N030" initial.page="57"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To vest in, and secure to John Willson of the City of Augusta, his heirs and assigns forever, certain property devised and bequeathed to him by John Willson, lately also of the City of Augusta, deceased.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS by the last [Illegible Text] and Testament of John Willson, esq. late of the City of Augusta, deceased, certain property, both real and personal, was devised and bequeathed to John Willson, Nephew and partner of the testatorAnd whereas certain technical words deemed necessary to

<page id="GA1813.1.P57" no="GA1813.1.58" />

vest the fee simple and absolute estate in the said devisee and legatee are omitted in said Will; And whereas it appears evident that the testator intended by his said Will, to create an estate in fee, and absolutely to vest the property in the said John Willson his Nephew;</p><p> 1 <i>Be it therefore enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That all the property, as well real as personal, devised and bequeathed to the said John Willson, by the last Will and Testament of John Willson, late of Augusta, deceased, shall be, and the same is hereby vested as fully and absolutely in him the said John Willson, as if words of perpituity, or words of inheritance had been used and inserted in the Will of the said deceasedany law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N031" initial.page="58"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To alter and change the names of certain persons therein mentioned.</fulltitle><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That

<page id="GA1813.1.P58" no="GA1813.1.59" />

from and after the passing of this act, William Cade of Camden county shall be known and called by the name of William Hopkins.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, James Clement, William Clement, Jonathan Clement and Charles Clement of Scriven county shall be called and known by the names of James Platt, William Platt, Jonathan Platt and Charles Platt.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 20th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N032" initial.page="59"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To adda part of Clarke county to the county of Madison.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passage of this act, all that part of Clarke county which would be included by a line commencing where the Madison county line intersects the Clarke county line, thence along the dividing ridge between the waters of Beaver dam  Brushy creeks, to the head of Brushy creek, including all the waters of the same, thence to where the Jackson

<page id="GA1813.1.P59" no="GA1813.1.60" />

county line crosses Little Sandy creek, shall be added to, and become a part of the county of Madison, and that the county Surveyor of Madison be, and is hereby authorized to run, and plainly mark the lines herein contemplated<i>provided nevertheless,</i> that the county of Clarke shall not be chargeable with any part of the expence thereof.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 20th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N033" initial.page="60"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To extend the powers of the Commissioners of the court-house and Jail of the county of Madison.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS, in and by virtue of an act of the General Assembly of this state, laying out the county of Madison, the Justices of the Inferior court of the county aforesaid, or a majority of them, were authorized amongst other things, to purchase fifty acres of land for the purpose of fixing thereon the scite of the public buildings for said county, and to lay off the same into lots, and to sell the said lots under certain restrictions,  to apply the proceeds thereof to the building the Court-house and Jail of said county,  for other county purposes,

<page id="GA1813.1.P60" no="GA1813.1.61" />

and to contract for the building the Court house and Jail for said county;</p><p>And whereas the said Justices of the Inferior court have proceeded to contract for the building the Court-house of said county, and have also made sale of a number of lotsAnd whereas it is expedient that the same Commissioners, or a majority of them, should continue to act as Commissioners, so far as to carry into effect and complete the contract by them made, for the building the Court-house of said county, and to execute titles to such lots as they may have sold;</p><p> 1 <i>Be it therefore enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That Edward Ware, James Sanders, William Furgus, Isaac Strickland and Charles Sorrells, or a majority of them shall be, and they are hereby authorized to act as Commissioners, so far as to empower them, or a majority of them, to execute titles to such lots as they may have heretofore sold, and to carry into effect and complete the contract by them made for building the Court-house of said county<i>provided nevertheless</i> that in case they should refuse or neglect to perform the several duties herein required of them, then  in that case, the Justices of the Inferior court of said county for the time being, or their successors in office, or a majority of them, shall have full power and authority to do and perform the same.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court of the aforesaid county of Madison for the time being, and their successors in office, or a majority of them, shall be considered as Commissioners of the Court-house and Jail of

<page id="GA1813.1.P61" no="GA1813.1.62" />

said county, and clothed with the same powers as are given to the Justices of the Inferior court of the county of Madison, by an act of the General Assembly of this state, passed on the fifth day of December, eighteen hundred and eleven.</p><p> 3 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all acts, and parts of acts, which militate against this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N034" initial.page="62"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>Giving time to John Hardee to pay up money due by him to this state.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That so much money as is now due by Major John Hardee of Camden county to this state, as the security of Joseph Crews, Tax Collector for the years 1805, 6 and 7, in Camden county, shall be paid by him the said Major John Hardee into the Treasury of this state at the following periods, and in the following manner, viz: one third on the tenth day of November eighteen hundred and fourteen; one third on the tenth

<page id="GA1813.1.P62" no="GA1813.1.63" />

day of November eighteen hundred and fifteen; and the remaining one third on the tenth day of November eighteen hundred and sixteen<i>provided,</i> the said John Hardee gives bond and security to the Justices of the Inferior court of said county, in the amount due, payable to the Governor or his successors in office, with eight per cent interest on the sum found to be due.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 2d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N035" initial.page="63"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>Supplemental to an act, entitled an act, securing to Joseph Hill, his heirs and assigns, the exclusive right of erecting three toll bridges across Savannah river and its branches, and raising causeways across Hutchinson's island and other islands in the said river.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the said Joseph Hill, his heirs and assigns, shall be authorized to establish a ferry

<page id="GA1813.1.P63" no="GA1813.1.64" />

from the City of Savannah to Proctor's point, so called, in South Carolina, and that he or they shall be entitled to demand and receive for the conveyance of passengers and all others crossing said Ferry, the same toll as is authorized in and by the aforesaid recited act, to which this is a supplement.</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That this act shall continue in force until the said Joseph Hill, his heirs and assigns shall have built and completed the bridges and causeways mentioned in the before recited act<i>provided</i> that said bridges and causeways are built and completed within the period therein mentioned.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N036" initial.page="64"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the Justices of the Inferior court of the county of Madison to levy an extra tax.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the stage of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court of the county of Madison, or a majority of them be, and they are hereby authorized to levy an extra tax on the inhabitants and taxable property of

<page id="GA1813.1.P64" no="GA1813.1.65" />

said county for one year, which shall not exceed one fifth part of the general tax of said county; and the Collector of said county shall be entitled to receive two and a half per cent for collecting and paying over the same, which shall be collected in the same manner as the general tax of said county, to be applied to county purposes.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 20th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N037" initial.page="65"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To define the line dividing the counties of Columbia and Warren.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That Reuben Y Langston of Columbia county and P. Petit of Warren county be, and they are hereby authorized to run and plainly mark the line dividing said counties, beginning at Watson's old mill on Sweet water, running from thence to the old path at Hodgin's old place, known by the name of the old line path, where R. Lazenbury now lives, so as to leave said lazenbury in Warren county, from thence a direct line to Stark's old mill on Little river; and that the said Surveyors be entitled to receive for their

<page id="GA1813.1.P65" no="GA1813.1.66" />

trouble, the sum of twenty five dollars each, to be paid by the Inferior courts of their respective counties<i>provided,</i> that should either of the persons appointed by this act die or become unable to perform the duties herein assigned him, it shall then be lawful for the Justices of the Inferior court of the county where such failure may happen, to appoint some other fit and proper person to run the said line, in his or their room and stead.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N038" initial.page="66"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To organize the detachments of men which may hereafter be required by the President of the United States, from the Executive of this state for the service of the Union, and for other purposes therein expressed.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the twenty-fifth day of December instant, that when any detachment of [Illegible Text] may be required of this state by the proper authority, for the service of the United

<page id="GA1813.1.P66" no="GA1813.1.67" />

States, or for the service of this state, it shall be the duty of the Adjutant General of this state to apportion the numbers required from the several Divisions and Brigades, and to give orders to the respective Brigade Inspectors, whose duty it shall be to apportion the requisition required of the several Regiments, [Illegible Text] and Companies within the Brigade to which such Brigade Inspector may belong; and out of each Regiment, Battalion or Company, to raise by draft or otherwise, the proportion required from each Regiment, Battalion or Company.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That it shall be the duty of the general officer or officers commanding any detachment or detachments of militia of this state, which may hereafter be called out in the service of the United States, or of this state, either at the place of rendezvous or at his encampment, immediately to [Illegible Text] to hold an election for Regimental, Battalion or Company officers as the case may require.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all persons shall be entitled to vote at such elections who will be subject to the command of such officer or officers when so elected, and it shall be the duty of the General or commanding officer with two or more commanding officers of the said detachment not being candidates themselves, to preside at, and [Illegible Text] such elections; and the person or persons (as the case may be,) having the highest number of votes, shall be considered duly elected for the term of time for which the said detachment was called into service, unless such officer should be cashiered or otherwise suspended from office according to the laws and [Illegible Text] now

<page id="GA1813.1.P67" no="GA1813.1.68" />

in force for the government and regulation of such detachments<i>provided also,</i> that it shall be the duty of such presiding officers, or a majority of them, forth with after such election, to certify the person having the highest number of votes to the commanding officer of the detachment, whose duty it shall be to brevet such officer for the term of time aforesaid, and all such officers shall be obeyed in the same manner as if they, or either of them, had been elected and commissioned according to the militia law in force in this state.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That it shall be the duty of the several Lieutenant Colonels of Regiments, or Majors, in counties containing but one Battalion, whenever they, or either of them, may be required to furnish any Company or detachment of militia for the use of the United States, or for the use of this state, to convene the said Company or [Illegible Text] so required as aforesaid at some fit and convenient place, and then and there forth with proceed to an election for officers to command said company or detachment; and all persons shall be entitled to vote at such elections who will be subject to the command of such officers when so elected; and it shall be the duty of two or more commissioned officers, themselves not being candidates, to preside at, and superintend such elections; and the person or persons, (as the case may be) having the highest number of votes shall be considered as duly elected for the term of time for which the said detachment or detachments were called into service, unless such officer shall be cashiered or [Illegible Text] suspended from office according to the laws land regulations now in force for the government and regulation

<page id="GA1813.1.P68" no="GA1813.1.69" />

of such detachment<i>provided also,</i> that it shall be he duty of such presiding officers, or a majority of them, forth with after such election, to certify the person having the highest number of votes to the commanding officer of the detachment, whose duty it shall be to brevet such officer or officers for the term of time aforesaid; and all such officers shall be obeyed in the same manner as if they, or either of them had been elected and commissioned according to the militia law now in force in this state.</p><p> 5 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That nothing in this act contained, shall be so construed as to prevent any person from raising Volunteer Companies for the use of the United States, or this state, when called for as as aforesaid, who shall be breveted by the officer commanding for the term of time aforesaid; and it shall be the duty of all the Volunteers under such officer to obey him in the same manner as if he had been elected according to the regulations of the before recited act; and the Lieutenants and Ensigns of all such Companies so formed shall be elected and breveted in the same manner, and under the same restrictions as expressed in the before recited act.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in any [Illegible Text] division in this state where there are a sufficient number of Cavalry to form a Squadron, and not a sufficient number to form a Regiment, and where there has been no Colonel elected to command the same, the same shall be commanded by a Major; and it shall be the duty of the Major General commanding such Division to order an election accordingly, giving at least forty days notice of the time and place of holding such

<page id="GA1813.1.P69" no="GA1813.1.70" />

election, by advertisement, at two or more of the most public places within such Division; and that the Cavalry in the fifth Division shall be considered attached to the said Division.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all laws, or parts of laws heretofore passed in this state, militating against this act shall be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives,</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N039" initial.page="70"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize John [Illegible Text] to establish a ferry across the [Illegible Text] river, the landings of said ferry on the premises of said John Jeter.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That John [Illegible Text], his heirs and assigns shall have a right to keep a ferry on the Oconee river, at or near the [Illegible Text] where his flat at present crosses said river, on his own land, on a road leading from Hancock county to [Illegible Text] county, liable to the same [Illegible Text] and [Illegible Text] as other [Illegible Text] in said

<page id="GA1813.1.P70" no="GA1813.1.71" />

countiesany law usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 2d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N040" initial.page="71"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To relievethe purchasers of lots in the town of Sumpterville.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court of the county of Laurens, [Illegible Text] their successors in office are hereby authorized to pay over to the purchasers of lots in the town of Sumpterville, all such [Illegible Text] of money as may have been paid by the said purchasers to the Inferior court of said county, on account of such purchases, with interest from the time said money was received until paid to said purchasers out of any of the county funds not otherwise appropriated; and to deliver up to the said purchasers, all their notes or bonds that may have been given them on account of said lots, on the said purchasers giving up their titles to the said lots.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Justices

<page id="GA1813.1.P71" no="GA1813.1.72" />

of the Inferior court, or a majority of them, are hereby authorized to dispose of the square of land belonging to said county, at the place called Sumpterville, on such terms, and in such manner, as they, or a majority of them, may think expedient, and that it shall be the duty of the the said Justices to pay over to the Clerk of the Inferior court, the proceeds of such sales for county purposes.</p><p> 3 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all laws, and parts of laws, which militate against this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N041" initial.page="72"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the Judge of the Superior courts of the Middle Circuit to hold an extra session in the county of Washington.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS there was a failure of the Superior court which should have been holden in and for Washington county, on the first Monday in November instantand whereas inconveniencies are likely to result therefrom; For remedy whereof;</p><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of</i>

<page id="GA1813.1.P72" no="GA1813.1.73" />

<i>Representatives of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Judge of the Superior courts for the Middle Circuit be, and he is hereby authorized and empowered to hold in and for the said county of Washington, a court on the second Monday in January next; and that all officers of said court, jurors and witnesses be required to attend under the same penalties and like restrictions as if said court had been holden at the period heretofore pointed out by law for the holding of said court.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the jury drawn to serve at the court which should have been holden in  for the said county of Washington, on the first Monday in November instant, be considered, held and taken as the jury for the term to be holden in pursuance of this act.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That all and every person and persons who were bound by recognizance or otherwise, to attend the court which should have been holden in Washington county, on the first Monday in November instant, and who shall not have been discharged by due course of law be, and they are hereby required under the same penalties to attend the court which shall be holden in pursuance of this act.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 30th November, 1813.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P73" no="GA1813.1.74" />

<law id="L1813V1N042" initial.page="74"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the judge the Ocmulgee district to hold an extra session in the county of Baldwin.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS there was a failure of the Superior court which should have been holden in and for the county of Baldwin, on the third Monday in September lastand whereas inconveniences are likely to result therefrom; For remedy whereof;</p><p> 1 <i>BE it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Judge of the Superior court of the Ocmulgee Circuit be, and he is hereby authorized and empowered to hold a court in and for the said county of Baldwin, on the fourth Monday in January next, and that all officers of said court, jurors and witnesses be required to attend under the same penalties, and under the like restrictions, as if the said court had been holden on the third Monday in September last.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the jury drawn to serve at the court which should have been holden in and for the said county of Baldwin, on the third Monday in September last, be considered, held and taken as the jury for the term to be holden in pursuance of this act.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all and every person and persons who were bound by recognizance or otherwise to attend the court which should have been holden in Baldwin county, on the third Monday

<page id="GA1813.1.P74" no="GA1813.1.75" />

in September last, and who shall not have been discharged by a due course of law be, and they are hereby required under the same penalties to attend the court which shall be holden in pursuance of this act.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N043" initial.page="75"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To alter the time of holding the Superior courts for the county of Wilkes, and allowing the entering of appeals as pointed out by this act.</fulltitle><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, the Superior courts to be held for the county of Wilkes, shall be on the third Monday in January, and the first Monday in June in each yearany law to the contrary notwithstanding</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all writs and processes heretofore issued, or which may issue, shall be returned and tried on the third Monday in January and the first Monday in June, in the same manner they would otherwise have

<page id="GA1813.1.P75" no="GA1813.1.76" />

been, had not the times for holding said [Illegible Text] been altered and changed by this act.</p><p> 3 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all jurors, witnesses, parties to suits, or other persons whatsoever concerned, shall give their attendance on the aforesaid third Monday in January and first Monday in June, as punctually as if thereto summonedany law or usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in all cases, in any of the counties of this state, where a failure to hold adjourned courts may have prevented persons entitled to an appeal from the benefit of said appeal, the court at their next regular session thereafter shall allow said persons to appeal in manner and form as they would have been entitled to appeal at said adjourned courtsany law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives,</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, [Illegible Text].</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N044" initial.page="76"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To make permanent the scite of the public buildings in Telfair county.</fulltitle><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority</i>

<page id="GA1813.1.P76" no="GA1813.1.77" />

<i>of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, the place for building the Court-house and Jail for the county of Telfair shall be on part of lot Number three hundred and forty in the eighth district Wilkinson, now Telfair county.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That as soon as the Court-house is built on said lot, all courts and elections which the law requires to be held at the Court-house, shall be held and conducted at the Court house aforesaid, and the same shall become the permanent scite of the public buildings for the county of Telfairany law to the contrary notwithstanding</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that the Justices of the Inferior court, or a majority of them, for the county aforesaid, shall be authorized and empowered to lay off and sell as many lots as they may deem necessary to defray the expences of building the Court house and Jail in said county.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior court, or a majority of them for the county aforesaid, after giving thirty days notice at three or more public places in said county, shall proceed to let out the building of the Court-house and Jail at public out-cry to the lowest bidder.</p><p><i>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</i></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives,</p><p><i>WILLIAM RABUN,</i></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 30th November, [Illegible Text].</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P77" no="GA1813.1.78" />

<law id="L1813V1N045" initial.page="78"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize Ezekiel Dubose to erect a ferry across Savannah river at his plantation in the county of Lincoln</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it will be of general good to the community, that a ferry should be established at the plantation of the said Ezekiel Dubose;</p><p> 1. <i>BE it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the aforesaid Ezekiel Dubose, his heirs and assigns are hereby authorized and empowered, so far as the Legislature of the state of Georgia can invest him or them, to erect a ferry across Savannah river, at his plantation and be entitled to demand and receive the following rates of ferriage or toll, to witfor a loaded waggon, team and driver, seventy-five cents; for an empty waggon, team, and driver, fifty cents; for a four wheel pleasure carriage, fifty cents; for a two wheel pleasure carriage, twenty five cents; for a loaded cart, team and driver, twenty five [Illegible Text] for an empty cart, team and driver, eighteen  three fourth cents; for every rolling hogs-head, team and driver, twenty-five cents; for a horse and rider, twelve and a half cents; for every led horse, ass or mule, six and a quarter cents; for each head of cattle, two cents; for each head of hogs, sheep or goats, one cent; and for each foot passenger, six and a quarter cents.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That this act shall continue and be in full force and effect for the term of seven years from  after the first day of January eighteen hundred

<page id="GA1813.1.P78" no="GA1813.1.79" />

and fourteenany law to the contrary notwithstanding<i>provided,</i> the same does not interfere with the established rights of any other ferry.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 6th December, 1818.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N046" initial.page="79"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>For the relief of John D'Antignac, Esq. Tax Collector for the county of Richmond, for 1812.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS John D'Antignac, Esq by his petition, addressed to the Senate  House of Representatives of this state, has prayed relief in relation to a large sum of money stated to have been stolen from him on the 9th instant, and which sum amounting to nearly fifteen hundred dollars, was a part of the taxes collected for the county of Richmond for 1812: And the fact of the loss of said money being confirmed by affidavit;</p><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the said John D'Antignac, esquire, be compeled to pay into the Treasury of this state the balance due by him as Tax Collector for the county of Richmond, for the year

<page id="GA1813.1.P79" no="GA1813.1.80" />

1812, in three separate instalments, to witon the fifteenth day of November 1814, the sum of five hundred dollars; on the fifteenth day of November 1815, the sum of five hundred dollars; and on the fifteenth day of November 1816, the balance which shall then be due<i>provided,</i> the said John D'Antignac shall give good and sufficient security to His Excellency the Governor, for the payment of the aforesaid sums at the times therein respectively mentioned, which security shall be approved of by the Inferior court of Richmond county.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p>PETER EARLY, <i>Governor.</i></p><approvaldate>Assented to, 3d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N047" initial.page="80"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To sell and dispose of the State-house Lots and Public Square in the town of Louisville.</fulltitle><p> 1. <i>BE it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized to empower one or more proper persons to sell and dispose of the State-house in Louisville, together with the lots or public

<page id="GA1813.1.P80" no="GA1813.1.81" />

square belonging to the state to the highest bidder, taking bond and approved security from the purchaser, payable in three equal annual instalments, first giving public notice in two or more of the public Gazettes of this state at least sixty days previous to the sale thereof.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 2d Decembe,r [Illegible Text].</approvaldate></law><law id="L1813V1N048" initial.page="81"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorize the fortunate drawers in the late land lotteries of this state to take out their grants until the tenth day of November 1814, and after that day to authorize any citizen of this state to take out grants in said Lotteries.</fulltitle><p> 1 <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That all persons who may have drawn land in the late land lotteries of this state, or their legal representatives, be at liberty to take out grants for the lots of land drawn by them respectively, on payment of the office fees, until the

<page id="GA1813.1.P81" no="GA1813.1.82" />

tenth day of November eighteen hundred and fourteenany law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p> 2 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That after the tenth day of November next, any person or persons, citizens of this state, who shall apply at the necessary offices, may on payment of the usual fees for taking out grants in the late land lotteries of this state, take out and receive in his own name, a grant for any one lot of land in either of the land lotteries in this state, which shall not be then granted<i>provided,</i> that no person shall be authorized to take out a grant for any lot drawn by any orphan or orphans not then of age, and having no legal representative in the state.</p><p>BENJAMIN WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 2d December, 1813.</approvaldate></law></part>

<page id="GA1813.1.P82" no="GA1813.1.83" type="INFERRED" />

<part><title><b>RESOLUTIONS,</b><br set="CENTER"><i>Which originated in the House of Representatives.</i><br set="CENTER" /></br></title><law id="R1813V1N049" initial.page="83" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Wednesday, 3d November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That the two branches of the Legislature convene in the Representative Chamber, on Saturday next, at ten o'clock, for the purpose of electing a Health Officer and Harbor Master for the City of Savannah</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N050" initial.page="83" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 4th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That [Illegible Text] Barrett, Frasier and Campbell be, and they are hereby appointed Vendue Masters for the City of Augusta, for the year eighteen hundred and fourteen.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N051" initial.page="83" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 5th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Thomas W Grimes be, and he is hereby appointed Vendue Master for the town of Greensborough, in the county of Greene.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N052" initial.page="83" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 6th, 1815.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Harris Allen and Alexander

<page id="GA1813.1.P83" no="GA1813.1.84" />

Greene be, and they are hereby appointed [Illegible Text] Masters for the town of Milledgeville.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N053" initial.page="84"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 5th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Joseph Hutchinson, Esq. be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the City of Augusta and county of Richmond.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N054" initial.page="84"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 6th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That James Hunter be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Chatham.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N055" initial.page="84"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 8th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Thomas Dawson be, and he is hereby appointed Notary Public for the county of Greene and town of Greensborough.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N056" initial.page="84"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 10th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That John R. Brown be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Franklin and Village of Carnesville.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N057" initial.page="84"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 5th 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Hezekiah Luckie, Esq. be, and he is hereby appointed a Trustee of Meson Academy

<page id="GA1813.1.P84" no="GA1813.1.85" />

in the county of Oglethorpe, in the place of Doctor George Phillips, removed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N058" initial.page="85"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 5th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That William G. Porter, Esq. be, and he is hereby appointed a Commissioner of the Academy of the county of Effingham, in place of Thomas Polhill, esq. removed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N059" initial.page="85"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 9th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Allen B Powell, esq be appointed Commissioner of the Wayne county Academy, in place of Benjamin Liles, esq. removed out of the county.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N060" initial.page="85"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 9th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Miles Gathwright and James Ware be appointed Commissioners of public buildings for the county of Twiggs, in place of John Hardin and Lovett B. Smith, resigned.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N061" initial.page="85"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 10th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Charles M'Kennon and James A. Rogers, esquires, be appointed Commissioners of the Academy of Telfair county, to fill the vacancies of Benjamin G. Cray and Thomas Mitchell, esquires, who reside in that part of Telfair

<page id="GA1813.1.P85" no="GA1813.1.86" />

county added to Montgomery county, by an act of eighteen hundred and twelve.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N062" initial.page="86"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 10th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Richard Walker, esquire, be appointed Commissioner of the Court-house and Jail for the county of Wayne, in place of Benjamin Liles, esq. removed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N063" initial.page="86"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 5th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That His Excellency the Governor be requested to lay before this House, information of the proceedings that have been had on the bond of Adams and Duyckinck, who contracted to print the Laws and Resolutions of this state, since the political year eighteen hundred, in pursuance of a resolution of this House at the last session.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N064" initial.page="86"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 6th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized and required to have the Constitution of the State of Georgia, with the several amendments [Illegible Text] printed and annexed to the laws that may be passed at the present session.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 13th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N065" initial.page="86"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 11th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That both branches of the Legislature

<page id="GA1813.1.P86" no="GA1813.1.87" />

will convene in the Representative Chamber on Wednesday next, at twelve o'clock, for the purpose of electing a Secretary of State, Comptroller General, Treasurer and Surveyor General.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 17th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N066" initial.page="87"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, November 11th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Gee Dupree, [Illegible Text] be, and he is hereby appointed Notary Public for the county of Glynn.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 20th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N067" initial.page="87"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, 15th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That the Executive appointment of David P. Hillhouse and [Illegible Text] G. Campbell, esquires, Commissioners of the Town and Academy of Washington in Wilkes county be, and the same is hereby confirmed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 20th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N068" initial.page="87"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, 16th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That the Executive appointment of John Cumming, esq. as a Commissioner of the Chatham county Academy in the place of Richard M. Stites, esq. deceased, be, and the same is hereby confirmed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 20th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N069" initial.page="87"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, 16th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That James Blair and James Hooper, esquires, be, and they are hereby appointed

<page id="GA1813.1.P87" no="GA1813.1.88" />

Commissioners of the Franklin county Academy, in addition to those heretofore appointed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 20th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N070" initial.page="88"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Friday, 3d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>The committee on Finance to whom was referred the Comptroller General's report relative to the Digest of taxable property and Tax Collectors in default,</p><div><title><i>REPORT,</i><br set="CENTER" /></title><p>That they have had the same under consideration, and are of opinion, that the law passed at the last session of the Legislature so far as respects the Receivers of Returns of taxable property (if continued,) will remedy as far as possible, the evil complained ofyour committee therefore beg leave to recommend the following resolution;</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That it is the opinion of this Legislature, that the Justices of the Inferior courts for the several counties within this state, to whom is confided the most important part of revenue, ought in future to be cautious in the taking of bonds of the several Tax Collectors within this state, that good and sufficient security be given, whereby the state shall not sustain loss; and your committee beg leave further to recommend the following resolution;</p><p>Resolved, That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby requested without delay, to put in suit all the bonds in his department against all defaulting Receivers of Returns and their securities, who have failed in forwarding the Digest to the Comptroller's officeand the Treasurer is hereby directed to issue executions against

<page id="GA1813.1.P88" no="GA1813.1.87" />

Tax Collectors and their securities, who now may be in default, and who may hereafter be in default of their taxes when they become due, and to direct each Solicitor General to move for a rule against the late Sheriffs of this state who have collected monies of Collectors, and withhold the same from the Treasury Office of this state.</p></div><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N071" initial.page="87"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Friday, 3d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>The committee on Finance to whom was referred the petition of Frederick [Illegible Text] Fell, praying compensation for printing sundry documents for the foreclosure of Mortgages on certain property in the county of Wayne, for the benefit of this state,</p><div><title><i>REPORT,</i><br set="CENTER" /></title><p>That they have taken the same under consideration, and are of opinion, that the petitioner is justly entitled to the amount stated in his account, therefore beg leave to recommend the following resolution;</p><p>Resolved, That His Excellency the Governor be requested to pay to Frederick S Fell two hundred and twenty six dollars and sixty-six cents out of the contingent fund, in full compensation for printing and publishing twenty-four Rules Nisi for the foreclosure of mortgages in the county of Wayne, for the benefit of the state; and also pay to Messrs. Grantlands and other printers the several sums due them for similar services, upon their producing satisfactory vouchers to His Excellency the Governor.</p></div><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P89" no="GA1813.1.88" />

<law id="R1813V1N072" initial.page="88"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Tuesday, 23d November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That the present Commissioners of the Jackson county Academy, or any three of them be, and they are hereby authorized and empowered to call on all or any of the former Commissioners of said Academy, or any one or more of them, who may have or may be supposed to have any of the funds, monies or credits of said Academy, or the joint Academy of Jackson and Clarke counties in their hands for settlement; and on failure to settle and pay over any money which by them appears to be due said institution, to institute in the name of said Board of Commissioners, a suit or suits for, and recover in their corporate capacity, any sum or sums of money as may be due by said former Commissioners, in any court of law or equity in this state having competent jurisdiction thereof.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 30th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N073" initial.page="88"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Wednesday, 17th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Whereas the lives and the property of the citizens of the Southern and Western frontier of this state are imminently exposed, and their condition peculiarly calamitous from their local situation, and the hazards and privations they have to encounter in consequence of being exposed to the inroads of a savage and inveterate foe; that our Eastern frontier is also exposed to the predatory incursions of a foe of equal malignance and more refined barbarity;</p><p><i>Therefore be it resolved,</i> as the sense of this Legislature, that it would be inequitable and imprudent

<page id="GA1813.1.P90" no="GA1813.1.89" />

to coerce into public service, any of the citizens inhabiting the frontier military districts of this stateand that His Excellency the Governor be authorized and requested to issue an order dispensing with the services in the field from their own frontier districts, the citizens aforesaid, during the countinuance of the present alarm, except in cases of actual invasion, or where a voluntary tender of services may be made.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 20th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N074" initial.page="89"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Tuesday, 23d November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, that the Attorney General and the Solicitors General for the Eastern and Western districts be required to report to the Governor a statement of the situation of suits commenced, and judgments obtained in their several districts on the bonds given for the purchase of reverted confiscated property, and also of the situation of the mortgages given to sesure the payment of said bonds, and that His Excellency the Governor do cause such statements to be laid before the Legislature at the next annual session, and that he do also cause the above mentioned officers to be notified of the requisitions of this resolution.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 2d December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N075" initial.page="89"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Thursday, 18th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>The committee on Finance to whom was referred the Treasurer's Abstract, have examined so much of said Abstract as relates to the Bounty Warrants issued in the names of Jere and Jeremiah Russet, together with the subject matter of

<page id="GA1813.1.P91" no="GA1813.1.90" />

John Ragan's bond, and beg leave to report, that they have had the same under consideration, and are of opinion that the Certificates or Bounty Warrants were correctly issued, therefore recommend the following resolution;</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the said Bounty Warrants, together with the Certificate of James Meriwether, Comptroller General, and the bond of John Ragan be filed in the Treasurer's office.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 30th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N076" initial.page="90"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Wednesday, November 24th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>The committee appointed to enquire into the facts relative to a violation of the non importation or non intercourse laws of the United States, and a fraud practised on the revenue of the said United States by Archibald M. Devereux and other persons, and the conduct of the honorable William Stevens, Judge of the District court of the Georgia District, and Abraham Bessent, Collector of the Port of St Mary's, being implicated by the documents submitted to your committee, they deem it a duty they owe to the good people of the State of Georgia, as well as from a sacred regard to individual character, to recommend the following resolution;</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the documents upon this subject be transmitted by His Excellency the Governor, to the Representatives of this state in the Congress of the United States, that a full and fair investigation of the conduct of the persons implicated may be had before the proper tribunal</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P92" no="GA1813.1.91" />

<law id="R1813V1N077" initial.page="91"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Friday, 12th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>The committee on the State of the Republic to whom was referred so much of the Governor's Communication as relates to the defence of the sea-coast, beg leave to</p><div><title><i>REPORT,</i><br set="CENTER" /></title><p>That they have had under consideration that important subject, and whilst it appears to them that additional protection is necessary to that exposed section of the country, they are happy to add, that they conceive there are ample means at the disposal of this Legislature to afford protection to that portion of the good people of this state who have been thus exposed to the incursions of the enemy.</p><p>They they therefore recommend that the seven hundred stand of arms, which they are informed by the Communication of the late Governor are at Point Petre, and were intended to have been distributed in the different counties bordering on the sea board, be immediately distributed in the Brigade commanded by Brigadier General John Floyd and be at the disposal of the respective Colonels in that Brigade, in the following manner, that is to say, Col Scott's Regiment two hundred; to Col Johnson's Regiment, one hundred and fifty; to Col Harden's Regiment, one hundred and fifty; and to Col. Pray's Regiment, also, two hundred; and that His Excellency the Governor be requested to furnish in addition, five hundred stand of arms, if in his power so to do, to be distributed among the different Regiments aforesaid, in equal proportions; and also, that His Excellency be requested to furnish for

<page id="GA1813.1.P93" no="GA1813.1.92" />

the use of said Brigade, sixteen hundred pounds of powder,  six thousand four hundred pounds of lead, ball or buck shot, to be disposited in equal proportions at the town of Jefferson in Camden county, and the City of Savannah, and subject to the distribution and disbursement of the Colonels of the respective Regiments in equal proportions, whose duty it shall be to guard against all improper wastes or abuse of said munitions of war, and shall stand bound at all times to return said munitions of war (which may not be unexpended) when required so to do by the proper authority.</p><p>Your committee further recommend that His Excellency the Governor be authorized and required to order two full companies of the militia to repair without delay to the sea-board, one of which to be stationed in the following counties, vizBryan, Liberty and M'Intosh, the other to be stationed in the counties of Glynn and Camden, at such place or places in each county as shall be determined upon by the Lieutenant Colonels commanding within the aforesaid counties, which companies shall remain in service for six months, subject to be relieved at the discretion of His Excellency the Governor, after they shall have served the term of two months:  if after the expiration of six months, the situation of that part of the country should still in the opinion of the Executive require the like protection, His Excellency is authorized and required to order two other companies to supply the places of those whose term of service will have then expired, to be continued in service for the like term of six months, subject to be relieved at the discretion

<page id="GA1813.1.P94" no="GA1813.1.93" />

of His Excellency the Governor after they shall have served the term of two months. And we further recommend that His Excellency the Governor be requested to make application to the General Government, and request that provision be made for support of the militia employed in the service contemplated by this resolutionAnd that in the mean time, His Excellency be required to take the necessary steps for supplying them.</p></div><approvaldate>Approved, 20th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N078" initial.page="93"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Wednesday, 2d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Whereas a resolution which lately passed both branches of this Legislature, and assented to by the Governor, authorizing an expedition against the hostile Indians, under the command of Lieutenant Colonel David Adams, and therein limits the time to be employed on said expedition to thirty days;</p><p><i>And whereas,</i> 'tis extremely probable that the time specified in the aforesaid resolution may be insufficient for the performance of any service to the country, and the object of said resolution be defeatedfor remedy whereof;</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized to extend the time for the performance of the aforesaid expedition, so far as in his opinion may be necessary to answer its object<i>provided,</i> that he shall not exceed the space of sixty days<i>and provided,</i> the corps shall agree to the extension of their time of service.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th November.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P95" no="GA1813.1.94" />

<law id="R1813V1N079" initial.page="94"><shorttitle>In the House of Representatives, Friday, 3d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to have the following acts which have passed during the present session of the General Assembly, published one time in each of the public Gazettes of this state, to wit: An act to authorize the Governor to settle with the United States the amount of Direct Tax due by the state of Georgia, and to point out the mode of reimbursing the state in part Also, an act, supplementary to, and amendatory of the alleviating law, and the act amendatory of the tax laws of this state</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N080" initial.page="94"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Monday, 29th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Alexander Irvine and James S. Bulloch be, and they are hereby appointed Notaries Public for the City of Savannah and county of Chatham.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N081" initial.page="94"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, 2d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Alexander Kean be, and he is hereby appointed a Vendue Master for the town of St. Mary's and county of Camden.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N082" initial.page="94"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Saturday, 27th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to cause the Commissioners of the Penitentiary to make a

<page id="GA1813.1.P96" no="GA1813.1.95" />

report with respect thereto; particularly as regards the monies received and expended by them, the state of forwardness of the building, and the condition of the materials purchased for its erection.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 2d December.</approvaldate></law></part><part><title><b>RESOLUTIONS,</b><br set="CENTER"><i>WHICH ORIGINATED IN SENATE.</i><br set="CENTER" /></br></title><law id="R1813V1N083" initial.page="95"><shorttitle>In Senate. 2d November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That the Senate will convene in the Representative Chamber, on Thursday next, at twelve o'clock, to proceed to the election of Governor of this state.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 4th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N084" initial.page="95"><shorttitle>In Senate, 2d November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That the Senate will convene in the Representative Chamber on Saturday next, at ten o'clock, in order to proceed to the election of a Senator from this State, to the Senate of the United States, to fill the vacancy of the Honorable William H Crawford resigned. And also four Judges of the Superior courts, vizone for the Eastern Circuit, one for the Middle Circuit, one for the Western Circuit, and one for the Oakmulgee Circuit, and also an Attorney General for the Middle Circuit, a Solicitor General for the Eastern Circuit, a Solicitor General for the Western Circuit, and one for the Oakmulgee Circuit.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th November.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P97" no="GA1813.1.96" />

<law id="R1813V1N085" initial.page="96"><shorttitle>In Senate, 2d November, 1813.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That in the opinion of this Legislature, the services of the Adjutant General of this state are necessarily required with the troops from this state, which are now in the service of the United States during their expedition against the hostile Indians.</p><p><i>Resolved also,</i> That the Adjutant General be, and he is hereby authorized to appoint an assistant to do the duties of his office in the state during his absence from the state<i>provided,</i> the Adjutant General shall pay the said assistant for his services out of his salary already provided for him by law.</p><p><i>And resolved also,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby requested, to direct the Adjutant General to repair without delay to the army now under the command of Brigadier General John Floyd.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N086" initial.page="96"><shorttitle>In Senate, <i>November</i> 9th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Whereas the murders that have been committed in Morgan county have instructed us in the species of warfare that the Indians intend against us (namely) a predatory war upon our frontier throughout its whole extent, to meet which effectually, while our troops are carrying on offensive operations in the heart of the Indian tribes, it will be necessary to establish a line of posts on the frontier, or in advance as the Executive may think expedient to order.</p><p>Be it therefore resolved, That His Excellency the Governor cause to be built Block houses, united by stockading at such points on the frontier

<page id="GA1813.1.P98" no="GA1813.1.97" />

of this state, or in advance, as he may deem advisable for the security and protection of the frontier inhabitants, and that he cause to be stationed at each fort or garrison, such number of militia as he may from time to time deem necessary, and that he be requested to apply to the Government of the United States for subsistance for the men called out under his authority, and in the mean time, that he do cause the necessary rations to be furnished</p><approvaldate>Approved, 12th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N087" initial.page="97"><shorttitle>In Senate, November 12th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Whereas it has been represented by a Communication from His Excellency the Governor, that the want of necessary supplies has considerably retarded the progress of our army, destined to act against the Creek Nation of Indians, and there being reason to believe that there are not funds sufficient at the disposal of the proper officer for the procurement of those supplies, without which, the contemplated expedition must failAnd whereas the public interest is essentially involved in the success of our army in that quarter.</p><p><i>Be it therefore resolved,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized and requested, to advance on account of the United States, for the purpose of procuring supplies for the said army, a sum of money not exceeding twenty thousand dollars, out of any funds which may be in the Treasury of this stateand should any difficulty arise from the want of money in the Treasury, His Excellency is hereby authorized and required to negotiate

<page id="GA1813.1.P99" no="GA1813.1.98" />

a loan with the Bank of Augusta or Planters Bank for the sum aforesaid, for a term not exceeding one hundred and twenty days, and for the repayment of which, to the said Bank, the faith of the state is hereby pledged.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 12th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N088" initial.page="98"><shorttitle>In Senate, 4th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Whereas the Legislatures of several states immediately after the glorious capture of the Guerrier, the Macedonian and the Java, returned their thanks to Captain Hull, to Commodore Decatur, and to Commodore Bainbridge, for these results memorable in our history;</p><p><i>And whereas</i> the time of our meeting affords us an opportunity of rendering the first Legislative tribute to Captain Perry for his most glorious victory on Lake Erie, over a superior British forcea victory the most important, and the consequences of which will be more momentous to the United States than any victory which has blessed our arms since the surrender of Cornwallis at York towna victory by which we have acquired the undisputed command of the waters of the West, from Lake Erie to the Lake of the Woods, and which has shed a blaze of light around our National Flag, which no time and no circumstance can extinguish, for neither individual subterfuge nor national vanity can subtract aught from this victory; and even England, that has felt in every contest, must acknowledge in this our superiority;</p><p><i>Be it therefore resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met,</i> on behalf of the people of Georgia, that the thanks

<page id="GA1813.1.P100" no="GA1813.1.99" />

of this Legislature, and the thanks of this people are due to Captain Perry for his indefatigable exertion in equipping the American fleet on Lake Erie, for his prompt and ready pursuit of the enemy, and for the masterly manner in which he engaged, and the unexampled intrepidity which he displayed in bearing his flag from a ruined and overwhelmed ship, to be triumphantly displayed upon another.</p><p><i>And be it further resolved,</i> That the thanks of this Legislature and of this people, are due to the officers and seamen on board the American fleet, for the able support of Captain Perry by each and every of his officers, and for the cool intrepedity displayed by our gallant seamen, which will consecrate, if any thing were necessary to consecrate the indelible affection which is born to them by their fellow citizens.</p><p><i>And be it further resolved,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be requested to transmit these resolutions to Captain Perry.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 12th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N089" initial.page="99"><shorttitle>In Senate, 10th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>The Committee on the State of the Republic to whom was referred the Governor's Communication relative to the late depredations committed by the hostile Indians on the frontier of Morgan county, beg leave to</p><div><title>REPORT,<br set="CENTER" /></title><p>That they have examined said Communication, and are gratified in saying, they highly approve of the vigilance evinced by His Excellency the Governor in adopting speedy measures for the protection and security of that part of the frontier invaded,</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P101" no="GA1813.1.100" />

<p>They also approve of the distribution of the public arms, and the provision making for the furnishing of the frontier in general with ammunition</p><p>But experience has taught us, that the most effectual means of defending our frontier against the incursions of our present insidious and artful foes is, by carrying slaughter and devastation into their own countryAnd whereas the want of provision and means of transportation, will tend very much to retard the progress of the army from Georgia, at present in the field, and almost inevitably prevent either them or the army from Tennessee from attacking and destroying the Oakfuskee or upper waring Creek towns;</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That it is the opinion of your committee, that some active vigilant officer, who may be acquainted with the Indian mode of warfare, may be tolerated and authorized by His Excellency the Governor, to raise by voluntary enrolments or tender of service, a number of mounted rifle or musket men, not less than five hundred, nor more than one thousand, each furnishing [Illegible Text] own arms and provisions, if convenient, if not by the public, for a term not less than fifteen, or more than thirty days after they shall arrive at the place of rendezvous, for the purpose of destroying the upper and most adjacent warring Creek towns, and that the expence of the expedition be paid out of the Treasury of this state, which may be set apart for military disbursements.</p></div><approvaldate>Approved, 16th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N090" initial.page="100"><shorttitle>In Senate, November 9th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Thomas H. Kenan be, and

<page id="GA1813.1.P102" no="GA1813.1.101" />

he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the County of Baldwin.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 18th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N091" initial.page="101"><shorttitle>In Senate, 11th November, [Illegible Text].</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Samuel Davis, esq. be, and he is hereby appointed Commissioner of the Academy of the county of Lincoln, in place of Gibson Clark, esq removed.</p><approvaldate>Approved 18th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N092" initial.page="101"><shorttitle>In Senate, November 9th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That William Tilman be, and he is hereby appointed a Commissioner of the Madison county Academy, in place of George Christian removed, and that John M`Curdy, Giles Harris, George Hudson and Dabney Gholson be, and they are hereby appointed Commissioners of the said Academy, in addition to those heretofore appointed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 18th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N093" initial.page="101"><shorttitle>In Senate, 11th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>The joint committee appointed to receive proposals and report on the subject of printing the Laws, the Journals and Concurred Resolutions of the present session,</p><div><title>REPORT,<br set="CENTER" /></title><p>That they have received proposals from Nicholas Childers and Seaton and Fleming Grantland, and having duly considered said proposals, are of opinion, that the terms proposed by said Seaton and Fleming Grantland, under all the circumstances, would be the most advantageous to the state. The committee do therefore recommend the following resolution;</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P103" no="GA1813.1.102" />

<p>Resolved, That Messrs Seaton and Fleming Grantland have the printing the Laws, Journals, and Concurred Resolutions of the present session of the Legislature, that is to say fifteen hundred copies of the Laws and Resolutions, and fifteen hundred copies of the Journals of each branch of the General Assembly, at the same price, and under the same regulations and restrictions, as those of the last session of the Legislature.</p></div><approvaldate>Approved, 18th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N094" initial.page="102"><shorttitle>In Senate, November 8th, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That His Excellency the Governor be authorized and requested to send on to the Major Commandant of the county of [Illegible Text], for the use of his Battalion, forty stand of arms from the public arsenal at this place, and the Major Commandant shall be authorized to contract with some proper person to make the necessary repairs to the said arms at the expence of the state, taking his receipt for the same.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 20th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N095" initial.page="102"><shorttitle>In Senate, 17th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That our Senators and Representatives in the Congress of the United States be, and they are hereby particularly requested to use their influence to have the law of Georgia of eighteen hundred and four, regulating fees of the Health Officers and Harbor Masters for the Ports of Savannah and St. Mary's, sanctioned for two years from the end of next session of Congress, that being the expiration of the time prescribed by a previous sanction.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 20th November.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P104" no="GA1813.1.103" />

<law id="R1813V1N096" initial.page="103"><shorttitle>In Senate, 22d November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Whereas a Resolution passed last session of the General Assembly, requesting and authorizing His Excellency the Governor to put in suit the bond of Adams and Duyckinck, printers, who had contracted for the printing of a compilation of the Laws and Resolutions of this state, passed since the political year 1800And in pursuance thereof, suit having been commenced, and which is now pending in the [Illegible Text] of Richmond against the said Adams and Duyckinck, and the securities, upon the bond given for the performance of said contract.</p><p><i>Be it therefore resolved,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be authorized and required to receive from the said Adams and Duyckinck or their securities, or any one of them, two thousand printed and bound copies of a compilation of the Laws of Georgia, made by A. S. Clayton, Esquire, from 1800 to 1810, so that they be executed in terms of the contractand upon the receipt thereof, the contract shall be considered as complied with and performed<i>provided,</i> the said books be delivered at the State-house in Milledgeville, on or before the first day of October next; and upon compliance with this resolution, His Excellency the Governor shall authorize and require the Attorney General to dismiss the suit so commenced, at the costs of the defendants.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 30th November.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N097" initial.page="103"><shorttitle>In Senate, 13th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That His Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized and required

<page id="GA1813.1.P105" no="GA1813.1.104" />

to contract with some fit and proper person to make the necessary repair on the arms now in the public arsenal of this state.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 3d December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N098" initial.page="104"><shorttitle>In Senate, 24th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That James M. Wayne, esq. be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Chatham</p><approvaldate>Approved, 3d December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N099" initial.page="104"><shorttitle>In Senate, 27th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Augustus Moore be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the City of Augusta and county of Richmond.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 3d December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N100" initial.page="104"><shorttitle>In Senate, 26th November, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Whereas it is the opinion of all men well informed upon the subject, and with whom experience has combined with local information, to enable them to judge justly, that a naval force affords the best protection for the defence of the sea-coast;</p><p><i>Be it therefore resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That our Senators are required, and our Representatives requested, to use their efforts with the President of the United States, and with the Secretary of the Navy, to enlarge that description of force, between the ports of Savannah and St. Mary's, more particularly necessary since the calamitous Hurricane which has occurred in this quarter.</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P106" no="GA1813.1.105" />

<p><i>And be it further resolved,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be requested to transmit this Resolution to our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 3d December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N101" initial.page="105"><shorttitle>In Senate, 1st December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That William Habersham, esq. be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Chatham.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N102" initial.page="105"><shorttitle>In Senate, 1st December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Elijah Wallis be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Pulaski.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N103" initial.page="105"><shorttitle>In Senate, 3d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That George Hudson be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Madison.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N104" initial.page="105"><shorttitle>In Senate, 3d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That [Illegible Text] Pelot and Edmund Roberts be, and they are hereby appointed Notaries Public for the county of Charham.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N105" initial.page="105"><shorttitle>In Senate, 3d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Pierson Pettit be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Warren.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1813.1.P107" no="GA1813.1.106" />

<law id="R1813V1N106" initial.page="106"><shorttitle>In Senate, 2d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Nicholas Thompson and Thomas Ard, esquires, be, and they are hereby appointed Commissioners of the Academy of Wilkinson county, in the room of Stephen Gafford and Jeremiah [Illegible Text] removed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N107" initial.page="106"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 2d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That Stephen Hoge and Warner L. Kennon, esquires, be, and they are hereby appointed Trustees of the Columbia county Academy, in place of Abraham Marshal and Nathan Crawford, esquires, resigned.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1813V1N108" initial.page="106"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 3d December, 1813.</shorttitle><p>Resolved, That James Roach, esq. be, and he is hereby appointed a Commissioner of and for the Academy of the county of Pulaski, in the place of Edmund Hogan, esq. removed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 6th December.</approvaldate></law></part>

<page id="GA1813.1.P108" no="GA1813.1.107" type="INFERRED" />

<part><title>THE<br set="CENTER"><b>CONSTITUTION</b><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><i>STATE OF [Illegible Text]</i><br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></title><law id="R1813V1N109" initial.page="107" type="INFERRED"><div><title>ARTICLE I.<br set="CENTER" /></title><p> 1. The Legislative, Executive and Judiciary Departments of Government shall be distinct, and each department shall be confided to a separate body of magistracy; and no person, or collection of persons, being of one of those departments, shall exercise any power properly [Illegible Text] to either of the others, except in the instances herein expressly permitted.</p><p> 2 The Legislative power shall be vested in two separate and distinct branches, to wit:a Senate and House of Representatives, to be styled The General Assembly.</p><p> 3. The Senate shall be elected annually on the first Monday in November, until such day of election be altered by law; and shall be composed of one member from each county, to be chosen by the electors thereof.</p><p> 4. No person shall be a Senator who shall not have attained to the age of twenty-five years; and have been nine years a citizen of the United States, and three years an [Illegible Text] of this state, and shall have usually resided within the

<page id="GA1813.1.P109" no="GA1813.1.108" />

county for which he shall be returned, at least one year immediately preceding his election, (except persons who may have been absent on public business of this state, or of the United States; and is and shall have been possessed in his own right of a settled freehold estate of the value of five hundred dollars, or of taxable property to the amount of one thousand dollars within the county, for one year preceding his electionand whose estate shall, on a reasonable estimation, be fully competent to the discharge of his just debts, over and above that sum.</p><p> 5. The Senate shall elect, by ballot, a President out of their own body.</p><p> 6. The Senate shall have the sole power to try all impeachments:When sitting for that purpose, they shall be on oath or affirmation; and no person shall be convicted, without the concurrence of two-thirds of the members present:Judgment in cases of impeachment, shall not extend further than removal from office, and disqualification to hold and enjoy any office of honor, trust or profit within this state; but the party convicted shall, nevertheless, be subject to indictment, trial, judgment and punishment, according to law</p><p> 7. The House of Representativas shall be composed of members from all the counties which now are, or hereafter may be included within this state, according to their respective numbers of free white persons, and including three-fifths of all the people of color:The actual enumeration shall be made within two years, and within every subsequent term of seven years thereafter, at such time, and in such manner, as

<page id="GA1813.1.P110" no="GA1813.1.109" />

this Convention may direct: Each county containing three thousand persons, agreeably to the foregoing plan of enumeration, shall be entitled to two members, seven thousand to three members,  twelve thousand to four members; but each county shall have at least one,  not more than four membersThe Representatives shall be chosen annually, on the first Monday in November, until such day of election be altered by law: Until the aforesaid enumeration shall be made, the several counties shall be entitled to the following number of Representatives, respectively: Camden two[Illegible Text] twoLiberty threeM'Intosh twoBryan oneChatham fourEffingham twoScriven twoMontgomery twoBurke threeBullock oneJefferson threeLincoln twoElbert threeJackson twoRichmond threeWilkes fourColumbia threeWarren three - Washington threeHancock fourGreene threeOglethorpe threeand Franklin two</p><p> 8. No person shall be a Representative who shall not have attained to the age of twenty-one years, and have been seven years a citizen of the United States, three years an inhabitant of this state, and have usually resided in the county in which he shall be chosen, one year immediately preceding his election (unless he shall have been absent on public business of this state or of the United States; and shall be possessed, in his own right, of a settled freehold estate of the value of two hundred and fifty dollars, or of taxable property to the amount of five hundred dollars, within the county, for one year preceding his election; and whose estate shall, on a reasonable

<page id="GA1813.1.P111" no="GA1813.1.110" />

estimation [Illegible Text] competent to the discharge of his just debts, over and above that sum.</p><p> 9. The House of Representatives shall choose their Speaker and other officers.</p><p> 10. They shall have solely the power to impeach all persons who have been, or may be in office.</p><p> 11. No person holding any military commission or other appointment having any emolument or compensation annexed thereto, under this state or the United States, or either of them, [except Justices of the Inferior court, Justices of the Peace, and officers of the militia,] nor any person who has had charge of public monies belonging to the state, unaccounted for and unpaid, or who has not paid all legal taxes or contributions to the government, required of him, shall have a seat in either branch of the General Assembly; nor shall any Senator or Representative be elected to any office or appointment by the Leg slature, having any emoluments or compensation annexed thereto, during the time for which he shall have been elected, with the above exceptions, unless he shall decline accepting his seat, by notice to the Executive, within twenty days after he shall have been elected; nor shall any member, after having taken his seat, be eligible to any of the aforesaid offices or appointments during the time for which he shall have been elected.</p><p> 12. The meeting of the General Assembly shall be annually on the second Tuesday in January, until such day of meeting be altered by law; a majority of each branch shall be authorized to proceed to business....but a smaller

<page id="GA1813.1.P112" no="GA1813.1.111" />

number may adjourn from day to day, and compel the attendance of their members in such manner as each house may prescribe</p><p> 13. Each house shall be judges of the elections, returns and qualifications of its own members, with powers to expel or punish by censuring, fining and imprisoning, or either, for disorderly behavior, and may expel any person convicted of any felonious or infamous offence; each house may punish by imprisonment, during session, any person, not a member, who shall be guilty of disrespect by any disorderly or contemptuous behavior in its presence, or who, during session, shall threaten harm to the body or estate of any member, for any thing said or done in either house, or who shall assault any of them therefor; or who shall assault or arrest any witness, in going to or returning therefrom, or who shall rescue any person arrested by order of either house.</p><p> 14. No Senator or Representative shall be liable to be arrested during his attendance on the General Assembly, or for ten days previous to its sitting, or for ten days after the rising thereof, except for treason, felony, or breach of the peace; nor shall any member be liable to answer for any thing spoken in debate in either house, in any court or place elsewhere; but shall nevertheless be bound to answer for perjury, bribery or corruption.</p><p> 15. Each house shall keep a Journal of its proceedings, and publish them immediately after their adjournment; and the yeas and nays of the members on any question, shall, at the desire of any two members, be entered on the Journals.</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P113" no="GA1813.1.112" />

<p> 16. All bills for raising revenue or appropriating monies shall originate in the House of Representatives; but the Senate shall propose or concur with amendments as in other bills.</p><p> 17. Every bill shall be read three times and on three separate days, in each branch of the General Assembly, before it shall pass, unless in cases of actual invasion or insurrection; nor shall any law or ordinance pass, containing any matter different from what is expressed in the title thereof; and all acts shall be signed by the President in the Senate,  Speaker in the House of Representatives: No bill or ordinance which shall have been rejected by either house, shall be brought in again during the session, under the same or any other title, without the consent of two thirds of each branch.</p><p> 18. Each Senator and Representative, before he be permitted to take his seat, shall take an oath or make affirmation, that he hath not practised any unlawful means, either directly or indirectly, to procure his election, and every person shall be disqualified from serving as a Senator or Representative, for the term for which he shall have been elected, who shall be convicted of having given or offered any bribe or treat, or canvassed for such election; and every candidate employing like means and not elected, shall, on conviction, be ineligible to hold a seat in either house, or to hold any office of honor or profit for the term of one year, and to such other disabilities or penalties as may be prescribed by law.</p><p> 19. Every member of the Senate, or House of Representatives, shall before he takes his seat take the following oath or affirmation, to wit:

<page id="GA1813.1.P114" no="GA1813.1.113" />

I, <i>A. B.</i> do solemnly swear or affirm, (as the case may be) that I have not obtained my election by bribery, treats, canvassing, or other undue or unlawful means, used by myself, or others by my desire or approbation, for that purpose; that I consider myself constitutionally qualified as a Senator or Representative; and that on all questions and measures which may come before me, I will give my vote, and so conduct myself, as may, in my judgment, appear most conducive to the interest and prosperity of this state; and that I will bear true faith and allegiance to the same; and to the utmost of my power and ability observe, conform to, support and defend the Constitution thereof.</p><p> 20. No person who hath been, or may be convicted of felony, before any court of this state, or any of the United States, shall be eligible to any office or appointment of honor, profit or trust, within this state.</p><p> 21. Neither House, during the session of the General Assembly, shall, without the consent of the other, adjourn for more than three days, nor to any other place, than that at which the two branches shall be sitting; and in case of disagreement between the Senate and House of Representatives, with respect to their adjournment, the Governor may adjourn them.</p><p> 22. The General Assembly shall have power to make all laws and ordinances, which they shall deem necessary and proper for the good of the state, which shall not be repugnant to this Constitution.</p><p> 23. They shall have power to alter the

<page id="GA1813.1.P115" no="GA1813.1.114" />

boundaries of the present counties, and to lay off new ones, as well out of the counties already laid off, as out of the other territory belonging to the state; but the property of the soil, in a free government, being one of the essential rights of a free people, it is necessary, in order to avoid disputes, that the limits of this state should be ascertained with precision and exactness; and this Convention, composed of the immediate representatives of the people, chosen by them to assert their rights, and to revise the powers given by them to the government, and from whose will, all ruling authority of right flows, DOTH assert and declare the boundaries of this state to be as follows: That is to sayThe limits, boundaries, jurisdictions and authority, of the State of Georgia, do, and did, and of right ought to extend from the sea or the mouth of the river Savannah, along the northern branch or stream thereof to the fork or confluence of the rivers now called Tugalo and Keowee, and from thence along the most northern branch or stream of the said river Tugalo, till it intersects the northern boundary line of South-Carolina; if the said branch or stream of Tugalo, extends so far north, reserving all the islands in the said rivers Savannah and Tugalo to Georgia; but if the head spring or source of any branch or stream of the said river Tugalo, does not extend to the north boundary line of South Carolina, then a west line to the Mississippi, to be drawn from the head spring or source of the said branch or stream of Tugalo river, which extends to the highest northern latitude; thence down the middle of the said river Mississippi, until it

<page id="GA1813.1.P116" no="GA1813.1.115" />

shall intersect the northernmost part of the thirty-first degree of north latitude; south by a line drawn due east, from the termination of the line last mentioned, in the latitude of thirty-one degrees north of the equator, to the middle of the river Apalachicola or Chatahoochee; thence along the middle thereof to its junction with Flint river; thence straight to the head of St. Mary's river; and thence along the middle of St. Mary's river to the Atlantic ocean; and from thence to the mouth or inlet of Savannah river, the place of beginning. Including and comprehending all the lands and waters within the said limits, boundaries and jurisdictional rights; and also, all the islands within twenty leagues of the sea coast. And this Convention doth further declare and assert, that all the territory without the present temporary line and within the limits aforesaid, is now, of right the property of the free citizens of this state, and held by them in [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] but by their consent<i>provided nevertheless,</i> That nothing herein contained shall be [Illegible Text] so as to prevent a sale to, or contract with the United States, by the Legislature of this state, of and for all or any part of the western territory of this state, laying westward of the river Chatahoochee, on such terms as may be beneficial to both parties; and may procure an extension of settlement, and an extinguishment of Indian claims, in and to the vacant territory of this state, to the east and north of the said river Chatahoochie, to which territory, such power or contract or sale, by the Legislature, shall not extend<i>And provided also,</i> The Legislature may give its consent to the establishment

<page id="GA1813.1.P117" no="GA1813.1.116" />

of one or more governments west-ward thereof; but monopolies of land by individuals, being contrary to the spirit of our free government, no sale of territory of this state, or any part thereof, shall take place to individuals or private companies, unless a county or counties shall have been first laid off, including such territory, and the Indian rights shall have been extinguished thereto.</p><p> 24. The foregoing section of this article having declared the common rights of the free citizens of this state, in and to all the territory without the present temporary boundary line, and within the limits of this state, thereby defined, by which the contemplated purchases of certain companies of a considerable portion thereof, are become constitutionally void; and justice and good faith require, that the state should not detain a consideration for a contract, which has failed, the Legislature, at their next session, shall make provision by law, for returning to any person or persons, who has or have bona fide deposited monies for such purchases in the Treasury of this state<i>provided,</i> that the same shall not have heen drawn therefrom in terms of the act passed the thirteenth of February, one thousand seven hundred and ninety-six, commonly called the rescinding act, or the appropriation laws of the years one thousand seven hundred and ninety-six, and one thousand seven hundred and ninety-sevenNor shall the monies paid for such purchases, ever be deemed a part of the funds of this state, or be liable to appropriation as such; but until such monies be drawn from the treasury, they shall be considered

<page id="GA1813.1.P118" no="GA1813.1.117" />

altogether at the risque of the persons who have deposited the same. No money shall be drawn out of the treasury, or from the public funds of this state, except by appropriation made by law; and a regular statement and account of the receipts and expenditures of all public monies, shall be published from time to time. No vote, resolution, law, or order shall pass the General Assembly, granting a donation or gratuity in favor of any person whatever, but by the concurrence of two-thirds of the General Assembly.</p><p> 25. It shall be the duty of the Justices of the Inferior court or any three of them, in each county respectively, within sixty days after the adjournment of this Convention, to appoint one or more fit persons in each county, not exceeding one for each battalion district, whose duty it shall be to take a full  accurate [Illegible Text] or enumeration of all free white persons and people of color, residing therein, distinguishing in separate columns, the free white persons, from persons of color, and return the same to the Clerks of the Superior courts of the several counties, certified under their hands, on or before the first day of December nextthe persons so appointed, being first severally sworn before the said Justices or either of them, duly and faithfully to perform the trust reposed in them; and it shall be the duty of the said Clerks, to transmit all such returns, under seal, directed to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, at the first session of the Legislature thereafter: And it shall be the duty of the General Assembly, at their said first session, to apportion the members of the House of Representatives among the several counties,

<page id="GA1813.1.P119" no="GA1813.1.118" />

agreeably to the plan prescribed by this Constitution, and to provide an adequate compensation for the taking of the said census. Every person whose usual place of abode shall be in any family on the first Monday in July next, shall be returned as of such family, and every person, occasionally absent at the time of taking the enumeration, as belonging to that place in which he usually resides. The General Assembly shall, by law direct the manner of taking such census or enumeration, within every subsequent term of seven years, in conformity to this Constitution. And it is declared to be the duty of all officers, civil and [Illegible Text] throughout this state, to be aiding and assisting in the true and faithful execution thereof In case the Justices of the Inferior courts should fail to make such appointments, or if there should not be a sufficient number of such Justices in any county, then the Justices of the Peace, or any three of them, shall have and exercise like powers and authority respecting the said census; and if the census or enumeration of any county shall not be so taken and returned, [Illegible Text] and in that case, the General Assembly shall apportion the representation of such county, according to the best evidence in their power, relative to its population.</p></div><div><title>ARTICLE II.<br set="CENTER" /></title><p> 1. The Executive power shall be vested in a Governor, who shall hold his office during the term of two years, and until such time as a successor shall be chosen  qualified; he shall have a competent salary established by law, which shall not be increased or diminished [Illegible Text] the period for which he shall have been elected; neither

<page id="GA1813.1.P120" no="GA1813.1.119" />

shall he receive, within that period, any other emolument from the United States, or either of them, or from any foreign power</p><p> 2 The Governor shall be elected by the General Assembly, at their second annual session after the rising of this Convention, and at every second annual session thereafter, on the second day after the two houses shall be organized and competent to proceed to business.</p><p> 3. No person shall be eligible to the office of Governor, who shall not have been a citizen of the United States twelve years, and an inhabitant of this state six years, and who hath not attained to the age of thirty years, and who does not possess five hundred acres of land, in his own right, within this state, and other property to the amount of four thousand dollars, and whose estate shall not, on a reasonable estimation, be competent to the discharge of his debts, over and above that sum.</p><p> 4. In case of the death or resignation, or disability of the Governor, the President of the Senate shall exercise the Executive powers of government, until such disability be removed, or until the next meeting of the General Assembly.</p><p> 5 The Governor shall, before he enters on the duties of his office, take the following oath or affirmation: I do solemnly swear or affirm (as the case may be) that I will faithfully execute the office of Governor of the State of Georgia; and will, to the best of my abilities, preserve, protect, and defend the said state, and cause justice to be executed in mercy therein, according to the Constitution and laws thereof</p><p> 6. He shall be Commander in Chief of the

<page id="GA1813.1.P121" no="GA1813.1.120" />

army and navy of this state, and of the militia thereof.</p><p> 7. He shall have power to grant reprieves for offences against the state, except in cases of impeachment, and to grant pardons, or to remit any part of a sentence, in all cases after conviction, except for treason or murder, in which cases he may respite the execution, and make report thoreof to the next General Assembly, by whom a pardon may be granted.</p><p> 8. He shall issue writs of election to fill up all vacancies that happen in the Senate or House of Representatives; and shall have power to convene the General Assembly on extraordinary occasions; and shall give them, from time to time, information of the state of the republic, and recommend to their consideration such measures as he may deem necessary and expedient.</p><p> 9. When any office shall become vacant by death, resignation or otherwise, the Governor shall have the power to fill such vacancy; and persons so appointed, shall continue in office until a successor is appointed, agreeably to the mode pointed out by this Constitution, or by the Legislature.</p><p> 10 He shall have the revision of all bills passed in both Houses, before the same shall become laws, but two-thirds of both houses may pass a law notwithstanding his dissent; and if any bill should not be returned by the Governor within five days after it hath been presented to him, the same shall be a law, unless the General Assembly, by their adjournment, shall prevent its return.</p><p> 11. Every vote, resolution or order, to which

<page id="GA1813.1.P122" no="GA1813.1.121" />

[Illegible Text] concurrence of both Houses may be necessary, except on a question of adjournment, shall be presented to the Governor; and before it shall take effect, be approved by him, or being disapproved, may be repassed by two-thirds of both Houses, according to the rules and limitations prescribed in case of a bill.</p><p> 12 There shall be a Secretary of the State, a Treasurer, and a Surveyor General, appointed in the same manner, and at the same session of the Legislature, and they shall hold their offices for the like period as the Governor, and shall have a competent salary, including such emoluments as may be established by law, which shall not be increased or diminished during the period for which they shall have been elected.</p><p> 13. The Great Seal of the State shall be deposited in the office of Secretary of State, and shall not be affixed to any instrument of writing, but by order of the Governor or General Assembly; and the General Assembly shall, at their first session after the rising of this Convention, cause the Great Seal to be altered by law.</p><p> 14. The Governor shall have power to appoint his own Secretaries.</p></div><div><title>ARTICLE III.<br set="CENTER" /></title><p><footnoteref pointer="GA1813.1.F1">*</footnoteref><footnote target="GA1813.1.F1"><p>* This section alteredsee 2d amendment at the end of the Constitution.</p></footnote> 1. The Judicial powers of this state shall be vested in a Superior court, and in such inferior jurisdictions as the Legislature shall, from time to time, ordain and establish. The Judges of the Superior courts shall be elected for the term of three years, removable by the Governor

<page id="GA1813.1.P123" no="GA1813.1.122" />

on the address of two thirds of both Houses for that purpose, or by impeachment and conviction thereon. The Superior court shall have exclusive and final jurisdiction in all criminal cases, which shall be tried in the county where-in the crime was committed, and in all cases respecting titles to land, which shall be tried in the county where the land lies; and shall have power to correct errors in inferior judicatories by writs of <i>Certiorari,</i> as well as errors in the Superior courts, and to order new trials on proper and legal grounds<i>provided,</i> That such new trials shall be determined, and such errors corrected, in the Superior court of the county in which such action originated. And the said court shall also have appellate jurisdiction in such other cases, as the Legislature may by law direct, which shall in no case tend to remove the cause from the county in which the action originated; and the Judges thereof, in all cases of application for new trials, or correction of errors, shall enter their opinions on the minutes of the court. The Inferior courts shall have cognizance of all other civil cases, which shall be tried in the county wherein the defendant resides, except in cases of joint obligors, residing in different counties, which may be commenced in either county; and a copy of the petition and process, served on the party or parties residing out of the county in which the suit may be commenced, shall be deemed sufficient service, under such rules and regulations as the Legislature may direct: But the Legislature may, by law, to which two-thirds of each branch may concur, give concurrent jurisdiction to the Superior courts. The Superior

<page id="GA1813.1.P124" no="GA1813.1.123" />

and Inferior courts shall sit in each county twice in every year, at such stated times as the Legislature shall appoint</p><p> 2. The Judges shall have salaries, adequate to their services, established by law, which shall not be increased or diminished during their continuance in office; but shall not receive any other perquisites or emoluments whatever, from parties or others, on account of any duty required of them.</p><p> 3 There shall be a state's attorney and solicitors appointed by the Legislature, and commissioned by the Governor, who shall hold their offices for the term of three years, unless removed by sentence on impeachment, or by the Governor, on the address of two thirds of each branch of the General Assembly. They shall have salaries adequate to their services, established by law, which shall not be increased or diminished during their continuance in office.</p><p><footnoteref pointer="GA1813.1.F2">*</footnoteref><footnote target="GA1813.1.F2"><p>* These sections alteredsee 3d amendment.</p></footnote> 4. Justices of the Inferior courts shall be appointed by the General Assembly, and be commissioned by the Governor, and shall hold their commissions during good behavior, or as long as they respectively reside in the county for which they shall be appointed, unless removed by sentence on impeachment, or by the Governor, on the address of two-thirds of each branch of the General Assembly. They may be compensated for their services, in such manner as the Legislature may by law direct.</p><p><footnoteref pointer="GA1813.1.F2">*</footnoteref>  5. The Justices of the Peace shall be nominated by the Inferior courts of the several

<page id="GA1813.1.P125" no="GA1813.1.124" />

counties, and commissioned by the Governor, and there shall be two Justices of the Peace in each Captain's district, either or both of whom, shall have power to try all cases of a civil nature, within their district, where the debt or liquidated demand does not exceed thirty dollars, in such manner as the Legislature may by law direct. They shall hold their appointments during good behavior, or until they shall be removed by conviction on indictment in the Superior court, for mal-practice in office, or for any felonious or infamous crime, or by the Governor, on the address of two-thirds of each branch of the Legislature.</p><p> 6. The powers of a Court of Ordinary or register of probates, shall be vested in the Inferior courts of each county, from whose decision there may be an appeal to the Superior court, under such restrictions and regulations as the General Assembly may by law direct; but the Inferior court shall have power to vest the care of the records and other proceedings therein, in the Clerk or such other person as they may appoint, and any one or more Justices of the said court, with such Clerk or other person, may issue citations, and grant temporary letters, in time of vacation, to hold until the next meeting of the said court; and such Clerk or other person may grant marriage licenses.</p><p> 7. The Judges of the Superior courts, or any one of them, shall have power to issue writs of <i>mandamus,</i> prohibition, <i>scire facias,</i> and all other writs which may be necessary for carrying their powers fully into effect.</p><p>Sec. 8. Within five years after the adoption of

<page id="GA1813.1.P126" no="GA1813.1.125" />

this Constitution, the body of our laws, civil and criminal, shall be revised, digested and arranged, under proper heads, and promulgated in such manner as the Legislature may direct; and no person shall be debarred from advocating or defending his cause, before any court or tribunal, either by himself or counsel, or both.</p><p>Sec. 9. Divorces shall not be granted by the Legislature, until the parties shall have had a fair trial before the Superior court, and a verdict shall have been obtained, authorizing a divorce upon legal principles. And in such cases, two-thirds of each branch of the Legislature may pass acts of divorce accordingly.</p><p><footnoteref pointer="GA1813.1.F3">*</footnoteref><footnote target="GA1813.1.F3"><p>* These sections [Illegible Text]see 1st amendment.</p></footnote> 10. The Clerks of the Superior and Inferior courts shall be appointed in such manner as the Legislature may by law direct, shall be commissioned by the Governor, and shall continue in office during good behavior.</p><p><footnoteref pointer="GA1813.1.F3">*</footnoteref>  11. Sheriffs shall be appointed in such manner as the General Assembly may by law direct, and shall hold their appointments for the term of two years, unless sooner removed by sentence on impeachment, or by the Governor, on the address of two thirds of the Justices of the Inferior court, and of the Peace in the county; but no person shall be twice elected Sheriff within any term of four years; and no county officer after the next election shall be chosen at the time of electing a Senator or Representative.</p></div><div><title>ARTICLE IV.<br set="CENTER" /></title><p>Sec. 1. The electors of members of the General Assembly, shall be citizens and inhabitants

<page id="GA1813.1.P127" no="GA1813.1.126" />

of this state, and shall have attained the age of twenty-one years, and have paid all taxes which may have been required of them, and which they have had an opportunity of paying, agreeably to law, for the year preceding the election, and shall have resided six months within the county; <i>provided,</i> That in case of invasion, and the inhabitants shall be driven from any county, so as to prevent an election therein, such refugee inhabitants, being a majority of the voters of such county, may meet under the direction of any three Justices of the Peace thereof in the nearest county, not in a state of alarm, and proceed to an election, without having paid such tax so required of electors and the persons elected thereat, shall be entitled to their seats.</p><p>Sec. 2. All elections, by the General Assembly, shall be by joint ballot of both branches of the Legislature; and when the Senate  House of Representatives unite for the purpose of electing, they shall meet in the Representative Chamber, and the President of the Senate shall in such cases preside, receive the ballots, and declare the person or pereons elected. In all elections by the people, the electors shall vote <i>viva voce,</i> until the Legislature shall otherwise direct.</p><p>Sec. 3. The general officers of the militia, shall be elected by the General Assembly, and shall be commissioned by the Governor. All other officers of the militia shall be elected in such manner as the Legislature may direct, and shall be commissioned by the Governor; and all militia officers now in commission, and those which may be hereafter commissioned, shall hold their commissions during their usual residence within

<page id="GA1813.1.P128" no="GA1813.1.127" />

the division, brigade, regiment, battalion, or company, to which they beiong, unles removed by sentence of a court martial, or by the Governor, on the address of two thirds of each branch of the General Assembly.</p><p> 4 All persons appointed by the Legislature, to fill vacancies, shall continue in office, only so long as to complete the time for which their predecessors were appointed.</p><p> 5. Freedom of the press, and trial by jury, as heretofore used in this state, shall remain inviolate; and no <i>ex post facto</i> law shall be passed.</p><p> 6. No person, who heretofore hath been, or hereafter may be, a collector, or holder of public monies, shall be eligible to any office in this state, until such person shall have accounted for, and paid into the Treasury, all sums for which he may be accountable or liable.</p><p> 7. The person of a debtor, where there is not a strong presumption of fraud, shall not be detained in prison, after delivering, bona fide, all his estate real and personal, for the use of his creditors, in such manner as shall be hereafter regulated by law.</p><p> 8. Convictions on impeachments, which have heretofore taken place, are hereby released, and, persons lying under such convictions, restored to citizenship.</p><p> 9. The writ of <i>habeas corpus</i> shall not be suspended, unless when in case of rebellion, or invasion, the public safety may require it.</p><p> 10. No person within this state, shall, upon any pretence, be deprived of the inestimable privilege of worshipping God, in a manner agreeable

<page id="GA1813.1.P129" no="GA1813.1.128" />

to his own conscience, nor be compelled to attend any place of worship, contrary to his own faith and judgment; nor shall he ever be obliged to pay tithes, taxes, or any other rate, for the building or repairing any place of worship, or for the maintenance of any minister or ministry, contrary to what he believes to be right, or hath voluntarily engaged to do. No one religious society shall ever be established in this state, in preference to another; nor shall any person be denied the enjoyment of any civil right, merely on account of his religious principles.</p><p> 11. There shall be no future importation of slaves into this state, from Africa, or any foreign place, after the first day of October next. The Legislature shall have no power to pass laws for the emancipation of slaves, without the consent of each of their respective owners, previous to such emancipation They shall have no power to prevent emigrants, from either of the United States to this state, from bringing with them such persons, as may be deemed slaves, by the laws of any one of the United States</p><p> 12. Any person, who shall maliciously dismember, or deprive a slave of life, shall suffer such punishment as would be inflicted, in case the like offence had been committed on a free white person, and on the like proof, except in case of insurrection by such slave, and unless such death should happen by accident, in giving such slave moderate correction.</p><p> 13 The arts and sciences shall be promoted, in one or more seminaries of learning, and the Legislature shall, as soon as conveniently may be, give such further donations and privileges,

<page id="GA1813.1.P130" no="GA1813.1.129" />

to those already established, as may be necessary to secure the objects of their institution; and it shall be the duty of the General Assembly, at their next session, to provide effectual measures for the improvement and permanent security of the funds and endowments of such institutions.</p><p> 14 All civil officers shall continue in the exercise of the duties of their several offices, during the periods for which they were appointed, or until they shall be superceded, by appointments made in conformity to this Constitution; And all laws, now in force, shall continue to operate, so far as they are compatible with this Constitution, until repealed; and it shall be the duty of the General Assembly to pass all necessary laws and regulations, for carrying this Constitution into full effect.</p><p> 15. No part of this Constitution shall be altered, unless a bill for that purpose, specifying the alterations intended to be made, shall have been read three times in the House of Representatives, and three times in the Senate, on three several days in each house, and agreed to by two thirds of each house respectively; and when any such bill shall be passed in manner aforesaid, the same shall be published at least six months previous to the next ensuing annual election for members of the General Assembly; and if such alterations, or any of them so proposed, shall be agreed to in their first session thereafter, by two thirds of each branch of the General Assembly, after the same shall have been read three times, on three separate days, in each respective [Illegible Text], then and not otherwise, the same shall become a part of this Constitution.</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P131" no="GA1813.1.130" />

<p>WE, the underwritten Delegates of the People of the State of Georgia, chosen and authorized by them to revise, alter and amend, the powers and principles of their government, DO declare, ordain and ratify, the several Articles and Sections contained in the six pages hereunto prefixed, as the Constitution of this State; and the same shall be in operation from the date hereof.</p><p><i>IN TESTIMONY WHEREOF,</i> We, and each of us respectively, have hereunto set our hands, at LOUISVILLE, the seat of government, this thirtieth day of May, in the year of our LORD one thousand seven hundred and ninety eight, and in the twenty-second year of the Independence of the United States of America; and have caused the Great Seal of the state to be affixed thereto.</p><p>Article 4th, section 11th, and first line, the following words being interlined, to witAfter the first day of October next.</p></div><p>JARED IRWIN, <i>President,</i></p><p><i>and Delegate from Washington.</i></p><p>[Signed by the Delegates from the several counties.]</p><approvaldate /></law></part>

<page id="GA1813.1.P132" no="GA1813.1.131" type="INFERRED" />

<part><title>AMENDMENTS<br set="CENTER">TO THE<br set="CENTER"><b>CONSTITUTION.</b><br set="CENTER" /></br></br></title><law id="R1813V1N110" initial.page="131" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle>FIRST AMENDMENT.</shorttitle><fulltitle><i>An act to alter and amend the tenth section of the third article of the Constitution.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the said tenth section is in the words following: The Clerks of the Superior and Inferior courts, shall be appointed in such manner as the Legislature may by law direct; shall be commissioned by the Governor, and shall continue in office during good behaviorfor remedy whereof;</p><p> 1. <i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the Clerks of the Superior and Inferior Courts shall be elected on the same day as pointed out by law for the election of county officers.</p><p>Finally passed and became a part of the Constitution, the 16th day of December, 1808.</p><approvaldate /></law><law id="R1813V1N111" initial.page="131" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle>SECOND AMENDMENT.</shorttitle><fulltitle><i>An act to alter the first section of the third article of the Constitution.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the first section of the third article of the Constitution is in the words following, to witThe Judicial powers of this state shall

<page id="GA1813.1.P133" no="GA1813.1.132" />

be vested in a Superior court, and such inferior jurisdictions as the Legislature shall from time to time ordain and establish. The Judges of the Superior courts shall be elected for the term of three years, removable by the Governor on the address of two thirds of both Houses for that purpose, or by impeachment and conviction thereon.</p><p>The Superior courts shall have exclusive and final jurisdiction in all criminal cases, which shall be tried in the county where the crime was committed, and in all cases respecting the titles to lands, which shall be tried in the county where the land lies, and shall have power to correct errors in [Illegible Text] judicatories by writs of certiorari, as well as errors in the Superior courts, and to order new trials on proper and legal grounds<i>provided,</i> that such new trials shall be determined, and such errors corrected in the Superior court of the county in which such action originated; and the said court shall also have appellate jurisdiction in such other cases as the Legislature may by law direct which shall in no case tend to remove the cause from the county in which the action originated, and the Judges thereof in all cases of application for new trials or correction of errors, shall enter their opinions on the minutes of the courtThe Inferior courts shall have cognizance of all other civil cases, which shall be tried in the counties where the defendant resides, except in cases of joint obligors residing in different counties, which may be commenced in either county, and a copy of the petition and process served on the party or parties residing out of the county in which the suit

<page id="GA1813.1.P134" no="GA1813.1.133" />

may be commenced, shall be deemed sufficient service, under such rules and regulations as the Legislature may direct: but the Legislature may by law, to which two-thirds of each branch may concur, give concurrent jurisdiction to the Superior courts. The Superior and Inferior courts shall sit in each county twice every year, at such stated times as the Legislature shall appoint.</p><p> 1. <i>Be it therefore enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the Judicial powers of this state shall be vested in a Superior, Inferior and Justices courts, and in such other courts as the Legislature shall from time to time ordain and establish.</p><p> 2. The Judges of the Superior courts shall be elected for the term of three years, removable by the Governor on the address of two-thirds of both branches of the General Assembly for that purpose, or by impeachment and conviction thereon.</p><p> 3. The Superior courts shall have exclusive  final jurisdiction in all criminal cases (except as relates to people of color, and fines for neglect of duty, and for contempt of court, for violations against road laws, and obstructing water courses, which shall be vested in such judicature or tribunal as shall be, or may have been pointed out by law, which shall be tried in the county where the crime was committed. And in all cases respecting titles to land, which shall be tried in the county where the land lies; and also concurrent jurisdiction in all other civil cases, and shall have

<page id="GA1813.1.P135" no="GA1813.1.134" />

power to correct errors in inferior judicatories by writ of certiorari, as well as errors in the Superior courts, and order new trials on proper and legal grounds<i>provided,</i> that such new trials shall be determined, and such errors corrected in the Superior court of the county in which such action originated; and the said court shall have appellate jurisdiction in all such other cases as are, or may be pointed outby law, which shall in no case tend to remove the cause from the county in which the action originated; and the Judges thereof in all cases of application for new trials or correction of errors, shall enter their opinion on the minutes of the court. The Inferior [Illegible Text] shall also have concurrent jurisdiction in all civil cases except in cases respecting the titles to lands, which shall be tried in the county where the defendant resides; and in cases of joint obligors or joint promisors, residing in different counties, the same may be brought in either county, and a copy of the petition and process served on the party residing out of the county in which the suit may be commenced, shall be deemed sufficient service, under such rules and regulations as the Legislature have, or may direct. The Superior and Inferior courts shall set in each county twice in every year, and at such stated times as have, or may be appointed by the Legislature</p><p>Finally passed and become a part of the Constitution the 18th day of November, 1811.</p><approvaldate /></law><law id="R1813V1N112" initial.page="134"><shorttitle>THIRD AMENDMENT</shorttitle><fulltitle><i>An act to alter the</i> 4<i>th and</i> 5<i>th sections of the</i> 3<i>d article of the Constitution of this state.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the fourth and fifth sections of

<page id="GA1813.1.P136" no="GA1813.1.135" />

the Constitution of this state are in the words following, viz<i>Fourth section</i>The Justices of the Inferior courts shall be appointed by the General Assembly, and shall be commissioned by the Governor, and shall hold their commissions during good behavior, or as long as they respectively reside in the county, for which they shall be appointed, unless removed by sentence on impeachment, or by the Governor on the address of two-thirds of each branch of the General Assembly; they may be compensated for their services in such manner as the Legislature may by law direct.</p><p><i>Fifth section</i>The Justices of the Peace shall be nominated by the Inferior courts of the several counties, and commissioned by the Governor, and there shall be two Justices of the Peace in each captain's district, either or both of whom shall have power to try all cases of a civil nature within their district where the debt or liquidated demand does not exceed thirty dollars, in such manner as the Legislature may by law direct; they shall hold their appointments during good behavior, or until they shall be removed by conviction on indictment in the Superior court for mal-practice in office, or for any felonious or infamous crime, or by the Governor on the address of two-thirds of each branch of the Legislature.</p><p>And whereas the term of good behaviour has a tendency to destroy that responsibility which should ever be kept alive in a free country, and felt by every individual in whose [Illegible Text] the duties of office are reposed;</p><p> 1 <i>Be it therefore enacted by the Senate  House</i>

<page id="GA1813.1.P137" no="GA1813.1.136" />

<i>of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same it is hereby enacted,</i> That as soon as this act shall have passed agreeably to the requisitions of the Constitution, that then the sections above recited shall be repealed, and the following adopted in lieu thereof.</p><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,  it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior courts shall be elected on the third Tuesday in October, 1813, and on the third Tuesday in October in every fourth year thereafter, by the electors entitled to vote for members of the General Assembly, which election shall be held and conducted in the same manner as pointed out by law for the elections of Clerks and Sheriffs, and the persons so elected shall be commissioned by the Governor, and continue in office for the term of four years, unless removed by impeachment for mal-practice in office, or by the Governor on the address of two thirds of both branches of the General Assembly; they may be compensated for their services in such manner as the Legislature may by law direct: and there shall be five Justices for each county, who shall hold their offices until their successors are elected and qualified; and when any vacancy shall happen by death, resignation or otherwise, of any Justice of the Inferior court, it shall be the duty of two or more of the Justices of the Inferior court or Justices of the peace, to give at least twenty days notice by advertisement at three of the most public places in the county, previous to the election to fill such vacancy,

<page id="GA1813.1.P138" no="GA1813.1.137" />

which election shall be held in the same manner as is by this section before expressed.</p><p> 3 <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That there shall be two Justices of the peace in each Captain's district in the several counties of this state, either or both of whom shall have power to try all cases of a civil nature within their district, where the debt or liquidated demand does not exceed thirty dollars, in such manner as the Legislature may by law direct; they shall be elected on the first Saturday in January eighteen hundred and thirteen, and on the first Saturday in January in every fourth year thereafter, by the citizens of the district to which they respectively belong, entitled to vote for members of the General Assembly, which election shall be superintended by three freeholders of the district, whose duty it shall be to take the following oath, to be administered by the Captain or Commanding officer of the said district, to witI A. B. do solemnly swear that I will to the best of my abilities superintend the election of Justices of the peace for this district, so help me Godand they shall transmit a return of said election within twenty days to His Excellency the Governor, who is hereby authorised to commission the persons so elected accordingly; and they shall hold their appointments during the term of four years, and until their successors are elected and qualified, unless they shall be removed by conviction on indictment in the Superior Court for mal practice in office or any felonious or infamous crime, or by the Governor on the address of two thirds of each brach of the Legislature.</p>

<page id="GA1813.1.P139" no="GA1813.1.138" />

<p>And when any vacancy shall happen by death, resignation or otherwise, of any justice of the peace between the time of such election and the expiration of the time for which such justice or justices were elected, it shall be the duty of two of the Justices of the peace in any of the adjoining districts where such vacancy or vacancies may happen, to advertise in three of the most public places in the district where such vacancy or vacancies may happen, the time of holding an election for the purpose of filling such vacancy or vacancies, and give at least fifteen days notice of the time and place where such election shall be held, which shall be in the district where such vacancy or vacancies shall have happened, and it shall be the duty of the said justices to superintend such election, and certify the same under their hands to His Excellency the Governor, who shall within ten days after receiving the same, commission the persons having the highest number of votes, provided the same is not contested.</p><p>(Finally passed and became a part of the Constitution the 17th day of November, 1812)</p><approvaldate /></law></part></body>

<page id="GA1813.1.P140" no="GA1813.1.i" type="INFERRED" />

<backmatter><index><title>INDEX.<footnoteref pointer="GA1813.1.F4">*</footnoteref><footnote target="GA1813.1.F4"><p>* <i>Pages</i> 87  88, <i>by [Illegible Text], are twice [Illegible Text]</i></p></footnote><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title><b>A.</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Actions<br /></title><indexentry>see limitations.</indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Appropriation<br /></title><indexentry>act <pagenbr>Page 22</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Academies,<br /></title><indexentry>a commissioner of Meson Academy appointed <pagenbr>84</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One for Effingham and one for Wayne county do <pagenbr>85</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two for Telfair county do <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two for Wilkes, one for Chatham  two for Franklin <pagenbr>87</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of Jackson county academy authorised to sue any person holding money belonging to <pagenbr>88</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>A comm'r of the Lincoln county academy appointed <pagenbr>101</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Five for Madison county do <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two for Wilkinson, two for Columbia  one for Pulaski <pagenbr>106</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Adams  [Illegible Text],<br /></title><indexentry>proceedings had on their [Illegible Text] reported to the Legislature <pagenbr>86</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To deliver 2000 copies of the laws  resolutions by 1st Oct'r next,  their contract to be considered as complied with <pagenbr>103</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Attorney and Solicitors Gen'l required to report to the Gov'r<br /></title><indexentry>the situation of suits on bonds for confiscated property <pagenbr>89</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Arms,<br /></title><indexentry>a distribution of in Gen Floyd's brigade ordered, <pagenbr>91</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>40 stand directed to be sent to Tatnall county <pagenbr>102</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>The major com. authorised to have them repaired <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>The Gov. requested to have those in the arsenal repaired <pagenbr>104</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Ammunition<br /></title><indexentry>to be sent to Camden and Chatham counties <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Adjutant Gen'l,<br /></title><indexentry>his presence with gen. Floyd's army required <pagenbr>96</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>May appoint an assistant <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>B.</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Boog John,<br /></title><indexentry>an act for the relief of <pagenbr>37</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Brunswick,<br /></title><indexentry>comm'rs of the town of, declared to be comm'rs of the academy of Glynn county <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Comm'rs of appointed,  not more than 1-4th of the future rent of said common to be applied to courthouse  jail <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Bounty Warrants,<br /></title><indexentry>one issued to Jer. Russell and John Ragan's bond to be filed in the treasury office <pagenbr>89</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>C.<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Clerks,<br /></title><indexentry>cert ain acts  procedings of, legalized  made valid <pagenbr>18</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Certain acts of Angus M[dot]Donald, as deputy clerk of the Superior court of Wayne county made valid <pagenbr>29</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Of the superior and inferior courts  courts of ordinary not bound to make a schedule of the papers belonging to their respective offices and exhibit to the inferior courts 30 days previous to the elections for clerks <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall deliver to their successors in office all books and papers belonging to their offices within 5 days after they are qualified <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>And Sheriffs c. tho' out of office, may be ruled by court <pagenbr>57</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1813.1.P141" no="GA1813.1.ii" />

<indexdiv><title>Clarke county,<br /></title><indexentry>part of added to Oglethorpe <pagenbr>20</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Part of added to Madison county <pagenbr>59</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Constables,<br /></title><indexentry>lawful for them to attend elections in certain cases <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Courts<br /></title><indexentry>Battalion courts of Inquiry allowed in certain cases <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall have a clerk who shall record all proceedings <pagenbr>50</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall hear and determine appeals from comp, courts <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>An extra session of the Superior court in Washington county authorized <pagenbr>72</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>An extra session of the Sup. court in Baldwin authorised <pagenbr>74</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Time of holding the Superior court in Wilkes co. altered <pagenbr>75</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Cade Wm.<br /></title><indexentry>name altered to that of Hopkins <pagenbr>58</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Clement,<br /></title><indexentry>Jas. Wm. Jona. and Chs. altered to that of Platt <pagenbr>59</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Columbia County,<br /></title><indexentry>line dividing it from Warren co. defined <pagenbr>65</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>D.</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Debtors,<br /></title><indexentry>an act to alleviate the condition of, <pagenbr>3</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Bank transactions not affected by the provisions of <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Actions upon the case for words not suspended by <pagenbr>3</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>4</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Plaintiffs in judgment or execution upon making affidavit that the deft, is about to remove his property out of the state or any county thereof, may compel him to give freehold security, or cause executions to be levied <pagenbr>4</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Security may be taken by the officer holding the writ, on which further proceedings shall be stopped <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Not extended to Ex'ors, Adm'rs or guardians who have in their hands money belonging to orphans <pagenbr>5</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>In what cases clerks may issue writs <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Suits for titles to land not suspended by <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Foreclosure of mortgages on personal property, provided the mortgage make oath that the property is about to be removed out of the state, or any county thereof, may be had and taken <pagenbr>5</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>6</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Creditors shall, before they call on their debtors for a liquidation of their accounts, prove the same <pagenbr>6</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Such parts of the act to which this is amendatory, as militate against this act, repealed <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To continue in force till the 25th of Dec'r 1814 <pagenbr>6</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Dimond Richard M. vested with all the property of Augusta Fisher,<br /></title><indexentry>but subject to the payment of her just debts <pagenbr>21</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>22</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>D'Antignae John,<br /></title><indexentry>an act for his relief <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>E.</b><br /></title><indexdiv><title>Emanuel county,<br /></title><indexentry>Clerks of, not compelled to keep their offices within one mile of the courthouse of <pagenbr>33</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>The line dividing it from Bulloch county defined <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Comm'rs for fixing on site of public buildings appointed <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>May purchase not less than 50 nor more than 100 acres <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>In case of [Illegible Text] among the comm'rs, the Inf. court may appoint a person to ascertain the centre of <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Inferior court of, may levy an extra county tax <pagenbr>35</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Do. authorised to draw jurors for Spring term 1814 <pagenbr>48</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1813.1.P142" no="GA1813.1.iii" />

<indexdiv><title>Elections<br /></title><indexentry>[Illegible Text] of militia which may hereafter be called out, may elect their officers <pagenbr>63</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>A resolution fixing the day for election of state officers <pagenbr>86</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One fixing the day for the election of the Governor <pagenbr>95</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointing the day for the election of a Senator in Congress, four judges of the superior courts and an Attorney and three Solicitors General <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>F.</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Fisher Augusta,<br /></title><indexentry>all her property, both real and personal, vested in Richard M. Dimond <pagenbr>21</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Ferries,<br /></title><indexentry>John Jeter authorised to establish one across the Oconee river <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Ezekiel Dubose authorised to establish one across Savannah river <pagenbr>78</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Fees<br /></title><indexentry>our Representatives in Congress requested to use their exertions to have the law of Georgia regulating the fees of Heath-Officer and Harbor Master for the city of Savannah, sanctioned for two years <pagenbr>102</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>G.</b><br /></title><indexdiv><title>Grants,<br /></title><indexentry>a certain description of legalized <pagenbr>45</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall be as valid where the grantee was dead at the time of the issuing of, as if the grantee had been alive <pagenbr>45</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Where they shall have issued to females after their intermarriage, declared legal and valid <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Governor,<br /></title><indexentry>requested to lay before the Legislature the proceedings had on Adams  [Illegible Text] bond, for printing the laws and resolutions since 1800. <pagenbr>86</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to have the constitution with the amendments published with the laws of 1813 <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to put in suit the bonds of all Receivers in default <pagenbr>88</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to pay the different printers for publishing foreclosure of state mortgages <pagenbr>87</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to transmit to our Representatives in Congress Documents relative to a violation of the non-intercourse law <pagenbr>90</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to apply to the General Government for the support of the militia to be ordered out on the maritime frontier <pagenbr>93</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to have several laws published in the Newspapers <pagenbr>94</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to call on the Commissioners of the [Illegible Text] to report their proceedings relative to said building <pagenbr>94</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to have forts and block-houses built on the frontier <pagenbr>96</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall order militia to build and defend <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to apply to the Gen'l gov. to furnish them <pagenbr>97</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to loan not exceeding $ 20,000 for the use of the army commanded by Gen. Floyd <pagenbr>97</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1813.1.P143" no="GA1813.1.iv" />

<indexdiv><title>Governor<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexentry>authorised to borrow the same <pagenbr>98</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Conduct of, in repeling the attack by the Indians in Morgan county approbated <pagenbr>99</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Authorised to send an army against the warring towns <pagenbr>100</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>H.</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Hardee John,<br /></title><indexentry>time allowed him to pay into the Treasury Office certain money as the security of Joseph Crews, Collector for Camden county for 1805, 1806  1807, <pagenbr>62</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Hill Joseph,<br /></title><indexentry>vested with the exclusive right to erect bridges and a ferry across Savannah river, from the city of Savannah to Proctor's Point, South Carolina, <pagenbr>63</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>House-State,<br /></title><indexentry>the old state-house and public square in Louisville, how to he disposed of, <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>L.</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Limitation,<br /></title><indexentry>actions by grantees of land prior to the revolutionary war, who fied from this country and did not return in 21 years, barred against minor grantees and persons elaiming under them, <pagenbr>12</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Not to apply to confiscated lands, <pagenbr>13</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Lotteries,<br /></title><indexentry>fortunate drawers in the late land lotteries to take out their grants till the 10th November, 1815, <pagenbr>81</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>After that time any citizen may take them out in their own name, <pagenbr>82</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Laws  Journals,<br /></title><indexentry>the printing of given to Messrs Grantlands <pagenbr>101</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>M</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Militia,<br /></title><indexentry>a portion of, of Camden county required to muster in the town of St. Marys only, except as to their company musters, <pagenbr>6</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Bound nevertheless to muster there, as often as the Adjutant and Major General of that division may direct, and subject as other militia defaulters for neglect of duty <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Any drafted or volunteer militiaman, who may hire a substitute, shall return to the line and be liable in all cases of emergence to do the duty which such substitute would have been liable to perform, <pagenbr>51</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Colonels shall order one battalion muster in each battallion every year, <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Free negroes or [Illegible Text] not permitted to stand in the ranks or to be enroled, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Any officer permiting the same, shall be fined not exceeding $20 <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Fines how applied, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Staff officers must reside in the Regiment, Brigade or Division to which they are attached,  must attend all reviews, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Officers permitted to uniform in blue homespun, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Detachments of, which may hereafter he called into service may elect their own officers, after arriving at the place of rendezvous, <pagenbr>66</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1813.1.P144" no="GA1813.1.v" />

<indexdiv><title>Militia,<br /></title><indexentry>Adjutant General shall in case of a call from the General Government hereafter, apportion the number required from the several divisions, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>On the southern and western frontier not to be sent out of the state on service during the present alarms <pagenbr>88</pagenbr> <pagenbr>89</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two companies of, ordered out for the defence of the maritime frontier, <pagenbr>92</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>The term of service of a detachment of on an expedition under Col. Adams, extended to 60 days, <pagenbr>93</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To be ordered out to build Forts and Block-houses, and defend tham, <pagenbr>96</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>M'Donald Augus,<br /></title><indexentry>certain acts of, as deputy Clerk of the Superior court of Wayne county legalized and made valid, <pagenbr>29</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Monticello,<br /></title><indexentry>[Illegible Text] of the town of, to elect their town Comm'rs [Illegible Text] the last Saturday in Dec. in each year, <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Milledgeville,<br /></title><indexentry>powers of the Commissioners of the town of, extended, <pagenbr>39</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Montgomery county,<br /></title><indexentry>scite of the public buildings of, made permanent at Mount Vernon, and the Inferior court authorized to select and draw Grand and Petit Jurors for the spring term, <pagenbr>44</pagenbr> <pagenbr>45</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Madison county,<br /></title><indexentry>part of Clark added to, <pagenbr>59</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Powers of the Commissioners of the Court-house and Jail of, extended, <pagenbr>60</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of, appointed, <pagenbr>61</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Inferior court of, authorized to levy an extra county tax, <pagenbr>64</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>N</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Ne [Illegible Text]<br /></title><indexentry>writ of, the Judges of the Superior courts authorized to grant and issue, <pagenbr>40</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall be granted and allowed as well where the debt exists and is not due, as where it is due, <pagenbr>41</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Notaries Public,<br /></title><indexentry>one appointed for the City of Augusta, <pagenbr>84</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for the City of Savannah and county of Chatham, <pagenbr>84</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for Greensborough and county of Greene, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for Carnesville and county of Franklin, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for the county of Glynn, <pagenbr>87</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two appointed for the City of Savannah and county of Chatham, <pagenbr>94</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for Baldwin county, <pagenbr>101</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for the county of Chatham, <pagenbr>104</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for the City of Augusta, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for the county of Chatham, <pagenbr>105</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for the county of Madison, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two appointed for the county of Chatham, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for the county of [Illegible Text] <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Naval force,<br /></title><indexentry>our Representatives in Congress requested to use their exertion with the Secretary of the Navy to have that between Savannah and St. Mary's enlarged and increased, <pagenbr>104</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1813.1.P145" no="GA1813.1.vi" />

<indexdiv><title><b>O</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>[Illegible Text] county,<br /></title><indexentry>part of Clark added to, <pagenbr>29</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>P</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>[Illegible Text],<br /></title><indexentry>$ 6000 appropriated to carry on the building of, <pagenbr>25</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Puleski county, the seite of public buildings of, made [Illegible Text] at the town of Hartford in said county, <pagenbr>30</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Inferior court of, authorized to dispose of the county funds arising from the sale of town lots, after paying for the Court house and Jail, as they may deem most expedient, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Perry Captain,<br /></title><indexentry>thanks of the Legislature tendered to, <pagenbr>98</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Governor requested to transmit him a copy of the resolution, <pagenbr>99</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>R</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Roads,<br /></title><indexentry>Scott William authorized to open one from Bulltown Swamp to Fort Barrington, and may receive toll thereon, <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Inferior court of Glynn county authorized to appoint three Commissioners for each public road in said county, <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Made judges of the necessity of all public roads in said county, and to apportion the hands, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>May regulate and direct all things regarding said roads on the island St. Simons, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of said roads to lay all fines and hear excuses for neglect of duty, <pagenbr>38</pagenbr> <pagenbr>39</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Rents,<br /></title><indexentry>mode of recovery of, in the City of Savannah and its [Illegible Text] prescribed <pagenbr>53</pagenbr> <pagenbr>55</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>S</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Scott William,<br /></title><indexentry>authorised to open, and required to keep in repair a road from Bull-town Swamp to Samuel Jones's in M'Intosh county, from thence the nearest and best way to Fort Barrington, <pagenbr>14</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>To give bond and security in the sum of $ 5000 for the performance of a [Illegible Text] to open and keep in repair the said road, <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Toll to be allowed him on the same, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners appointed to say when the same is completed agreeably to contract, and when toll may be demanded, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Sheriffs,<br /></title><indexentry>acts and proceedings of, legalized and made valid in certain cases, <pagenbr>16</pagenbr> <pagenbr>17</pagenbr> <pagenbr>18</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Clerks and Coroners may be ruled by the court though they may be out of [Illegible Text], <pagenbr>57</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Sumpterville,<br /></title><indexentry>purchasers of lots in, relieved <pagenbr>71</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>T</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Tax,<br /></title><indexentry>Receivers of tax Returns to keep their books open and receive returns till the 1st day of August in each year, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall deposit their digests in the several offices required, by the first Monday in November in every year, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr> <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1813.1.P146" no="GA1813.1.vii" />

<indexdiv><title>Tax,<br /></title><indexentry>Collectors shall receive from defaulters for 1813 but one third of the amount assessed by the Receivers. <pagenbr>9</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Receivers to advertise at each Captain's muster ground, when the time will expire for receiving returns, and after the expiration of the time for receiving, shall publish at said muster ground a list of all persons in default, and not publish in the Gazettes <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall assess a double tax on each defaulter, <pagenbr>10</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Receivers and Collectors hereafter appointed, may receive returns and collect tax for any property in default in any year since 1800, <pagenbr>11</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>The Gov'r. authorized and directed to pay the amount of direct tax due by this state to the U. States, and receive a discount of 15 per cent. <pagenbr>18</pagenbr> <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Authorized to draw out of the Treasury of the United States all money due by them to Georgia, <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Fifty per [Illegible Text] laid on the amount of the tax for 1813, to reimburse the state in part for paying the direct tax, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>[Illegible Text] of 1813 authorized to collect the 50 pr. [Illegible Text] <pagenbr>19, 20</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall receive 2 1-2 pr. ct. commissions on the 50 pr. ct. <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Shall give additional bonds and security before they proceed to collect the same, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Should the Collectors for 1813 refuse to collect said tax, the Inferior courts of the respective counties in which such refusal shall be made, may appoint others, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>The Collectors for 1813 must signify their acceptance or refusal to the Inferior courts of their respective counties by the 1st day of March, 1814, <pagenbr>21</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Tatnall county,<br /></title><indexentry>Inferior court of, authorized to draw Grand and Petit Jurors to serve at the pring term, 1814, <pagenbr>48</pagenbr> <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Telfair county,<br /></title><indexentry>scite of the public buildings therein, made permanent, <pagenbr>76</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Justices of the Inferior court constituted Comm'rs, <pagenbr>77</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Twiggs county,<br /></title><indexentry>Commissioners of public buildines of, appointed, <pagenbr>85</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Treasurer,<br /></title><indexentry>requested to issue executions against all Tax Collectors in arrears <pagenbr>88</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>U</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>United States,<br /></title><indexentry>persons in the service of, from this state, may be elected to any county appointment and not compelled to qualify and give bond prior to the first day of April next <pagenbr>36</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>V</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Vendue Masters,<br /></title><indexentry>three appointed for the City of Augusta, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for Greensborough, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two appointed for Milledgeville, <pagenbr>83</pagenbr> <pagenbr>84</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for St. Mary's <pagenbr>94</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title><b>W</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Waynesborough,<br /></title><indexentry>lot holders in the town of, quieted in their claims to, <pagenbr>25</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Lot holders under grants from the state prior to the sale of lots by the Commissioners not affected by this act <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1813.1.P147" no="GA1813.1.viii" />

<indexdiv><title>Waynesboro',<br /></title><indexentry>Deeds from the town Commissioners and the Commissioners of the Academy to be admitted as the best evidence, without requiring the production of a grant, <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Washington,<br /></title><indexentry>town of, in the county of Wilkes, the powers of the Commissioners of, extended, and shall be governed in all cases by the best information they can obtain, <pagenbr>47</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Their authority extended to one [Illegible Text] round said town, <pagenbr>48</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two Commissioners appointed for, <pagenbr>87</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Willson John,<br /></title><indexentry>the property of John Willson, sen. vested in, <pagenbr>57</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Warren county,<br /></title><indexentry>line dividing it from the county of Columbia defined, <pagenbr>65</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Wayne county,<br /></title><indexentry>a Commissioner of the Court-house and Jail appointed for, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv></index></backmatter></document></galaw>
