<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<galaw><metadata><coretitle>Acts of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</coretitle><creator>Georgia</creator><subject>Law, Georgia</subject><description>Georgia. Acts and resolutions of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</description><publisher>S.  F. GRANTLAND.</publisher><contributors><contributor /></contributors><date>18141000</date><type /><format /><identifier /><source /><language>English</language><relation /><coverage /><rights /></metadata>
<document initial.page="1" type="INFERRED">
<page id="GA1814.1.P1" no="GA1814.1.1" type="INFERRED" />

<titlepage><title><b>ACTS</b><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER">GENERAL ASSEMBLY<br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><b>STATE OF GEORGIA,</b><br set="CENTER">PASSED AT MILLEDGEVILLE<br set="CENTER"><b>At an Annual Session,</b><br set="CENTER">IN OCTOBER AND NOVEMBER, <b>1814</b>.<br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></title><sessiondate>18141000</sessiondate><sessiondate>18141100</sessiondate><pubinfo><p><i>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY.</i></p><p>MILLEDGEVILLE:</p><p>PRINTED BY S.  F. GRANTLAND.</p><p>STATE PRINTERS.</p><p>1814.</p></pubinfo></titlepage>

<page id="GA1814.1.P2" no="GA1814.1.3" type="INFERRED" />

<body><part><title><b>ACTS</b><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><b>GENERAL ASSEMBLY</b><br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER"><b>STATE OF GEORGIA;</b><br set="CENTER"><b>PASSED IN OCTOBER AND NOVEMBER, 1814.</b><br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></br></br></title><law id="L1814V1N001" initial.page="3" type="INFERRED"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To authorize the several Courts of Equity in this State to grant remedies in certain cases and to regulate the Courts of Law and Equity in this state, and for affording temporary relief to the Soldiers whilst in the service of this state or of the United States, and for other purposes.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> that where any person or persons has or shall run out of this state the property of a deceased person or persons to the injury of the orphans of said deceased, or to the injury of the next of kin entitled to the same, it shall and may be lawful for the Judges of the several Courts of Equity in this state, upon application and the facts being stated on oath made to the truth thereof, and also the property being described and its value sworn to by the person or persons entitled to said estate, his, her or their agent or attorney, to give the party a remedy either by arresting the defendant or taking his property, or both, as the Court in its discretion shall deem necessary and proper<i>Provided always,</i> that the Judge granting the same shall take good security

<page id="GA1814.1.P3" no="GA1814.1.4" />

of the party, his, her or their agent or attorney, in double the amount sworn, to make good all costs and damages the defendant shall sustain, if the plaintiff shall discontinue or be cast in the said suit.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that the defendant if arrested, and his property also if taken, shall be discharged and returned to him on his giving good security to perform the order and decree of the Court.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that if the defendant fails, or neglects or refuses to give such security, the Court may make such disposition of the property as in its discretion it shall deem most advantageous to the parties on both sides.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that in all cases where a verdict shall hereafter be rendered and judgment entered and signed thereon in any of the Superior or Inferior Courts of this state, the party against whom such judgment shall be so entered may stay all further proceedings by entering good and sufficient security, either in open Court or in the Clerk's office within ten days after the judgment of said Court, for the payment of the judgment and costs within twelve months from the date of said judgment, and if such party shall not pay the same agreeably thereto, execution may issue against such party and the security without any other proceedings thereon.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that all parties against whom judgments are rendered in any of the Justices Courts in this state, shall be entitled to the benefits and provisions of the foregoing sections upon their complying with the terms therein required, by giving security to the Justices of the Peace.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that it shall not be lawful for any of the Judges of the Superior Courts, Justices of the Inferior Courts, or Justices of the Peace in this state, to suffer any verdicts to be rendered, or judgments entered or signed in any or either of their said courts against any soldier or officer of this state, whilst such soldier or officer is in the service of this state or of the United States; but in all cases where it shall be made satisfactorily to appear to any of the said courts that either of the parties to any case in either of their said courts depending, is in the service aforesaid, the same shall be held, deemed and considered

<page id="GA1814.1.P4" no="GA1814.1.5" />

a good ground and sufficient cause of continuance of said case, if either of said parties, their agent or attorney, choose to claim the sameNor shall any execution be levied on, or the property of any such soldier or officer be sold, by virtue of any execution which has heretofore or may hereafter be issued against him, whilst he is in the service aforesaid, or on his way to or returning from the place of rendezvous, or within six months after the expiration of the term of service of such soldier, <i>provided</i> such soldier shall within twenty days after the expiration of his term of service give security, as other persons are required to do by this act; nor shall any civil process whatever be issued against any soldier or officer whilst in such service.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that in all cases where judgment has already been obtained in any of the courts aforesaid, the party against whom the same has been obtained may, by complying with the terms contained in the fourth section of this act, claim and receive the benefits and provisions of said sectionand where execution has already issued, the officer in whose hands the same may be, shall be bound to take the security required as directed in said section.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>In the House of Representatives, 22d November, 1814, repassed by a majority of two thirds of the House, agreeable to the provisions of the Constitution.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker.</p><p>Attest,</p><p>A. S. CLAYTON, <i>[Illegible Text]</i></p><p>Repassed by two thirds of the Senate, 23d November, 1814.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>Attest,</p><p>WILL ROBERTSON, <i>Sec'ry.</i></p><approvaldate>Dissented to by the Governor, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P5" no="GA1814.1.6" />

<law id="L1814V1N002" initial.page="6"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To make permanent the scite of the public buildings in the county of Emanuel, and to add two more Commissioners to the board of Commissioners heretofore appointed to contract and build said Court-House and Jail for said county.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> that the scite of the public buildings be at or within one mile of the place pointed out by Jesse Mezzell to be the centre of said county.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that Jesse Mezzell and Archibald Culberth be appointed Commissioners to join the board of Commissioners heretofore appointed to contract and carry into effect the building of the Court-house and Jail of said countyand the said Commissioners or a majority of them shall have the same power, and to be governed by the same law passed to that effect the sixth day of December, 1813, so far as respects the contracting and building said court-house and jail, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N003" initial.page="6"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To levy a [Illegible Text] for the support of Government for the political year</i> 1815, <i>and to reimburse the state in part the sum for which his Excellency the Governor is authorised by a concurred resolution to settle with the General Government the Direct Tax for the political year</i> 1814.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> that the act to impose a tax for the support of government for the year 1813, with the amendments made for the year 1814, be and they are hereby revived and continued in force for the political year 1815.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P6" no="GA1814.1.7" />

<p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that for the purpose of reimbursing the state in part the sum directed to be paid by his Excellency in conformity with the said resolution, that each citizen of this state, and all other persons holding taxable property real or personal in said state, is, and are hereby liable and required to pay a tax of 50 per centum on the amount of the state tax required of him, her or them, for the support of the government of this state, for the political year 1814, which shall be collected and settled by the Tax-Collectors with the Comptroller General, on or before the 1st day of Dec'r, 1815, under the same rules, regulations and restrictions, as are pointed out for the collection of the state tax now in force in this state; and it shall be the duty of the respective Tax-Collectors in this State, to collect the tax herein assessed, agreeably to the requisitions of an act entitled an act to authorize his Excellency the Governor to settle with the United States the amount of the direct tax due by the state of Georgia, and to point out the method of reimbursing the state the said sum in part, passed on the 6th day of December, 1813<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> that in case any of the Tax-Collectors aforesaid shall refuse or neglect to collect the tax aforesaid upon the terms pointed out in the before recited act, then and in that case the Justices of the Inferior Courts in counties where such refusal shall be made, shall proceed to appoint one fit and proper person to receive and collect said tax, agreeably to the requisitions of the tax laws now in force in this state; and the said Collectors so appointed as aforesaid, shall be commissioned by the Governor as heretofore practised for other Tax-Collectors in this state; and <i>provided also,</i> that such Collectors so to be appointed as aforesaid, if any such should be appointed as aforesaid, shall give bond and security in conformity with the tax laws now in force in this state, for the faithful performance of his or their duty as Collectors, which may be appointed in conformity with this act; and for the purpose of ascertaining the amount of tax required by this act, it shall be the duty of the Clerks of the Inferior Courts to deliver to such Collectors appointed in conformity with this act, the Digest of the Receiver of Tax-Returns, deposited in their offices.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that the Collectors aforesaid shall signify his or their acceptance or refusal in writing, to perform the duties by this act required, to three

<page id="GA1814.1.P7" no="GA1814.1.8" />

or more of the Justices of the Inferior Courts aforesaid, on or before the 1st Monday in January next, and shall give bond and additional security in terms of the tax laws now in force in this state:And <i>provided also,</i> that in case of such refusal being made by the Tax-Collector, the Inferior Court shall not appoint the said Tax-Collector to collect said tax.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that no security or securities for Tax-Collectors shall be entitled to hold the office of Sheriff in any county in this state until all monies collected by the said Tax-Collector or Collectors shall have been paid by him or them to the proper authorities.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that in all cases where the Treasurer and Comptroller General shall issue executions against delinquent Tax-Collectors, it shall be lawful for any Sheriff into whose hands such execution or executions may be placed, to collect from such delinquent Tax-Collector two and an half per cent on, and in addition to the amount of such execution or executions, which shall be full compensation for the trouble and expence of such Sheriff or Sheriffs, in collecting and paying over at the Treasury, the amount of such execution or executions as may be placed in their hands as aforesaid<i>Provided,</i> that every Sheriff who shall receive said per cent shall be liable to refund the same to the Collector from whom it may be received, if he does not return the execution and pay over the money collected thereon for the state at the Treary, on or before the day he may be required so to do by said execution.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> that no Collector shall hereafter be allowed an insolvent list, if he do not obtain the same at some term of the Superior Court prior to the day on which he may be required to close his accompt at the Comptroller General's office<i>Provided,</i> he shall not have been prevented from obtaining his insolvent list by reason of a failure of the Courts.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P8" no="GA1814.1.9" />

<law id="L1814V1N004" initial.page="9"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To alter and amend an act, entitled, an act to organize the detachments of men which may hereafter be required by the President of the U. States, from the Executive of this state, for the service of the Union, and for other purposes therein expressed. Passed on the</i> 6<i>th day of December,</i> 1813.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> that for the better organizing the detachments of militia which may hereafter be called into service, it shall and may be lawful for his Excellency the Governor to issue orders to the respective Major Generals from whose divisions detachments of militia may be called, directing him to order elections for field and company officers; and whose duty it shall be to issue orders accordingly, and to appoint the officers to advertise, hold and preside at such electionsand it shall be the duty of the officers thus appointed, to advertise said elections ten days previously to holding the same, and all persons shall be entitled to vote at such election who will be subject to the command of such officers when elected; and that in case such detachment should be marched to the place of rendezvous or encampment, previous to the election of any regimental, battalion, or company officers, it shall be the duty of the General or commanding officer of such detachment, to order an election for field and company officers, or other vacancy, as the case may requireand it shall be the duty of the presiding officers or a majority of them, forthwith after such election, to certify the person or persons having the highest number of votes, and make a return thereof to the Governor, who shall thereupon issue special commissions to the officers elected; and it shall and may be lawful for the commanding officer of the detachment to issue brevets to the officers elected until their commissions are received.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that in case of the death, resignation or other vacancy of any field or company officers of detachments in service, such vacancy shall be immediately filled by appointment to be made by the commissioned officers belonging to such detachments; and it shall be the duty of the commanding officer

<page id="GA1814.1.P9" no="GA1814.1.10" />

of said detachment, within ten days thereafter, to transmit a return thereof to his Excellency the Governor, who shall thereupon issue commissions to the person or persons so appointedand it shall and may be lawful for the commanding officer to brevet the officer or officers appointed till his or their commissions are received, and during the time that intervenes between such vacancy and the issuing brevets, the officer next in rank shall be the officer commandingand in case of the death, resignation or removal of any non-commissioned officer belonging to such detachment, the Captain of the company to which such non-commissioned officer was attached, shall forthwith proceed to fill such vacancy.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that there shall be attached to each regiment called into service one Colonel, one Lieut. Colonel, two Majors, one Adjutant, one Quarter-Masier, one Pay-Master, one Chaplain, one Surgeon, two Surgeon-Mates, one Sergeant-Major, one Quarter-Master Sergeant, and two principal Musiciansand to each company there shall be attached one Captain, one first Lieutenant, one second Lieutenant, one third Lieutenant, one Ensign, five Sergeants, four Corporals, two Musicians and ninety privates.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that nothing contained in this act shall operate in the smallest manner upon detachments heretofore called into service.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that his Excellency the Governor shall be and he is hereby authorised to consolidate the volunteer Infantry and Rifle companies of this state, in such manner as he may deem advisable and expedient for the public welfare, <i>provided</i> they should not be full previous to their call to take the field, and to select either of the Captains of said companies thus consolidated, to command such consolidated company when called into service; and the other commissioned officers of said company shall be appointed by the field officers and Captain of said company, out of the officers attached to either or any of the companies composing the said consolidated company; and the non-commissioned officers shall be appointed by the Captain.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that it shall be lawful and his Execellency the Governor is hereby authorised, to call into the service of the United States or of this state, any portion of Cavalry, to act either

<page id="GA1814.1.P10" no="GA1814.1.11" />

as light Dragoons or as mounted Infantry, and he may consolidate incomplete troops, provided such consolidation be made of troops belonging to the same squadronand the Captains of such consolidated troops shall be selected by the Major commanding the squadron in which such consolidation may take place, together with the Colonel to whose regiment such squadron is attached and the Brigade Major of the Cavalry, or a majority of them, out of the Captains of the troops so consolidatedthe other commissioned officers shall be selected from the officers of said consolidated troops by the Major aforesaid, the brigade Major of Cavalry and the Captain selected as aforesaidthe non-commissioned officers to be appointed by the commissioned officers<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> that nothing herein contained shall prevent incomplete troops from forming voluntary conselidations as aforesaidand his Excellency the Governor shall in all cases recognize such voluntary consolidated associations and give preference to them for the service aforesaid.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that when any detachment or detachments of militia or volunteer companies shall be hereafter called into service, the men belonging to the class ordered out shall appear at the place of rendezvous at the time appointed, or offer a suitable substitute, to be received at the discretion of the Captain commanding said companyand on failure thereof the commanding officer of said company shall be and he is hereby invested with full and ample power to coerce the attendance of any defaulter.</p><p> 8. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> that it shall be the duty of all persons subject to militia duty, who shall remove from the district wherein they were classed, to report themselves within ten days after such removal to the commanding officer of the district to which they may so remove, and produce a certificate from under the hand of the Captain of the district from which they have so removed, specifying the class to which they belong, and on failure thereof, he or they shall be attached to the class that will next thereafter be called into service.</p><p> 9. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the respective lieutenant colonels or commanding officers of regiments are hereby authorised and required to convene as soon as may be after the passage of this act, the commissioned officers of their respective regiments, or so many thereof as will make

<page id="GA1814.1.P11" no="GA1814.1.12" />

a number not less than thirteen, at their respective regimental muster grounds, giving at least ten days notice of such convention by advertisement in each captain's district, in such regimental district, setting forth the day and place where such convention shall be held, and the purpose for which they are convened, which shall be for hearing and determining on all applications for exemptions from militia serviceand that from and immediately after the passage of this act, the captains of the different militia districts, be and they are hereby directed to enrol for duty all persons within their respective districts supposed to be over the age of eighteen and under the age of forty-five years.</p><p> 10. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That in counties containing but one battalion, and not attached to any regiment, the major or commanding officer of such battalion shall proceed to convene the officers at their battalion muster grounds for the same purposes, and under like restrictions and regulations as prescribed by this act for the convention of officers in the respective regiments.</p><p> 11. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That where any person who has been, or hereafter may be classed, shall thereafter be promoted to the rank of a commissioned officer, such person shall not then be liable to perform the duty required of him in the ranks during the time he shall continue in commission; but in case he should resign, or be cashiered, such person shall return into the ranks and class to which he formerly belonged.</p><p> 12. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the students at the University subject to military duty shall be classed as other persons liable to militia service, except that such students may be divided in three classes in such manner as the major commanding the battalion in which they reside shall direct; and they shall be enroled in the first, second and third classes, in such manner as may be most conducive to the interest of the said institution, or that each class be at liberty to draw for their classes, and be enroled accordingly.</p><p> 13. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the surgeons of the different regiments, be and they are hereby required to attend each session of their respective regimental courts martial.</p><p> 14. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That his excellency the governor, be and he is hereby required to cause the second and third classes of the militia in this state, to be officered,

<page id="GA1814.1.P12" no="GA1814.1.13" />

as soon as convenient, agreeably to the provisions of this act.</p><p> 15. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all laws and parts of laws militating against this law, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N005" initial.page="13"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To appropriate monies for the political year one thousand eight hundred and fifteen.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That for the support of government for the political year one thousand eight hundred and fifteen, the following sums of money be, and the same are hereby appropriated, viz:</p><p>The salary of the Governor shall be two thousand dollars per annum; Secretaries of the Executive Department not exceeding two, five hundred dollars each; The Secretary of State two hundred dollars; The Treasurer twelve hundred dollars; The Surveyor General two hundred dollars; The Comptroller General six hundred dollars; the Clerk of the House of Representatives and Secretary of Senate three hundred dollars each; The Judges of the Superior Courts fourteen hundred dollars each; The Attorney General and three Solicitors General one hundred and fifty dollars each; which said several sums shall be, and the same are hereby appropriated for their use, to be paid quarter yearly, by warrant from the Governor on the Treasurer, out of any money not otherwise specially appropriated.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of twenty thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated as a contingent fund, subject to the orders of the Governor.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That for the compensation of the Members of the Legislature, three dollars each per day during their attendance be appropriated, and the

<page id="GA1814.1.P13" no="GA1814.1.14" />

sum of three dollars for every twenty miles in coming to and returning from the Seat of Government; and the sum of four dollars each per day to the President of the Senate and Speaker of the House of Representatives during their attendance, and the sum of three dollars each for every twenty miles in coming to and returning from the Seat of Government; To the Clerk of the House of Representatives and Secretary of the Senate during the sitting of the Legislature four dollars each per day, and the sum of sixty dollars for contingent expences; To the two engrossing Clerks and one assistant Clerk to the House of Representatives, and two engrossing Clerks to the Senate four dollars each per day; To the Clerk to the committee on Finance and to the Clerk of the committee on the State of the Republic sixty dollars each; to the Messengers and Door Keepers of the Legislature three dollars per day each during the session; To the Adjutant General twelve hundred dollars per annum, to be paid quarter yearly; And the sum of fifty thousand dollars to be set apart as a fund for Military disbursements, to be drawn for by His Excellency the Governor as he may think the public safety and expedience may require; To Alexander Green eighty dollars for airing, scouring and taking care of the State House, the desks and carpets in the recess of the Legislature and making fires on wet days, c. To Peter Fair sixty dollars for winding up the clock, keeping clean the stair cases, passages, c. To John M. Patrick the sum of eighty dollars, agreeably to a concurred and approved resolution.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of ten thousand dollars be and the same is hereby appropriated toward the completing the Penitentiary building, to be drawn by His Excellency as he may [Illegible Text] necessary.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of twenty thousand dollars be and the same is hereby appropriated for the re-payment of that sum which his Excellency the Governor has been authorised to borrow from the Banks of this state, to be advanced to the Quarter Master's Department on account of the United States, by a concurred resolution of both Houses of the present Legislature, provided he should find it necessary to negotiate a loan in pursuance of said resolution.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of fourteen dollars and thirty cents be appropriated to Seth Williams,

<page id="GA1814.1.P14" no="GA1814.1.15" />

fifteen dollars and thirty cents to Robert Kelly and six dollars and eighty cents to James [Illegible Text] in full compensation for their several services in riding as expresses; And that the sum of one hundred and thirty six dollars seventeen and a half cents be and the same is hereby ordered to be re-paid to Johnson  Kunze, that amount being over paid by them in discharging their taxes to the state; To Captain David Clarke two hundred and ten dollars, being the amount advanced by him for the purchase of a field piece for the Jefferson County Artillery<i>Provided,</i> That the said piece shall be the property of the state, and subject to the requisitions of the Commander in Chief.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of one hundred and seventy thousand dollars be and the same is hereby set apart subject to the draft of His Excellency the Governor to enable him to discount and settle the direct tax of this state, agreeable to a concurred resolution of both branches of the Legislature, with such discount as the general government may propose.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N006" initial.page="15"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To alter and amend an act to extend the operation of the Laws of this state, over the persons resident in Wafford's settlement, and to organize the same, passed the eighth December,</i> 1806.</fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the first day of June next, the third section of the before recited act be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 9th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P15" no="GA1814.1.16" />

<law id="L1814V1N007" initial.page="16"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To alter the times of holding the Superior Courts of the Middle Circuit in this state.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the end of the present Circuit of the Superior Courts in the Middle Circuit of this state, the said Superior Courts shall be holden as follows;</p><div><title>SPRING CIRCUIT.<br set="CENTER" /></title><p>On the third Monday in February, in the county of Jefferson; On the fourth Monday in February, in the county of Warren; On the first Monday in March, in the county of Columbia; On the second Monday in March, in the county of Scriven; On the third Monday in March in the county of Burke; On the fourth Monday in March, in the county of Washington; On the Monday thereafter, in the county of Montgomery; On the Monday thereafter, in the county of Tatnall; On the Monday thereafter, in the county of Emanuel; And on the fourth Monday in May, in the county of Richmond.</p></div><div><title>FALL CIRCUIT.<br set="CENTER" /></title><p>On the third Monday in August, in the county of Jefferson; On the fourth Monday in August, in the county of Warren; On the first Monday in September, in the county of Columbia; On the second Monday in September, in the county of Scriven; On the third Monday in September, in the county of Burke; On the fourth Monday in September, in the county of Washington; On the Monday thereafter, in the county of Montgomery; On the Monday thereafter, in the county of Tatnall; On the Friday thereafter, in the county of Emanuel; And on the second Monday in January, in the county of Richmond.</p></div><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all writs, suits, recognizances, together with other matter and things which may have been made returnable to the days heretofore appointed for holding the said Courts, shall be made returnable as herein pointed out, any law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P16" no="GA1814.1.17" />

<p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That all laws or parts of laws militating against this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 9th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N008" initial.page="17"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To authorise the collection of rent within the city of Augusta and the precincts thereof.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passage of this act, it shall and may be lawful for any person or persons within the city of Augusta or the precincts thereof, where the sum does not exceed thirty dollars, to apply for and obtain from a Justice of the Peace a distress warrant for the sum claimed to be due, which warrant shall be founded on the oath in writing, of the party, his agent or attorney for the sum claimed to be due, and it shall and may be lawful for any constable duly qualified, to levy the same on any property belonging to the tenant or tenants; and it shall be the duty of the constable levying said distress warrant, to advertise and sell in the same manner as is pointed out by the Judiciary for sales under execution; and when the rent claimed to be due exceeds the sum of thirty dollars, it shall and may be lawful for the Judge of the Superior or Justices of the Inferior Court of Richmond county to issue a distress warrant authorising and directing the Sheriff, or any lawful constable to distrain any property belonging to the tenant or tenants, and advertise and sell the same as in cases of executions<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That the said tenant or tenants shall be entitled to replevy the goods and chattels so distrained, by making oath that the amount claimed as rent, or some part thereof distrained for, is not

<page id="GA1814.1.P17" no="GA1814.1.18" />

due, and give security for the eventual condemnation money; and in that case it shall be the duty of such officer to return the same to the Court having cognizance thereof, and the same shall be determined by a Jury as practised in other cases; and the Jury on the trial of all such cases shall take the following oathYou shall well and truly try the case depending between A B distrainor, and C D distrainee, and a true verdict give according to evidence, so help you God.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That when any property may be distrained and claimed by a third person, the same shall be claimed on oath, and shall be returned and determined in like manner and under the same rules and regulations as are by law pointed out for the trial of the right of property; and the Jury shall in all such cases take the following oathYou shall well and truly try the cause depending between A B distrainor, and C D claimant, and a true verdict give according to evidence, and you do further swear that you will give to the distrainor such damages against the claimant, as to you shall seem reasonable and just, provided it shall appear to you that the claim is frivolous, and intended for delay onlyso help you God.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That in no case a preference shall be given to persons distraining for rent where there are any judgments against the person or property so distrained.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That when any tenant or tenants hold over his or their lease, it shall and may be lawful for the landlord to demand, collect and receive double rent.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all laws and parts of laws militating against this law shall be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P18" no="GA1814.1.19" />

<law id="L1814V1N009" initial.page="19"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>For adding a part of Tatnall county to Montgomery county, and for other purposes.</i></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That all that part of Tatnall county, contained in, or lying to the North West of the following boundary, be added to Montgomery county; begining at the place where the present line of Montgomery and Tatnall counties strikes Millecan's creek, thence a direct line to James M`Cloud's, including said M`Cloud in Montgomery county, then in a direct course to the present boundary line between Tatnall and Montgomery counties; and that the county Surveyor of Montgomery be directed within nine months to run out and mark said line; and that the Inferior Court of the county of Montgomery, be authorised and required to pay the said Surveyor out of the county funds, a sum which may in their opinion be commensurate with the services by him performed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 11th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N010" initial.page="19"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To divorce Alexander Fluellen and Kizziah his wife.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the aforesaid Alexander Fluellen, according to an act of the General Assembly, passed on the fifth day of December, eighteen hundred and six, commenced an action in the Superior Court of Putnam county, against his said wife Kizziah for a divorce, and whereas at March term eighteen hundred and twelve, of said Court, the said cause was tried by a Special Jury, who rendered into Court a verdict for an absolute divorce,</p><p> 1. BE <i>it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, the matrimonial

<page id="GA1814.1.P19" no="GA1814.1.20" />

connexion and civil contract of matrimony made between the aforesaid Alexander Fluellen and Kizziah his wife, late Kizziah Peoples, shall be completely annuled and set aside and dissolved, as fully and effectually as if no such contract had been made and entered into between them.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said Kizziah Fluellen, late Kizziah Peoples, is hereby declared to be a feme sole, and the said Alexander Fluellen shall not in future be bound on any [Illegible Text] whatever, for the payment of any debts, dues or demands of the said Kizziah, on or for her contracting, or with any actions of, or for damages, for or by reason of any tort, [Illegible Text] or damages whatever, hereafter to be committed by the aforesaid Kizziah [Illegible Text], late Kizziah Peoples.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N011" initial.page="20"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To secure to John M`Kinne and Henry Shultz, their heirs and assigns, the exclusive right to a Bridge across Savannah river, at or near Augusta.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS John M`Kinne and Henry Shultz, have, by their memorial made it known to the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia, that they have at very considerable expence, and with great personal attention, erected a strong, elegant and substantial bridge across the river Savannah, at the city of Augusta, well calculated to facilitate the intercourse of this state with the state of South Carolina, and of consequence of great public utility and convenienceand stating that they are now the proprietors of said Bridge, and praying that they may be secured in the exclusive right to the same.AND WHEREAS it is just and proper that the fostering and protecting arm of the government should be extended to all such valuable undertakings,</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P20" no="GA1814.1.21" />

<p> 1. BE <i>it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the exclusive right of erecting, having or keeping a Bridge across the river Savannah at [Illegible Text], or within four miles thereof, either above or below said city, be and the same is hereby vested in John M`Kinne and Henry Shultz, their heirs and assigns, as tenants in common and not as joint tenants, for, during and until the full end and term of twenty years, from and after the passing of this act<i>Provided,</i> That the said John M`Kinne and Henry Shultz shall keep said Bridge in good repair<i>And provided also,</i> That nothing herein contained shall operate to defeat, or in the slightest manner to impair the right of the Trustees of the Richmond Academy to the ferry landing at Augusta<i>And provided also,</i> That the consent of the said Trustees be obtained. <i>Provided also,</i> That nothing contained in this act, shall be so construed as to prevent the running of a ferry-flat at Wallicon's ferry or at Campbellton.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That it shall and may be lawful for the said John M`Kinne and Henry Shultz, their heirs and assigns, to demand, have and receive the following toll, and no more, at their said Bridge, for the term aforesaid, to wit:For every waggon and team, seventy five cents: for every four wheel carriage, seventy five cents: for every two wheel carriage, thirty seven and a half cents: for every cart, thirty seven and a half cents: for every rolling hogshead of any kind, twenty five cents: for a man and horse, twelve and a half cents: for a man on foot, six and a quarter cents: for every horse or cow, six and a quarter cents: for every hog, goat or sheep, four cents.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That no other Bridge across the Savannah river shall be established or permitted on any pretence whatever, within four miles of the city of Augusta, either above or below the said city; unless by the consent and approbation of the said John M`Kinne and Henry Shultz, their heirs or assigns, during the continuance of the exclusive right hereby vested in the said John M`Kinne and Henry Shultz, their heirs and assigns.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i>

<page id="GA1814.1.P21" no="GA1814.1.22" />

That if the Bridge so erected by the said M'Kinne and Shultz, shall be destroyed by freshets or otherwise, and shall not be again rebuilt within two years thereafter, or if the said Bridge shall from want of repairs or from any other cause be impassable for the space of two years at any one time, then and in such case, the right hereby vested in the said John M`Kinne and Henry Shultz, shall immediately thereafter cease, determine and become void, as if this act had never passed.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all acts and parts of acts militating against this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 9th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N012" initial.page="22"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To divorce and seperate John Womack and Mary his wife.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passage of this act, the matrimonial connexion or civil contract of marriage made between the said John Womack and Mary his wife, formerly Mary Hudson, shall be completely annuled, set aside and absolved, as fully and effectually to all intents and purposes, as if no such contract had ever been made between them.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said John Womack and Mary, shall in future be deemed and considered as separate and distinct persons, altogether unconnected by any mystical union or civil contract whatever, at any time made or heretofore entered into between them.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 16th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P22" no="GA1814.1.23" />

<law id="L1814V1N013" initial.page="23"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To create the office of Pay Master General for this state, and point out the mode of his election.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the office of Pay Master General for this state be, and the same is hereby created.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the said Pay Master General shall be elected by joint ballot of both branches of the General Assembly of this state; and in case of vacancies happening in the said office by death, resignation, or otherwise, that the said office shall be filled in the same manner as has hitherto been the practice in respect to the Quarter Master General thereof.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the said Pay Master General have the rank of Lieut. Colonel, and receive pay while in service, as the General Government have or may determine by law.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 16th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N014" initial.page="23"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To authorise the commissioners therein named to establish a Lottery for the purpose of raising the sum of seven thousand dollars, the better to enable Henry Heald, Jacob Gregg and Robert Pearman, to erect a Woollen Factory at some convenient place in the upper part of this state.</i></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That it shall  may be lawful for the commissioners herein after named, to establish a lottery within two years from  after the passing of this act, to raise the sum of seven thousand dollars, under such scheme and regulations as they or a majority of them may deem necessary and proper to carry into effect the above recited object.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P23" no="GA1814.1.24" />

<p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said Henry Heald, Jacob Gregg and Robert Pearman, or the survivors of them, shall, before they are entitled to receive the amount of money so raised, agreeable to the provisions of this act, enter into a bond, with three or more good securities, made payable to his Excellency the Governor for the time being, and his successors in office, in the penal sum of fourteen thousand dollars, to be void on condition, that if the money so raised as aforesaid, shall be applied and appropriated to the special purpose as contemplated by this act<i>Provided,</i> That the said Henry, Jacob and Robert shall give bond with good and sufficient securities in the sum of fifty thousand dollars to his Excellency the Governor, faithfully to discharge their duties, and also to account with the fortunate drawers in the said lottery, for the sum or sums which shall be drawnand in case the said lottery shall not be drawn, to return the sum or sums advanced for tickets in said lottery.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That Moses Speer, Anderson Dabney, Thomas S. Bonner, Tandy W. Key and Benson Henry, or a majority of them, be, and they are hereby appointed commissioners to carry into effect the aforesaid lottery.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N015" initial.page="24"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To amend an act, entitled an act to regulate attachments in this state, passed the</i> 18<i>th day of February,</i> 1799.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the above recited act has been found by experience to be inadequate to the complete effectuation of the purposes intended, and to require amendment,</p><p> 1. BE <i>it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That where any sheriff or constable shall levy any attachment on personal property, claimed by any person, not a party to such attachment, such person, his agent or attorney,

<page id="GA1814.1.P24" no="GA1814.1.25" />

shall make oath to such propertyand it shall be the duty of such sheriff or constable to return the fact of such claim, to the court to which the attachment shall be made returnableand such court shall cause an issue to be joined between the plaintiff and such claimant, and the right of property to be decided on by a jury at the same term, unless sufficient cause be shewn to induce the court to continue the same<i>Provided</i> the person claiming such property, his agent or attorney, shall give bond (to the sheriff or constable serving such attachment) with security in a sum equal to the amount of such attachmentconditioned to pay to the plaintiff all damages which the jury, on the trial of the right of property, may assess against such claimant, in case it should appear that such claim was made for the purpose of delay. And every juror on the trial of such claim shall be sworn in addition to the oath usually administered, to give such damages as may seem reasonable and just to the plaintiff, against the claimant, in case it shall be sufficiently shewn, that such claim was intended for the purpose of delay onlyand it shall be lawful for the plaintiff to enter up judgment and have execution against such claimant, for the amount of such verdictand where the jury shall find the property not subject to the attachment, the claimant may enter up judgment and have execution against the plaintiff for the costs by him incurred in establishing his claim.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That land or real estate shall not be subject to be attached under or by virtue of any attachment issuing and returnable out of the county in which such land is situateand in all cases of claims to land, levied on by virtue of any attachment, the proceedings shall be the same as those pointed out by the preceding section for claims to other propertyexcept that such claim shall be returned to, and tried in the Superior Court of the county where the land is situate.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That no person who may be summoned as Garnishee, shall be compelled to answer to any attachment out of the county in which such Garnishee lived at the time of serving such attachmentand where any Garnishee shall return that he has in his hands a note or notes, bond or bonds, or other evidences of debt belonging to the absent debtor, the same shall be forthwith deposited with the Clerk of the Court in which the attachment is pending, subject to the order of said Court;

<page id="GA1814.1.P25" no="GA1814.1.26" />

and after the plaintiff shall have established his demand against the absent debtor, the court may in its discretion direct the clerk to deliver to the plaintiff in such attachment, his agent or attorney, such note or notes, bond or bonds, or other evidence of debt, or so much thereof as will be sufficient to discharge the amount of the demand which the plaintiff shall have established against the defendant, taking a receipt therefor, which receipt [Illegible Text] be filed with the papers appertaining to such attachment, and shall be considered as a payment to that amount; unless the plaintiff shall make it appear that after due diligence used by him, he was unable to collect the amountand where the evidence so deposited is of a debt greater than the plaintiff's demand, and will not admit of division, the court shall order the same to be sued for, in such manner as will, in their discretion, best ensure recovery, and the money when collected, to be deposited with the clerk of the court in which the attachment pended, a part to be applied to the discharge of the amount due the attaching creditor, the balance to remain subject to the future order of said court.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That no suit by way of attachment shall abate by the death of either party, where the cause of action would survive to the executor or administrator, but such death being suggested on the record, the cause shall proceed under the restrictions and regulations followingwhen a plaintiff in attachment shall die, the executor or administrator of such plaintiff shall within six months after the probate of the Will, and obtaining letters testamentary, or obtaining letters of administration, cause to be issued by the clerk of the court in which such attachment is pending, a scire facias returnable to the next term of the said court, giving notice of his intention to become a party in the place and stead of the deceased testator or intestate, which shall be published at the door of the court house in the county in which such attachment is pending by the sheriff of said county, at least twenty days prior to the term at which such scire facias is made returnable; which being done, such executor or administrator may on motion, be made party plaintiff, and the cause proceedand where the defendent shall die, scire facias shall issue in manner aforesaid, immediately after the expiration of twelve months, which scire facias shall contain a notice to the legal representatives of the defendant, whether

<page id="GA1814.1.P26" no="GA1814.1.27" />

executor or administrator, of the pendency of such attachment, and of the intention of the plaintiff to proceed with the same; which being published in like manner, it shall be lawful for the plaintiff to proceed with his attachment, as if such death had not taken place<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That the executor or administrator of the [Illegible Text] may appear at the return of the scire facias, and upon giving security in terms of the act to which this is amendatory, shall be permitted to plead and defend the said attachment in the same manner that his testator or intestate might have done.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That in cases of attachments pending in Justices [Illegible Text], where either party shall die, such attachment shall not abate, but a notice of the intention of the representatives of the plaintiff, whether executor or administrator, to proceed, being published at the house where such Justices Courts are holden, by the constable of the district, ten days before the time at which parties are to be made, such parties shall thereupon be made and the cause proceed.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That where any witness resides out of this state, or out of the county in which any attachment may be pending, and in which his testimony may be required, it shall be lawful for the plaintiff, on filing interrogatories in the office of the clerk of the court where such attachment is pending, and publishing a notice at the door of the court house of said county, that such interrogatories are filed, to obtain a commission in like manner, as is prescribed by the 23d section of the Judiciary act of 1799, for taking testimony in other cases.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That in all cases the attachment first served shall be first satisfied.</p><p> 8. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That no lien shall be created by the levying of an attachment to the exclusion of any judgment obtained by any creditor, before judgment is obtained by the attaching creditor.</p><p> 9. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i>

<page id="GA1814.1.P27" no="GA1814.1.28" />

That so much of the before recited act as may be repugnant to this act, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President ef the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N016" initial.page="28"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To encourage an improved mode of transporting merchandize upon the waters of the state of Georgia.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS Samuel Howard of the city of Savannah, hath presented a memorial to the General Assembly, in which he proposes to adopt a new and improved mode of transporting merchandise upon the waters of the state of Georgia, by towing and warping the ships, vessels, boats and rafts, in and upon which the same may be laden, by means of other boats or vessels impelled by the aid of steam. AND WHEREAS it is right that those who bestow their time and money upon enterprises of public utility should be secured in the enjoyment of the fruit of their exertions and experiments,</p><p> 1. BE <i>it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That in order to encourage the said Samuel Howard and his heirs, and his and their associates in the prosecution of the object of public utility in which they are about to engage, the exclusive right of transporting merchandise upon the waters of the state of Georgia, in or upon ships, vessels, boats or rafts, warped or towed by means of other vessels or boats impelled by the aid of steam, be and the same is hereby vested in the said Samuel Howard, his heirs and assigns and his or their associates for and during the term of twenty years.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That during the continuance of the said term of twenty years, it shall not be lawful for any person or persons, other than the said Samuel Howard, his heirs and assigns and their associates, to transport merchandise upon the waters

<page id="GA1814.1.P28" no="GA1814.1.29" />

of the state of Georgia by means of said improved mode of transportation<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That nothing herein contained shall be construed to prevent any person or persons from transporting merchandise in any other mode now in use thereon at his or their [Illegible Text], or any other way that may hereafter be discovered, so that the progress thereof is not aided by the power of [Illegible Text].</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if any person or persons other than the said Samuel Howard, his heirs or assigns and their associates, shall during the continuance of the said term of twenty years before mentioned, transport or cause to be transported, any merchandise in or upon any ship, boat, vessel or raft, towed or warped by means of any other boat or boats, vessel or vessels impelled by the aid of steam, he or they so offending shall forfeit and pay for every such offence the sum of five hundred dollars, as well as the boat or boats, vessel or vessels and all her machinery, by means of which such transportation shall be effected, to be recovered by bill, plaint, indictment or otherwise, in any court having competent jurisdictionone half of such fine and forfeiture to go to the use of the prosecutor and the other half to the use of the state.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That so much of an act passed 18th February, 1799, entitled an act to appoint commissioners for the purpose of co-operating with the state of South-Carolina, in improving the navigation of the river Savannah, from the city of Augusta, to the city of Savannah, as would subject property conveyed by said improved mode of transportation, to the toll therein mentioned, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if the said Samuel Howard, his heirs or assigns, or his or their associates, do not within three years from the passage of this act carry into effect the said improved mode of transportation, by putting into active operation at least one machine, that then and in such case, the exclusive right hereby granted shall cease and determineand if the said Samuel Howard does not carry into operation said steam engine on all other waters under the jurisdiction of this state within ten years, the exclusive right granted in this act shall cease on each stream so neglected<i>Provided</i> that the operation of this act, so far as it respects the river

<page id="GA1814.1.P29" no="GA1814.1.30" />

Savannah, shall be suspended until the Legislature of the state of South-Carolina have passed an act similar in its provisions with this act; and if the said Samuel Howard shall neglect or discontinue the operation of the said machine for a greater length of time, at any one time, than twelve months, that then the grant of the exclusive right aforesaid, shall be null and void<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to extend to the said Samuel Howard, the exclusive right of navigating the river Oconee, after the expiration of the patent right to John L. Sullivan, without paying such toll as may be imposed, by any act of the Legislature thereafter, upon boats of similar burthen.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That it shall be lawful for said Samuel Howard, his heirs or assigns and his or their associates, to remove from the channel of the river Savannah, any logs, trees, snags or other obstacles which may impede the safe navigation thereof, and to place the same upon the bank or shore adjacent thereto, or upon any other place in the river, whereby the safe navigation thereof may not be obstructed,  to place marks, buoys, stakes or posts, upon any other obstacles in the river which he or they may not think proper to remove.</p><p> 7. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That if any person or persons shall carelessly, negligently or wilfully place, throw or put in said river, any obstacle to the safe navigation thereof, or shall carelessly, negligently or wilfully remove or destroy any mark, buoy, post or stake placed upon any obstacle in said river, such person or persons shall forfeit and pay a sum not exceeding one hundred dollars, to be recovered by bill, plaint or indictment in any court of competent jurisdiction, one half to the use of the prosecutor, the other half to the use of the state.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P30" no="GA1814.1.31" />

<law id="L1814V1N017" initial.page="31"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To alter the names of Whitmel Rogers and Reddick Rogers.</i></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, the aforesaid Whitmel Rogers and Reddick Rogers shall be called and known by the names and style of Whitmel Rutland and Reddick Rutland.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 3d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N018" initial.page="31"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To alter the time of holding the Superior Courts in the county of Lincoln.</i></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That from and after the passage of this act, the Superior Courts of Lincoln county shall be held on the second Monday in January and last Monday in May, in every year, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all writs and precepts heretofore issued, or which may hereafter issue, shall be returned and tried on the second Monday in January and last Monday in May, in the same manner they would otherwise have been, had not the time for holding said courts been altered and changed by this act.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem:</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P31" no="GA1814.1.32" />

<law id="L1814V1N019" initial.page="32"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To alter and change the name of Eliab Hodgens to that of Eliab Jones.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, Eliab Hodgens shall be called and know by the name of Eliab Jones.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N020" initial.page="32"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To raise money for the purpose of opening and improving the navigation of the Oconee river from the mouth of Fishing Creek to Barnett's shoals.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it appears essential to the interest and convenience of the citizens of this state residing on and near the waters of the Oconee river, that the navigation of said river be improved, by means of which the produce of those parts may be conveyed with more case to market,</p><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That it shall and may be lawful for the commissioners hereinafter named, to establish a lottery within three years from and after the passing of this act, to raise the sum of ten thousand dollars, under such schemes and regulations as they or a majority of them may deem necessary and proper, to carry into effect the above recited object.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That Thomas Terrell, sen. Sterling Grimes, Jeremiah Early, Thomas Reid and John Bush, or a majority of them, be and they are hereby appointed commissioners to carry the aforesaid lottery into full effect.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P32" no="GA1814.1.33" />

<p> 3. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That the before mentioned commissioners, before entering on the duties assigned them in this act, shall give bond and security in the sum of twenty thousand dollars, to the Governor of this state, for the faithful performance of their duties.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N021" initial.page="33"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To establish an uniform mode of calculating interest in this state, and to prevent the collection of compound interest.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it is just and equitable that there shall be an uniform and definite mode practised throughout the state for calculating interest,</p><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted therefore by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That in future the mode of calculating interest in this state shall be at and after the rate of eight per cent per annum, and whenever any payment shall be made on any note, bond or other instrument, demand, execution or judgment where, any interest has accrued on any such note, bond or other instrument, execution or judgment, such payment shall, in the first place, be applied to the discharge of interest due, and no part of the principal shall be considered as discharged until the interest shall have been first extinguished<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That in all cases where the payment made shall not be sufficient to discharge all the interest due at the time of the payment, no interest shall at any future payment be calculated on the balance of interest which was left unpaid.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in all cases where judgments may hereafter be obtained, all such judgments

<page id="GA1814.1.P33" no="GA1814.1.34" />

shall be entered up for the principal sum due with the interest, but no part of such judgment shall bear interest, except the principal which may be due on the original debtany law, usage, custom or practice to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N022" initial.page="34"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To amend an act, entitled an act more effectually to open and keep in repair the public roads, causeways and bridges in this state, passed on the</i> 16<i>th of December,</i> 1811, <i>and to amend an act, entitled an act to amend an act, entitled an act more effectually to open and keep in repair the public roads, causeways and bridges in this state, passed on the</i> 10<i>th day of December,</i> 1812.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That the commissioners heretofore appointed by virtue of the above recited acts, and such as may hereafter be appointed, shall continue to discharge the duties of their said appointments, for the term of one year, and until they shall make their resignation to the Inferior Court, and shall during the time they may continue as commissioners be subject to the like penalties for neglect of duty as is pointed out by the above recited acts.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That when any of the commissioners as aforesaid, shall resign as aforesaid, the Justices of the Inferior Court, or a majority of them, shall as soon as may be thereafter, appoint other fit and proper person or persons in their stead, who shall be subject to the like service and penalties as pointed out by the above recited acts, and shall also continue to discharge the duties required of them for the term of one year from the date of their appointment, and until they shall signify their resignation to the Justices of the Inferior Court.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in case any vacancy

<page id="GA1814.1.P34" no="GA1814.1.35" />

shall happen by death, removal or other disability, the Justices of the Inferior Court, or a majority of them, shall proceed to fill such vacancy, as soon as convenient, and the person so appointed, shall be subject to the like duty and penalties as all other commissioners appointed by virtue of this and the before recited acts.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the commissioners so appointed, shall hear and determine on all cases of default for neglect of duty required by the before recited acts<i>Provided</i> such hearing and determining shall be within thirty days after such default<i>Provided also,</i> That the said commissioners, or any one of them, shall advertise in two or more of the most public places in the district, giving at least fifteen days notice of the time and place appointed for hearing and determining the same.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all monies collected by virtue of this, and the above recited acts, shall be, by the commissioners aofresaid, paid into the hands of the Clerk of the Inferior Court, to be [Illegible Text] to the repairing the public roads, bridges and causeways.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in all cases where commissioners have been, or hereafter may be appointed, for the purpose of reviewing any new road intended to be laid out, and shall report to the Inferior Court the propriety of opening the same, the said Court may, if they or a majority of them deem it advisable, pass an order for opening such road.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That in case any commissioner appointed by virtue of this or the above recited acts, shall neglect or refuse to discharge the duties required of them, as pointed out by this and the before recited acts, and information thereof being lodged with the Justices of the Inferior Court by any person, it shall be the duty of the said Court to notify such commissioner of such information, and unless excuse be offered to the satisfaction of the Justices of said court, or a majority of them, within thirty days after such notice being given, they shall direct the Clerk to issue execution against any such delinquent commissioner, for the sum for which he had laid himself liable, as pointed out by the above recited acts, directed to any constable in the district where such commissioners may reside, for the collection of said fine, and to return the same at the next term of the said court; for which services the constable collecting

<page id="GA1814.1.P35" no="GA1814.1.36" />

and returning the same, shall receive from the Justices of the Inferior Court, the usual fees, out of the money so collected<i>Provided always nevertheless,</i> That this act shall not operate in the counties of Effingham, Chatham, Bryan, Liberty, Glynn, M'Intosh, Camden, Wayne, Burke, Washington, Warren, Richmond, Jefferson, Emanuel, Laurens, Bulloch, Tatnall and Telfair.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N023" initial.page="36"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To prevent encroachments on the streets and highways in the city of Augusta, and to remove such as now exist.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the General Assembly of the state of Georgia,</i> That the Surveyor General of this state be, and he is hereby authorised and required, within three months from the date hereof, (at the proper cost and expense of the corporation of Augusta,) to repair to said city of Augusta, and then and there re-admeasure, lay off and define the whole, or so many of the public streets and other highways in said city, as the City Council thereof may deem sufficient for them hereafter to determine and fix the proper meets and bounds.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said Surveyor General shall, from the best information he can obtain, determine on and declare the ends and intersections of so many of said streets, as the said City Council may conceive necessary, and shall set up and affix at such intersections and terminations of streets, such stones or wood-posts as shall plainly and distinctly shew the same.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That when the said streets and other highways shall be defined in manner aforesaid, the same shall be binding and conclusive on the inhabitants of Augusta forever, so far only as respects the lines and boundaries of said streets. And all and every person or persons whomsoever, that have encroached, or may hereafter encroach (before the streets are defined as

<page id="GA1814.1.P36" no="GA1814.1.37" />

aforesaid,) upon any of the streets or highways in said city, by buildings, enclosures or otherwise, shall cause such obstruction or encroachment to be removed, upon three months notice thereof being giving him, her or them, their agent or attorney, by the City Council of Augusta; and on failure or refusal, the party so offending shall forfeit the sum of one hundred dollars for each and every day such obstruction or encroachment shall remain after the expiration of the said three months; the amount so forfeited to be applied to the use of the City Council of Augusta, and to be recovered by action of debt or by bill of indictment in the Superior Court of Richmond county, to be instituted by the said City Council, should they think proper to sue for the same.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said City Council shall have full power and authority to remove or cause to be removed, any such obstructions or [Illegible Text] or any other obstruction or encroachment upon the streets or highways, within the limits of said city, at the expense of such person or persons as shall cause the same, and shall issue execution against such person, their goods and chattels, lands and tenements, for the amount of such expenditures and costs; which may be levied by the Marshal of said city, or the Sheriff of Richmond county.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That after the said streets are laid off and defined in manner aforesaid, it shall be the duty of all and every person to abide by and conform to such lines as may be designated as aforesaid; and any person about to erect buildings on any of the said streets, and who shall entertain doubts as to the boundary of his or her lot on such street, shall apply to the Surveyor of the said city, or such other person as the said City Council may appoint for that purpose, whose duty it shall be to designate the same.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said City Council of Augusta, shall have full power and authority to make such bye laws, rules and regulations as they may deem necessary, fully and effectually to prevent encroachments on the said streets and highways hereafter, and to remove such as now exist, and such as may hereafter exist, as in their opinion may be least burthensome to the citizens and best

<page id="GA1814.1.P37" no="GA1814.1.38" />

calculated to promofe the good order and welfare of said city and its inhabitants,</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N024" initial.page="38"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To Divorce Elizabeth O'Reily and John O'Reily her husband, and to secure certain property to the said Elizabeth, her heirs and assigns, and to divorce Rachel Jones and Robert Jones her husband.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS It appears by an exemplification of a record from the honorable the Superior Court of the county of Richmond, that sufficient reasons were offered before a special jury of that county to induce them to find a verdict for a total divorce between Elizabeth O'Reily and her husband John O'Reilyand whereas the said Elizabeth hath by her humble petition, prayed that the said verdict may be confirmed by an act of the General Assembly of this state, and that certain property which she has acquired by her honest industry may be secured to her and her heirs.</p><p> 1. BE <i>it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act, the matrimonial connexion existing between Elizabeth O'Reily of the City of Augusta and John O'Reily her husband, be thenceforth dissolved as fully, completely and entirely to all intents and purposes, so far as respects the said Elizabeth, as if the same had never been entered into, and the said Elizabeth shall thenceforth be considered as a feme sole.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all the property real and personal which the said Elizabeth O'Reily hath acquired since the seperation of her said husband from her, particularly a house and lot on broad street, in the city of Augusta, adjoining John Mann, Esq. and the heirs of Baxter Pool, dec. and nine negroesnamely,

<page id="GA1814.1.P38" no="GA1814.1.39" />

Ben, Friday, Nann, Bett, Let, Jenny, Maria, Fan and her child Betbe and the same is hereby declared to be vested in the said Elizabeth O'Reily, her heirs and assigns, free and clear from all claim or claims of her said husband John O'Riely<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That nothing herein contained, shall operate to defeat, or in the slightest manner to impair the claim of any other person or persons to the property herein before mentioned.</p><p>And whereas it appears by an exemplification from the record of the Superior Court of the county of Columbia, that sufficient cause was shewn to a special jury of that county to induce them to authorize a total divorce, on legal principles, in a case then and there submitted to them, in which Rachel Jones was [Illegible Text] and Robert Jones defendant, in a libel for divorce. And whereas it is the sincere and earnest request of said Rachel Jones, as expressed by frequent petitions to the Legislature, that the said judgment be carried into effect and confirmed by the Legislature,</p><p> 3. <i>Be it therefore further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act the matrimonial connexion between the said Rachel Jones and Robert Jones her husband be thenceforth dissolved as fully, completely and entirely, to all intents and purposes, as respects the said Rachel, as if the same had never been entered into, and the said Rachel shall thenceforth be considered as a feme sole.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N025" initial.page="39"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To authorize the Justices of the Inferior Courts of [Illegible Text] and Telfair counties, with the Clerks of the Superior Courts and Sheriffs of said Counties, to select and draw Grand and Petit Juries for the next terms of the Superior Courts of said counties.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i>

<page id="GA1814.1.P39" no="GA1814.1.40" />

That it shall be the duty of the Justices of the Inferior Court of Pulaski county, together with the Clerk and Sheriff, or a majority of them, to convene at the Court-House in said county, on the first Monday in January next, and then and there to select from the books of the Receiver of Tax returns, fit and proper persons to serve as Grand and Petit Jurors, under the same rules and regulations as are directed by law.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That it shall be the duty of the said Justices of the Inferior Court, together with the Clerk and Sheriff, so soon as the said Grand and Petit Jurors are selected, to proceed forthwith to draw a Grand and Petit Jury to serve at the next term of the Superior Court to be holden in said county.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior Courts of Telfair county, with the Clerk  Sheriff, meet at any time, being sixty days previous to the sitting of the Superior Court, and draw Grand and Petit Jurors, and correct Jury lists.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all laws and parts of laws militating against this law, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N026" initial.page="40"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>For the relief of James Tapley.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it appears from the petition of the said James Tapley and others of the inhabitants of Montgomery county, that the said James Tapley unfortunately became security for the appearance of one Darling Glover, before the Superior Court of the county of Montgomery, for which he gave his bond to the amount of one hundred dollars, and notwithstanding the said Glover made his appearance, and was discharged from the prosecution, on payment of the costs, which he failed to do, therefore judgment was entered against the said Tapley for the amount of his bond.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P40" no="GA1814.1.41" />

<p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the said James Tapley is hereby fully and completely exonerated and discharged from said judgment, on payment of all costs on said judgment, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N027" initial.page="41"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To add all that part of the unlocated territory of this state which lies without the limits of the present counties, to the county of Jasper, for the purpose of giving the Courts jurisdiction of crimes committed by white persons against white persons in said territory, and for other purposes.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the local situation of this state is such, that many of her citizens, as well as those of her neighboring states, are necessarily compelled to pass and repass through, and sometimes to transact business of great importance in that part of our unlocated territory which is, for the present, assigned to the Indians for their hunting groundand whereas several crimes of the most aggravating nature, as well as others against the peace and good order of society, have been, and may in future be committed against our good citizens; and as one of the primary objects of government is, that the parties composing it shall be protected in their persons and property, and as our Judiciary is deprived of doing either the one or the other, from the want of jurisdiction, which jurisdiction can only be given (agreeable to our constitution) by adding the same to some one of the counties of the state;</p><p> 1. BE <i>it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted,</i> That all the unlocated territory which lies within the present chartered limits of this

<page id="GA1814.1.P41" no="GA1814.1.42" />

state, and which is not contained in any of the present counties of this state, but which is reserved to the Indians, (by existing treaty) for their hunting ground, be and the same is hereby added to, and shall become a part of the county of Jasper<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That nothing in this act contained, shall be so construed as to justify any Surveyor in locating any warrant, or any person in obtaining any grant, or any right or privilege whatever, other than he, she or they had previous to the passing of this act, for any part of the aforesaid territory. And all surveys made, or grants issued for any part of the same, shall be null and void, to all intents and purposesand the parties making such survey or surveys, or obtaining any such grant or grants, shall be subject to all the penalties which are prescribed by the fifth section of an act, entitled an act, to amend some and repeal other parts of the several land acts of this state, passed on the 22d day of February, 1785, for preventing persons from making surveys or obtaining grants for any lands lying or being without the limits of the counties then defined<i>And provided also,</i> That in all cases of prosecution or imprisonment for criminal acts in said unlocated territory, the expense of the prosecution and imprisonment shall be paid by the state, in case it cannot be recovered from the criminal or his property.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N028" initial.page="42"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To authovise the Inferior Court of the county of Burke to sell the Glebe land of the said county, and for other purposes.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Inferior Court of the county of Burke be, and they are hereby authorised and empowered to sell and dispose of the Glebe lands of the said county, for the benefit of the Waynesborough

<page id="GA1814.1.P42" no="GA1814.1.43" />

Academy, upon such terms, as in the opinion of the Inferior court, will best promote the interest of the said Academyand the money arising from the said sale, to be, by the said Inferior Court, paid over to the trustees or commissioners of said Academy.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the commissioners or trustees of the Waynesborough Academy, be, and they are hereby authorised to sell and dispose of a tract of Land in Camden county, containing four hundred acres, conveyed to the said commissioners by the commissioners of confiscated property, and the money arising from said sale to be applied to the use of said Academy.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President ef the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N029" initial.page="43"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To authorise the Commissioners of the towns of Brunswick and Frederica to collect a tax upon the lots of the same, to re-build a Court House and Goal in the county of Glynn.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met, and by authority of the same,</i> That the Commissioners of the towns of Brunswick and Frederica, be, and they are hereby authorised to lay a tax upon the lots of said towns, whether improved or otherwise, and that the monies so collected be paid over to the Justices of the Inferior Court of the county of Glynn, to, and for the purpose of erecting a Court House and Goal in the said county.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said Commissioners, or a majority of them, in the event of said tax not being paid, have power to issue execution, which shall be levied on the aforesaid lots, after the usual advertisement of the same, unless the tax is paid, the lots shall be sold to satisfy the tax.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P43" no="GA1814.1.44" />

<p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all acts militating against this act be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N030" initial.page="44"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To create the office of Division Inspector, Division Quarter Master, Brigade Quarter Master, and Aid de Camp to Brigadier Generals, agreeably to an act of Congress passed</i> 18<i>th April,</i> 1814.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That there shall be to each Division, one Division Inspector, with the rank of Lieut. Col. and one Division Quarter Master, with the rank of Major; one Brigade Quarter Master, with the rank of Captain; and to each Brigadier General, one Aid de Camp, with the rank of Captain.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the Division Inspectors and Division Quarter Masters, shall be appointed by the Major Generals; and the Brigade Aid de Camp and Quarter Master, shall be appointed by the Brigadier Generals.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all laws and parts of laws militating against this law, shall be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P44" no="GA1814.1.45" />

<law id="L1814V1N031" initial.page="45"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>Authorising Captain Thomas H. Miller of Camden county, to establish a Ferry across the North River, and to throw up a Causeway through the adjoining marsh.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS it is of great importance to shorten the distance of communication between the fortifications at Point Peter and the city of St. Marys,</p><p> 1. THEREFORE <i>be it enacted by the Senate  House of Representatives of the state of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That Captain Thomas H. Miller be, and he is hereby authorised to establish a Ferry across the North river, opposite to his house, and he is also authorised to throw up a Causeway from the said Ferry through the marsh, to the high land on each side of the said river.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That to remunerate the said Captain Thomas H. Miller for making the aforesaid Causeway and keeping the Ferry, he is hereby authorised to demand and receive the following tollfor every footman, twelve and a half centsfor every man and horse, twenty five cents.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N032" initial.page="45"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>For the relief of the heirs and representatives of John Kennon, deceased.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of [Illegible Text] in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior Court of the counties of Putnam and Baldwin, are hereby authorised to release the heirs of John Kennon, from all the penalties of a bond given by him, during his life time, for the building and keeping in repair

<page id="GA1814.1.P45" no="GA1814.1.46" />

a bridge across Little river, at Mullin's ford, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N033" initial.page="46"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To move the scite of the public buildings in the county of Bryan, and for other purposes therein mentioned.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the Court House and scite of the public buildings in the county of Bryan is not central, by many miles, and to the great inconvenience to the inhabitants thereof,</p><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted therefore by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That the Court House and Jail be erected on the new scite, which shall be either central at, or near Mansford, on Canouchee river, as convemence will admit of.</p><p> 2. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That Godhilf Smith, Henry Shurman, James Martin, Zachariah Wells and Luke Man be, and they are hereby appointed commissioners, who, (or a majority of them) shall have power and authority to fix on the new scite of the public buildings for the county of Bryan, and to purchase in behalf of said county, a lot or tract of land, which shall contain two acres, on which the public buildings of the county of Bryan shall be erected.</p><p> 3. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That the commissioners are hereby also authorised to expose to sale, at public outcry, giving at least thirty days notice, in three of the most public places in the county, the old Court House, Jail and all the lot of land attached to said buildings, as the old scitewhich money shall be applied to the erecting the new Court House, on the new scite.</p><p> 4. <i>Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if on trial, the old Court House will not sell for its value, in that case the commissioners may either contract

<page id="GA1814.1.P46" no="GA1814.1.47" />

for the removal of the old one, or the building of a new one, on the new scite, to the lowest bidder, taking bond for the faithful performance of the work, from the undertaker, giving at least thirty days notice in three of the most public places in the county, and the commissioners shall adjudge of the value of the old buildings, and may bid in behalf of the county, to prevent the Court House selling under its value.</p><p> 5. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That it shall be the duty of the Justices of the Inferior Court to aid in facilitating the erection of the new Court House, and that they shall lay the extra tax allowed by law to the county of Bryan annually, until the Court House is fit for the reception of Courts, c. and that the Justices of the Inferior Courts shall pay over to the aforesaid commissioners, all the money from the county fund that may be now in hand, or that may be by extra tax or otherwise hereafter, that can be spared until the new Court House is fit for use.</p><p> 6. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That during the vacation of the Court House in said county, by sale or otherwise, that Courts, Elections, c. be held at the house occupied by Mr. Lamb, or any other house that may be procured by the commissioners aforesaid.</p><p> 7. <i>Be it further enacted,</i> That all laws or parts of laws militating against this law, or any part thereof, are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N034" initial.page="47"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To divorce and seperate John M. Jamison and Polly his wife.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act, the matrimonial connection, or civil contract of marriage

<page id="GA1814.1.P47" no="GA1814.1.48" />

made between John M. Jamison and Polly his wife, late Polly Grinage, shall be completely annulled, set aside and dissolved, as fully and effectually as if no such contract had been heretofore made and entered into between them.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the said John M. Jamison and Polly Jamison, late Polly Grinage, shall in future be held as separate and distinct persons, altogether unconnected by any mystical union or civil contract whatsoever, at any time heretofore made or entered into by them.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N035" initial.page="48"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To establish and regulate the Inspection of Flour.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS experience has shewn, that the establishment of Flour Inspections, under proper regulations, will advance and promote the interest of this state,</p><p> 1. BE <i>it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That there shall be a Flour Inspection established in the town of Petersburg, and cities of Augusta and Savannah.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the Inferior Courts in the several counties aforesaid, at the first term of said Courts after the passing of this act,  biennially thereafter, shall appoint one person, of good repute, and a skilful judge of the quality of flour, to be Inspector of Flour, at the before mentioned placesthat is to say, the Inferior Court of the county of Elbert shall appoint one Inspector for the town of Petersburg; the Inferior Court for the county of Richmond one Inspector for the city of Augusta; and the Inferior Court of Chatham county, one for the city of Savannah.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i>

<page id="GA1814.1.P48" no="GA1814.1.49" />

That in case of the death of any person so appointed, or in the event of his refusing or neglecting to act, the Justices of the Inferior Court of said county shall, as soon as conveniently may be thereafter, meet and appoint some other suitable person to fill such vacancy, who shall execute the duties of Inspector until the succeeding electionand if the Inferior Court shall neglect to make appointments, it shall and may be lawful for the city council or corporation of the before mentioned counties to appoint an Inspector.</p><p> 4. <i>Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all bolted wheat flour and every cask thereof, brought to the places before mentioned for sale or exportation, shall be made by the miller or manufacturer thereof merchantable, and of due fineness, and without mixture of coarser flour, or the flour of any other grain than wheat.</p><p> 5. <i>Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all flour barrels, packed with flour, brought to the before mentioned places for sale or exportation, shall be well made, and of good materials, twenty seven inches in length, tightened with at least ten hoops and sufficiently nailed, with the tare plainly marked on the head thereof; and every miller or bolter shall put into a barrel the full quantity of one hundred and ninety six pounds of flour, and shall put into every half barrel the full quantity of ninety eight pounds of flour; and on failure thereof, shall forfeit and pay the sum of four dollars, to be recovered by any informer before any Justice having jurisdiction thereofone half of which shall belong to the informer and the other half to the county.</p><p> 6. <i>Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all barrels or casks of flour brought to the places aforesaid for exportation, shall be submitted to the view and examination of the Inspector who shall expeditiously inspect the same by boring into the barrel from head to head with an instrument of not more than three quarters of an inch in diameter, to be by him provided for that purpose, and if he shall judge the same well packed and merchantable according to the directions of this act, he shall plug up the hole and brand the barrel with the name of the place at which he shall be inspector with a public brand mark, to be by him provided for that purpose, and approved of by the Inferior Court, City Council or Corporation, as the case may beand shall also mark the degree of fineness which

<page id="GA1814.1.P49" no="GA1814.1.50" />

he shall determine the flour to be on inspection, which degree shall be distinguished as followssuperfine, fine, middling and ship stuff; for which trouble the Inspector shall have and receive from the owner six an a quarter cents per barrel.</p><p> 7. <i>Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if any person or persons shall pack flour in old barrels which have been marked and branded agreeably to this act, and which shall still have the brand of the Inspector thereon, such person or persons shall forfeit and pay the sum of twenty dollars, to be recovered by any imformer before any Justice of the Peace having jurisdiction thereof, one half of which shall belong to the informer and the other half to the miller or manufacturer who has been injured by such false packing.</p><p> 8. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That it shall not be lawful for any Inspector directly or indirectly to purchase any flour by him condemned as unmerchantable or any other flour whatever, other than for his own and family use and consumption, under the penalty of thirty dollars for every barrel by him purchased, to be recovered upon information by any informer, before any Justice of the Peace having jurisdiction thereofone half of which shall belong to the informer and the other half to the county.</p><p> 9. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That if any person shall export from the place aforesaid, any flour without inspection as aforesaid, he, she or they shall forfeit and pay the sum of ten dollars for each barrel of flour so exported, to be recovered upon information by any informer before any Justice of the Peace having jurisdiction thereofone half of which shall belong to the informer and the other half to the Inspector.</p><p> 10. <i>Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That every Inspector before he enters on the duties of his office shall take and subscribe the following oath, to wit; I A B do solemnly swear (or affirm as the case may be) that I will well and truly inspect all flour brought to me for inspection, that I will faithfully brand and mark the barrels as directed by this act, so help me God.</p><p> 11. <i>Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the said Inspectors shall be liable to indictment for

<page id="GA1814.1.P50" no="GA1814.1.51" />

any neglect of duty, and upon conviction thereof, shall forfeit and pay a sum not less than thirty dollars.</p><p> 12. <i>Be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That it shall not be lawful for any owner or patroon of any boat in the city of Augusta to receive on board his or their boat any barrel of flour to be carried to Savannah, that shall not have been inspected, marked and branded as aforesaid; and any owner or patroon aforesaid, who shall violate this law, shall be liable to an indictment, and upon conviction thereof, shall be fined in a sum not exceeding one hundred dollars.</p><p> 13. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That this law shall go into operation from and after the expiration of six months from the passing thereof, and not before.</p><p> 14. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all laws and parts of laws militating against this act, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N036" initial.page="51"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To authorise the Justices of the Inferior Court of Baldwin county to levy an extra tax.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior Court of the county of Baldwm be, and they are hereby authorised to levy an extra tax on the inhabitants of said county, which shall not exceed one fourth part of the general tax for the purpose of defraying the expense of building the Court House in said county.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said extra tax shall be collected by the tax collector of said county for the

<page id="GA1814.1.P51" no="GA1814.1.52" />

time being, whose duty it shall be to pay over the same to the Inferior Court thereof, to be appropriated by them for the purpose aforesaid, after deducting the usual per centum for collection.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N037" initial.page="52"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>T<i>o amend an act, entitled an act to establish the fees of the Harbor Master  Health Officer of the ports of Savannah and St. Marys, passed the</i> 12<i>th December,</i> 1804.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the expiration of the term for which the present incumbents have been elected, the Health Officer of the Ports of Savannah and St. Marys shall not be entitled to have or receive any fees whatsoever, of or from any American vessel arriving at the said ports of Savannah or St. Marys in any case where such vessel shall have sailed or departed from any port or place within the limits of the state of Georgia.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That it shall not be necessary for the Health Officer to visit any vessel arriving at the port of Savannah from any port or place within the limits of this state.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That all acts and parts of acts militating against this law be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P52" no="GA1814.1.53" />

<law id="L1814V1N038" initial.page="53"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To make valid a transcribed copy of the records of the register of [Illegible Text] of Columbia county, and to confirm the same in courts of record.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS by an order of the Honorable the Court of Ordinary of the county aforesaid, they have had the same fairly transcribed into a bound book, and have received it as such;</p><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the aforesaid transcribed copy be, and the same is hereby confirmed as the lawful record of the Court of Ordinary of Columbia county.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said duplicate records shall be considered by the officers of courts as original records, and shall be received as such in all or any court of record, nor shall they, or any of them be barred in evidence by the courts of record throughout this state, any thing to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said court shall be, and they are hereby authorised to defray the expences of transcribing the said records.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N039" initial.page="53"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To amend an act, to make permanent the scite of the public buildings of Telfair county.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act, the place for building the Court House and Jail for the county of Telfair shall be on part of lot number three hundred and forty, in the eighth district of Wilkinson now Telfair county.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P53" no="GA1814.1.54" />

<p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior Court, or a majority of them shall have power to lay off any number of lots they may deem necessary, and proceed to sell the same, by giving at least thirty days notice in one of the public Gazettes of the Ocmulgee circuit and at three of the public places in said county, for the purpose of building a Court House and Jail for said county.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, all courts and elections which are required to be held at the Court House, shall be held at the place appointed as aforesaid, and all laws and parts of laws militating against this be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLR, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N040" initial.page="54"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To amend an act, entitled an act to make permanent the scite of the public buildings in Morgan county, at the town of Madison, and to incorporate the same, passed the</i> 12<i>th December,</i> 1809.</fulltitle><p>WHEREAS in the second section of the before recited act, that the first Monday in March annually, is set apart for holding the election for commissioners of the said townAND WHEREAS the citizens of said place failed to elect commissioners as contemplated by said actfor remedy whereof,</p><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That from  immediately after the passing of this act, that Samuel Shields, Roderick Leonard, Alston H. Greene, Samuel B. Hutchinson and Lancelott Johnston be, and they are appointed commissioners of the town of Madison, to continue in office until the first Monday in March next, invested with the same powers as if they had been elected agreeable to the provisions of the before recited act.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P54" no="GA1814.1.55" />

<p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That when any vacancy shall happen by death, resignation or otherwise of any one or more of the commissioners now appointed, or that may hereafter be elected agreeable to the act, to which this act is amendatory, that the then acting commissioners, or a majority of them shall give at least ten days previous notice by advertisement at the door of the Court House of such vacancy, and proceed to hold an election agreeably to such notice, which election shall be superintended by one Justice of the Peace of said county with a majority of the then acting commissioners; and the person or persons, as the case may be, having the highest number of votes, shall be considered qualified to act until the first Monday in March thereafter<i>Provided,</i> That the electors shall possess such qualifications as are required by the act to which this is amendatory.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N041" initial.page="55"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>For the relief of Charles Smith of Wilkes county.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS Charles Smith of Wilkes County became the security of John Darracott for the collection of Wilkes county tax for the year eighteen hundred and sevenAND WHEREAS the Grand Juries of said county for the January and June terms of the year eighteen hundred and fourteen, and a number of respectable citizens of said county have petitioned the Legislature to release the said Charles from the force and effect of the said bond, and the said Charles having presented his petition for that purposeAND WHEREAS the said matter exclusively concerns the said county of Wilkes;</p><p> 1. BE <i>it therefore enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior Court of Wilkes

<page id="GA1814.1.P55" no="GA1814.1.56" />

county be, and they are hereby authorised to release Charles Smith security for John Darracott, collector of the county tax of said county, from the tenour of his bond<i>Provided</i> they in their discretion think proper.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 3d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N042" initial.page="56"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To authorise the Board of Directors of the Planters Bank of the state of Georgia and its officers, to remove from the city of Savannah and transact business in any part of the state of Georgia, under certain circumstances therein mentioned.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the Board of Directors of the Planters Bank of the state of Georgia and its officers, are hereby authorised to remove from the city of Savannah, for such time as they may think proper, and transact business in any part of the state of Georgia, whenever the President and Directors, or a majority of the members thereof who may be present, shall think it prudent, from causes of alarm, which in their opinion may endanger the safety of the institution, or in cases of contagion affecting the city, or the vicinity thereof: and all the business of the said Bank which may be transacted after such removal as is authorised by this act, shall be equally binding and legal as if the same had been done and transacted in the city of Savannah.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 3d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P56" no="GA1814.1.57" />

<law id="L1814V1N043" initial.page="57"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To explain certain parts of an act, entitled an act to quiet and confirm the titles of persons who have purchased lots from and under the Commissioners of the town or Academy of Waynesborough, in the county of Burke, and for other purposespassed at Milledgeville 6th December,</i> 1813.</fulltitle><p>1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That nothing contained in the before recited act, or in the provisos to the 1st and 2d sections thereof was intended in the slightest manner to impair the title of the commissioners of the town of Waynesborough or the trustees of the Waynesborough Academy, to any lot or parcel of land not previously conveyed by them, embraced within the Waynesboro' township line, as laid out by the Commissioners under and by virtue of an act, entitled an act for laying out the reserved land in the town of Augusta into acre lots, the erecting of an Academy or seminary of learning, and for other purposes therein mentioned, passed at Augusta the 31st July, 1783But it was intended to leave all disputes between said Commissioners or trustees and other persons in relation to the said land, or any part of it, upon the same footing that they were prior to the passing the act of which this is explanatory.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N044" initial.page="57"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To explain the tenth section of an act, entitled an act for the more full and complete establishment of a public seat of learning in this state, passed the 27th day of January,</i> 1785.</fulltitle><p> [Illegible Text] BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i>

<page id="GA1814.1.P57" no="GA1814.1.58" />

<i>and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act that all persons who are now or who may hereafter become students at the University of this State, or within ten days after their arrival, shall be held and considered liable to do militia duty in the same manner as other persons from eighteen to forty-five years of age are.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That so much of the before recited act as militates against this act is [Illegible Text] repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate,</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 16th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N045" initial.page="58"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To repeal that part of the third section as relates to Clerks and Sheriffs, entitled an act to authorise the Justices of the Inferior Court in the county of Bryan, to levy a county tax not exceeding one third of the general tax, and to authorise the said Court to collect the monies arising from the rents of the [Illegible Text] lands in said county, and to appropriate the same to the defraying county purposes, passed the fourth day of December in the year one thousand eight hundred and five.</i></fulltitle><p>WHEREAS the Justices of the Inferior Court in the county of Bryan are authorised by the above recited act to pay monies to the Clerks and Sheriffs in said county in order that they may accept and hold their offices to the injury of the inhabitants, for remedy whereof,</p><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That so much of the above recited act as relates to the Clerks and Sheriffs be and the same is hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P58" no="GA1814.1.59" />

<law id="L1814V1N046" initial.page="59"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To alter and amend an act passed he [Illegible Text] December,</i> 1813, <i>for the regulation and government of the [Illegible Text] and commons of [Illegible Text] and Frederica in the county of Glynn.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That John Burnett, Sen. Leighton Wilson, Wm. Page, Henry Dubignon, Gee [Illegible Text] Wm. Huston, and James May, be and they are hereby appointed Commissioners for the towns and commons of [Illegible Text] and [Illegible Text] in the county of Glynn.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the above named Commissioners [Illegible Text] the towns and commons of [Illegible Text] and Frederica be, and the same are hereby nominated and appointed commissioners of the academy of said county of Glynn, and are fully authorised as such to sue and to be sued, and to do and perform all acts and things that may be necessary to recover such monies as may be due for rents or otherwise to the former commissioners of the aforesaid towns and commons; and they are hereby authorised to elect one of their board as a Treasurer, who shall give such security for the faithful performance of his duty, and to account for all monies which may come into his hands, as the said commissioners or a majority of them may require.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That one fourth of the future rents of said commons shall be appropriated to the building the Court-house and Jail of said county of Glynn, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all former laws appointing commissioners for the purpose aforesaid, and all laws and parts of laws militating against the provisions of this act, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P59" no="GA1814.1.60" />

<law id="L1814V1N047" initial.page="60"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To repeal so much of the 5th section of an act entitled an act to alter and amend the several Judiciary acts now in force in this state, so far as relates to Justices Courts, as requires persons claiming property under execution not a party to such execution to take an oath, and to prescribe the oath to be taken in such cases.</i></fulltitle><p>BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That so much of the fifth section of the above recited act, as requires persons claiming property under execution, not a party to such execution to make [Illegible Text] that such property is not liable to such execution, be and the same is hereby repealed. And that in all cases of executions from any Justices Courts in this state, levied on property claimed by any person not a party to such execution, such person shall make oath that the property levied on is his, her or their right and property, or his, her or their property as attorney, agent, guardian, executor or administrator, as the case may be, to the best of his, her or their knowledge and belief, and shall moreover give security in terms of the said 5th section.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives,</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N048" initial.page="60"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To amend an act, entitled an act, to authorise the fortunate drawers in the late land lotteries of this state to take out their grants until the</i> 10<i>th day of November,</i> 1814, <i>and after that day to authorise any citizen of this state to take out grants in said Lotteries, and for other purposes therein mentioned.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That after the said tenth day of November, any person or persons citizens of this

<page id="GA1814.1.P60" no="GA1814.1.61" />

state, who shall apply at the necessary offices may, on payment of one hundred dollars each, including the usual fees, take out  receive in his, her or their own name or names, a grant or grants, for any lot or lots of land in either of the land lotteries of this state, which shall not be then granted.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the first day of January next, it shall and may be [Illegible Text] for any person or persons, citizens of this state, who shall apply at the necessary offices, on payment of fifty dollars each, including the usual fees, to take out and receive in his, her or their own name or names, a grant or grants for any lot or lots of land in either of the land lotteries of this state, which shall not be then granted.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the first day of March next, it shall and may be lawful for any person or persons, citizens of this state, who shall apply at the necessary offices, on payment of twenty-five dollars each, including the usual fees, to take out and receive in his, her or their own name or names, a grant or grants for any lot or lots of land in either of the land lotteries of this state, which shall not be then granted.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the first day of May next, it shall and may be lawful for any person or persons, citizens of [Illegible Text] state, who shall apply at the necessary offices, on payment of the usual fees for taking out grants in the late land lotteries of this state, to take out in his, her or their own name or names, a grant or grants for land in either of the land lotteries in this state, which shall not be then granted.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That no person or persons shall be authorised to take out a grant for any lot drawn by, or for any orphan or orphans, who may not have been of age for the term of one year at the time of taking out such grant or grants; or who have no legal representative in this state.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all acts or parts of acts militating against this act shall be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 5th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P61" no="GA1814.1.62" />

<law id="L1814V1N049" initial.page="62"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>To appropriate a sum of money for the purpose of fortifying the city of Savannah, the city of St. Mary's and the several inlets situated between the said cities.</i></fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That a sum not exceeding forty-five thousand dollars be and the same is hereby appropriated to and for the purpose of purchasing the raw materials necessary for the defence and fortification of the city of Savannah, and for the purchase of the necessary munitions of war, and not by any means for the hire of laborers, in which sum shall be included the amount heretofore advanced by His Excellency the Governor for a like purpose. And that a further sum not exceeding ten thousand dollars be and the same is hereby appropriated to and for the purpose of purchasing the raw materials necessary for the defence and fortification of the city of St. Mary's, and for the purchase of the necessary munitions of war, and not by any means for the hire of laborers. And that the further sum of one thousand dollars each be and the same is hereby appropriated to and for the purpose of erecting a Block-House at the North end of little Cumberland Island, one at the South end of St. Simons, one at the South end of Sappelo, one at the North end of Black-beard, one at the North end of St. Catharine's, one at the North end of Ossaban, and one at the South end of Wilmington Islands.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be and he is hereby authorised to draw out of the Treasury of this State from any monies not otherwise appropriated, the said several sums of money aforesaid, and apply the same in the proportions and to the purposes aforesaid.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the following persons be and they are hereby appointed Commissioners to receive and apply the several sums herein appropriated to the several purposes above stated, vizfor the city of Savannah and county of Chatham, Messrs. Joseph Habersham, Charles Harris, George Jones, James Johnston and John Bolton, or a majority of them; for the city of Saint Mary's, Messrs. William Scott, Charles

<page id="GA1814.1.P62" no="GA1814.1.63" />

Floyd, John Hardy, William Gibson and David Lewis; for the county of Bryan, Col. John Pray, Major Lee Blacksil and George M. Waters; for the county [Illegible Text] Liberty, Gen. D. Stewart, John Stevens, William Fleming, John Elliott and Joseph Law; for the county of [Illegible Text], Major Francis Hopkins, James Nephew and Thomas Spalding; and for the county of Glynn, Major William Page, John Cooper and Leighton Wilson; and that the several sums, in the proportions and for the purposes contemplated in this law, be drawn for by warrant on the Treasury by his Excellency the Governor in their favor, so soon as they shall have given bond and security for the faithful performance of their duty in applying the same for the purposes contemplated by this law; and on receiving the same shall render half yearly a just and true account of the expenditure of the same to his Excellency the Governor for the time being<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> that in case any of the Commissioners herein named, shall refuse to accept, or comply with the requisitions herein contained, his Excellency the Governor is hereby authorised and required to appoint other fit and proper persons in their stead under like restrictions.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That his Excellency the Governor shall be and he is hereby authorised to effect a loan of what money he may deem advisable for the purposes aforesaid, in the event of there being a deficiency in the Treasury.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>JARED IRWIN,</p><p>President of the Senate, <i>pro tem.</i></p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 9th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1814V1N050" initial.page="63"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle><i>Supplementary to and amendatory of an act entitled, an act to amend an act entitled, an act to authorise the fortunate drawers in the land lotteries in this state to take out their grants until the</i> 10<i>th day of November,</i> 1814, <i>and after that day to authorise any citizen of this state to take out grants in said lotteries, and for other purposes therein mentioned, passed on the 5th day of November,</i> 1814.</fulltitle><p> 1. BE <i>it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives</i>

<page id="GA1814.1.P63" no="GA1814.1.64" />

<i>of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same,</i> That the fortunate drawers in the late land lotteries of this state be and they are hereby authorised, on payment of the usual fees, to take out their grants until the first day of April next.</p><p> 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That after the said first day of April next, any person or persons, citizens of this state, who shall apply at the necessary offices, may take out and receive in his, her or their own name or names, a grant or grants for any lot or lots of land in either of the land lotteries of this state which shall not then be granted, on payment of one hundred dollars on each grant, including the usual fees.</p><p> 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the first day of June next, it shall and may be lawful for any person or persons citizens of this state, who shall apply at the necessary offices to take out and receive in his, her or their own name or names, a grant or grants for any lot or lots of land in either of the land lotteries of this state, which shall not then be granted, on payment of fifty dollars on each grant including the usual fees.</p><p> 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the first day of August next, it shall and may be lawful for any person or persons citizens of this state, who shall apply at the necessary offices to take out and receive in his, her or their own name or names, a grant or grants for any lot or lots of land in either of the land lotteries of this state, which shall not then be granted, on payment of twenty-five dollars on each grant, including the usual fees.</p><p> 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That from and after the first day of October next, it shall and may be lawful for any person or persons, citizens of this state, who shall apply at the necessary offices, to take out and receive in his, her or their own name or names, a grant or grants for any lot or lots of land in either of the land lotteries of this state, which shall not then be granted, on payment of the usual fees.</p><p> 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That nothing in this act contained, nor the act to which this is amendatory, shall be so construed as to authorize any person or persons to take out any grant or grants in his, her or their own name or names, for any lot or lots of land drawn by or belonging to any orphan or orphans, until the expiration of one year

<page id="GA1814.1.P64" no="GA1814.1.65" />

after such orphan or orphans shall become of lawful age: And all grants issued in the name or names of any person or persons, for any lot or lots of land in either of the land lotteries of this State, drawn by or belonging to any orphan or orphans, until the expiration of one year after such orphan or orphans shall become of lawful age, such grant or grants shall be null and void to all intents and purposes as if such grant or grants had not been issued.</p><p> 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That all orphans or their legal representatives shall be, and they are hereby authorised to take out and receive their grant or grants, on payment of the usual fees, until the expiration of one year after such orphan or orphans shall become of lawful age.</p><p> 8. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That so much of the above recited act as authorises any person or persons, citizens of this State, to take out a grant or grants in the late land lotteries in this state, in his, her or their own name or names at the times therein stipulated, and all other parts of said act, and all other acts or parts of acts militating against this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p>BENJ. WHITAKER,</p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p>WILLIAM RABUN,</p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p>PETER EARLY, Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, 10th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law></part>

<page id="GA1814.1.P65" />

<part><title>RESOLUTIONS<br set="CENTER">WHICH ORIGINATED IN SENATE.<br set="CENTER" /></br></title><law id="R1814V1N051"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 19th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That both branches of the Legislature will convene in the Representative chamber on Monday the 31st inst. in order to elect a Brigadier General, in the place of Brigadier General John Stewart resigned, and a Quarter-Master General in the place of Lieut. Col. George W. Evans, also resigned.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N052"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 20th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the executive appointment of Dr. Joshua E. White, as a Commissioner of the Academy of Chatham county, be and the same is hereby confirmed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N053"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 20th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Edmund B. Jenkins, Esquire, be, and he is hereby appointed a Commissioner of the Penitentiary Edifice in the town of Milledgeville vice Hubert Reynolds, Esquire, deceased.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N054"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 21st October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the Commissioners of the Penitentiary Edifice be, and they are hereby directed to lay before this General Assembly, a statement of the receipts and expenditures up to the present period, together with a statement of the progress of the said edifice.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 31st October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N055" initial.page="68"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 21st October, 1814.</shorttitle><p>WHEREAS this state as well as several of her sister states having, during the present war, taken the earliest opportunity to enrol among the records of fame the illustrious deeds of their gallant naval commanders, and of their officers and seamen; and have in a highly honorable manner, through their Legislative councils, presented their thanks to Capt. Hull, Commodore Decatur, Commodore Bainbridge and to Capt. Perry: And this state, in a particular manner, has

<page id="GA1814.1.P66" no="GA1814.1.68" />

tendered their thanks to Capt. Perry for his glorious victory over a superior British force on Lake Erie;</p><p>And whereas since those memorable exploits have been achieved, a series of deeds [Illegible Text] splendid have been performed by others of our [Illegible Text] heroes, both by land and by sea; and whereas it is both fit and proper that the names and exploits of our gallant sons be recorded and transmitted to a grateful posterity, in order that future generations may emulate their exalted virtues and <i>Fame</i>the only reward a noble mind can ask, for his exertions in the defence of his country's rights and honor</p><p><i>Be it therefore unanimously resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met, on behalf of the people of Georgia,</i> That the thanks of the citizens and of the Legislature of this state are due to Capt. <i>Warrington</i> and to his officers and seamen, for their valor and skill in capturing the Epervier: To Capt. <i>Porter</i> and to his officers and seamen, for their unparalleled perseverance in defence of their country's rights, and for their noble conflict in defence of their ship under every disadvantage against a greatly superior force. To Commodore <i>Macdonough,</i> and to the officers and seamen on board the several vessels under his command, for the capture and destruction of a superior British naval force on Lake ChamplamTo Capt. Blakely of the United States' Sloop Wasp, and through him to the officers and seamen for their gallantry and good conduct in capturing the British Sloop of War Reindeer.</p><p>And whereas the armies of our country have latterly been equally successful and splendid in their victories</p><p><i>Be it therefore unanimously resolved,</i> That the thanks of the citizens and of the Legislature of this state are due to that galaxy of heroes, Gen. Brown, Gen. Scott, Gen. Gaines and Gen. Macomb, for their brilliant victories to the northto the intrepid Gen. Jackson to the South-West; and to Commodore Barney for his gallant conduct at the battle of BladensburghTo that gallant band of Heroes, Generals Porter, Ripley and Miller, for the intrepidity and skill displayed by them in the splendid sortie from Fort Erie on the enemy's batteriesTo the brave and intrepid Major William Lawrence, and through him to his officers and men, for their gallant and successful defence of Fort Bowyer, attacked by a greatly superior force both by land

<page id="GA1814.1.P67" no="GA1814.1.69" />

and waterTo the young Hero, a native of Georgia, Lieut. Col. Appling of the [Illegible Text] corps, for his brilliant and officer-like conduct at the [Illegible Text] of Plattsburgh, as well as for the gallantry displayed by him acting as Major at Sandy creek, in capturing the whole of the enemy's forceAnd to Brigadier Gen. Floyd, Adjutant Gen. Daniel Newman, and to the officers and men who so nobly distinguished themselves at the [Illegible Text] of Autossee and Caulebee. The zeal, patriotism and determined bravery manifested on those occasions by the officers and men from this state, establish a fair claim to military [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text], and justly merit the admiration and [Illegible Text] of a [Illegible Text] people.</p><p><i>Be it further resolved.</i> That his Excellency the Governor be requested to [Illegible Text] these resolutions to Capt. Warrington, Capt. Porter, Commodore Macdonough, Gen. Brown, Gen. Scott, Gen. Gaines, Gen. Jackson, Gen. Macomb and Commodore [Illegible Text]and to Capt. Blakely, Gens. Porter, Ripley and Miller, Major William Lawrence, Lieut. Col. Appling, Gen. Floyd, and Adjutant Gen. Newnan.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 31st October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N056" initial.page="69"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 22d October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the Justices of the Inferior courts of the counties of Columbia and Warren, be, and they are hereby authorised to pay out of the county fands [Illegible Text] Reuben Y. Langston and [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text], each the sum of two dollars and seventy-five cents for every [Illegible Text] that they necessarily run in running the dividing line between the aforesaid counties, agreeable to the certified plat and representation of said line now deposited with the [Illegible Text] of the Inferior court of Columbia county; that Reuben Y. Langston be paid by Columbia county and Pierson Petitt by Warren county; which shall be in full of the claims of the said Langsten and Petitt for running and marking said line, including the hire of chain carriers, choppers, flag-staff men and every other charge for running said line.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 31st October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N057" initial.page="69"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 22d October, 1814.</shorttitle><p>While the Legislature of Georgia, view with the liveliest sensations, the glorious achievements of the American arms <i>generally,</i> they cannot but felicitate themselves <i>particularly</i>

<page id="GA1814.1.P68" no="GA1814.1.70" />

in the recollection of the heroic exploits of the brave and gallant Lieut. Col. Daniel Appling, whom the state is proud to acknowledge her native son, and as a tribute of applause from the state which gave him birtha tribute due to the lustre of his actionsBe it unanimously resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Assembly met, that his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to have purchased and presented to him an elegant sword, suitable for an officer of his grade.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 31st October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N058" initial.page="70"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 25th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The joint committee appointed to contract for the printing of the laws, journals and other public documents, ordered by the present session of the Legislature to be printed, do recommend that the Senate do adopt the following resolution, to wit:</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Messrs. S.  F. Grantland have the public printing of this state at the same price and upon the same terms, c. c. as for the preceding political year.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 31st October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N059" initial.page="70"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 28th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the Senate will convene in the Representative Chamber on Monday next at 12 o'clock, for the purpose of electing a Health officer for the city of Savannah, in the place of Dr. Reuben S. Saffold, deceased; and also, commissioners for the town of Milledgeville, in the room of those who have resigned.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 31st October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N060" initial.page="70"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 28th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Joseph Hutchinson, Esq. be, and he is hereby appointed a trustee of Richmond academy in the place of Robert Cresswell, deceased.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 15th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N061" initial.page="70"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 31st October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That William Wood be, and he is hereby appointed a commissioner of the academy of Elbert county, in the room of John H. Brewer, deceased.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 15th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N062" initial.page="70"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 27th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The committee to whom was referred the petition of Abraham

<page id="GA1814.1.P69" no="GA1814.1.71" />

Borland, having had the same under their consideration, and examined the accompanying documents, are of opinion that the prayer of the petitioner is reasonable and ought to be granted; they therefore recommend the following resolution</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That full satisfaction be entered on the judgments obtained in the superior court of Baldwin county against Abraham Borland on the bonds given by him for fractions numbers 23 and 24 in the fourth district of Wilkinson county, and that a credit of one hundred and twenty-five dollars be entitled on other judgments had in the same court against the said Borland for fractions purchased by him. The said sum being the amount he expended in the prosecution of his suit against Lemuel Wiggins for fraction No. 24<i>Provided nevertheless,</i> that the satisfaction and credit herein authorised shall not be entered until the said Abraham Borland shall have relinquished to His Excellency the Governor, in behalf of this state, all the right, title or claim, which he now has or ever had to the aforesaid fractional surveys of land numbers 23 and 24 in the fourth district Wilkinson county.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 18th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N063" initial.page="71"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 4th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the commissioners of the town of Milledgeville be, and they are hereby authorised to lease to Joseph B. Jones for the term of ten years, ten acres of land on the common of said town, including the buildings and cleared ground now occupied by him for the establishment of a Brewery.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 19th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N064" initial.page="71"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 9th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, that our Senators in Congress be instructed and our Representatives be requested to use their best endeavors to prevail upon Congress to propose to the several states for their adoption, an amendment to the constitution of the United States to reduce the term of service of the Senators in Congress from six to four years.</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That His Excellency the Governor be requested to transmit copies of the foregoing resolution to the Executives

<page id="GA1814.1.P70" no="GA1814.1.72" />

of the different states, with a request that they be laid before the Legislatures of the several states, and also one copy to each member of the Senate and each member of the House of Representatives from this state, in the Congress of the United States.</p><p> This resolution was presented to the Executive on Friday the 18th November, 1814, but was suffered to remain in the Executive five days, so as to become a resolution in terms of the provision of the constitution, without being approved.</p><p>ANTHONY PORTER, Sec'ry.</p><approvaldate /></law><law id="R1814V1N065" initial.page="72"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 11th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives in General Asembly met, and by authority of the same, that it is expedient to authorize his Excellency the Governor to draw out of the Treasury of the state, or take from any monies that may be due to the state from the United States, a sum of money which may be equal to the amount of the direct tax for the state of Georgia, and to settle with the Government of the United States, the amount thereof.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N066" initial.page="72"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 15th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Gen. Thomas Flournoy be, and he is hereby appointed a trustee of the University of Georgia, in place of Stephen Upson, Esquire, resigned.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N067" initial.page="72"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 15th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>Whereas Mordecai Shackleford, Tax Collector of Clark county, was by the expedition conducted by Gen. Floyd, and application since, prevented from closing his collection in time to lay the insolvent list before the Grand Jury of the last term.</p><p>Be it therefore resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and by the authority of the same, that the Treasurer do stay all proceedings against the said Mordecai Shackleford until the tenth day of April next.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N068" initial.page="72"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 17th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>Be it resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives

<page id="GA1814.1.P71" no="GA1814.1.73" />

of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, that whereas [Illegible Text] have been commenced and instituted against Obadiah Echols, Reddick Sims and Francis Flournoy, late defaulting commissioners of this state, or their several bonds and every legal and proper exertion made to recover thereon, failing, and being found impracticableIt is the opinion of this legislature that any further prosecution of said suits will be unavailing, and would be calculated only to involve the state in additional and unnecessary expence.</p><p>Therefore be it resolved, that any further prosecution of the bonds of the said Obadiah Echols, Reddick Sims and Francis Flournoy do cease and be discontinued.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N069" initial.page="73"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 19th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, that the commissioners of the town of Milledgeville be, and they are hereby authorised to lease to Jesse Burson three acres of land on the common of said town, now occupied by him, for the term of seven years, upon such terms as they may deem reasonable and just.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N070" initial.page="73"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 19th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia, that the Treasurer of this state and all other officers employed in collecting money arising from the sale of fractional surveys be, and they are hereby authorised and directed to extend to all soldiers in the service of this state or of the United States, the same indulgence which is by law extended to such soldiers in cases of private contract; and to all other citizens indebted for fractional surveys the same indulgence which an act entitled an act, to authorise the several Courts of Equity in this state to grant remedies in certain cases and to regulate the Courts of Law and Equity in this state, and affording temporary relief to the soldiers whilst in the service of this state or of the United States, and for other purposes gives to citizens in case of private contract, on their complying with the requisitions of the said law.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P72" no="GA1814.1.74" />

<law id="R1814V1N071" initial.page="74"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 23d November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorised and required to cause to be published immediately in the several Gazettes of this state, an act to authorise the several Courts of Law and Equity in this state to grant remedies in certain cases and to regulate the Courts of Law and Equity in this state, and for affording temporary relief to the soldiers whilst in the service of this state or of the United States, and for other purposes.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N072" initial.page="74"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 4th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The committee to whom was referred the petition of Reuben WilkinsonReport, that they have with some pains investigated the subject matter of said petitioner, and find that Gen. Thomas Glascock in the year 1794 petitioned the General Assembly of this statealiedging, that he had purchased from the public a tract of land for the quantity of one thousand acres, which on a resurvey was found to contain only six hundred and ninety acres, and prayed relief in the premises, which prayer was thought reasonable and a resolution predicated on said petition passed, reccommending relief commensurate with the injury; but the sum thus recommended, not being put into the appropriation act, the same was not paid. That in the year 1797, the said Thomas Glascock again petitioned and prayed relief, which was granted, and a settlement in conformity therewith was made with the TreasurerIn consequence of which premises, the surplus of the 1000 acres, if to be found, became reverted in the state of Georgia.</p><p>The petitioner Reuben Wilkinson having stated in his petition that he knows the land in question, and that the same may be found, and praying that an opportunity may be afforded him in common with others, of purchasing the same, your committee recommend the following resolution</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the Sheriff of Scriven county be directed to advertise and sell to the highest bidder for cash or liquidated demands against the state at the Court-house of Scriven county, the said tract of three hundred and ten acres of land, the reverted surplus of the thousand acres so sold as aforesaid to the said Thomas Glascock, giving thirty days notice of the time of making such sale; and that the amount

<page id="GA1814.1.P73" no="GA1814.1.75" />

arising from the sale of said land be by said Sheriff deposited in the Treasury of this state.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N073" initial.page="75"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 18th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The joint committee on finance to whom was referred the Treasurer's statement of the Treasury up to the 6th November, 1814, inclusive, begleave to</p><p><i>Report,</i> That they have examined the several items therein countained, with the books, cash, c. in the Treasury, and find the same to agree with the statement in every particular.</p><p>They have had under their consideration the items in the Treasurer's statement, denominated bonds and notes, and find from enquiry of the Treasurer that some of the bonds are, or will be open to immediate collection while others for the want of directions from the Legislature, in this particular, will remain in the Treasury unacted upon; in order therefore to put all persons indebted to the state, by bonds or notes on the same footing, they recommend the following resolution</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor cause such measures to be adopted as will ensure as speedy as may be, the collection of the bonds in the Treasury office, given for Milledgeville lots, the notes given for the rent of fractions and for the rent of the twenty acre lots on the Milledgeville common, and such other bonds and notes as may be in the Treasury, and not heretofore required to be put in suit.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N074" initial.page="75"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 18th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The joint committee on Finance to whom was referred the report of the Solicitors of the Eastern and Western Districts, relative to confiscated property, beg leave to report, that they received from the Commissioners, William Robertson and Hines Holt, four mortgages, one given by Abraham Jones, one by James Montford, one by Sheftall Sheftall; and the fourth by Roger P. Sanders that there appears to be a deficiency of several mortgages, of which they have received no information, and they further report that they deem it expedient that measures should be taken as early as possible by the Attorney and Solicitors Generals to ensure the collection of the sums due by mortgages and bonds

<page id="GA1814.1.P74" no="GA1814.1.76" />

for confiscated property; we therefore recommend the following resolution</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor, be requested to instruct the Attorney and Solicitors Generals of this state to take the most speedy and effectual measures to ensure the collection and payment into the Treasury all the monies due for confiscated and reverted property.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N075" initial.page="76"><shorttitle><i>In Senate,</i> 18th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>WHEREAS public opinion must essentially influence the conduct of those who are called to the administration of a Republican Government, and in the prosecution of a war, the measures of the administration may be accelerated or retarded by the application of this momentum.</p><p>And whereas the recent advices from our Ministers Plenipotentiary at Ghent, have apprised us of the insolent and insulting pretensions of the cabinet of Britain; pretensions incompatible with the most essential rights of this Government, and which have excited feelings of indignation in every patriotic bosom against our proud and insolent foe</p><p>And whereas public policy demands that the government of the United States should be encouraged by the expressions of the sentiments in the prosecution of a war, rendered necessary by the endearing recollection of its being prosecuted in defence of our wives, our children, our sacred honor and the independence of our beloved country:</p><p>Be it therefore resolved unanimously by the General Assembly of the state of Georgia, that the terms and conditions proposed by the British ministers at Ghent to the ministers Plenipotentiary on the part of the United Statesas the <i>sine qua non</i> upon which a treaty of peace may be concluded are not only incompatible with the essential rights of the American Republic, and therefore inadmissible, but are in the highest degree insulting to the American character; and whilst the members of this Legislature deprecate the horrors of war, and would rejoice that its clouds should be dispelled by the cheering rays of an honorable peacethey take pleasure in the expression of the opinion that this portion of the American people will cheerfully breast the storm of war, rather than purchase the return of peace by the sacrifice of those rights which every independent American must hold dear.</p>

<page id="GA1814.1.P75" no="GA1814.1.77" />

<p>And be it further unanimously resolved, that to make peace upon the terms proposed would be to compromit the dignity and the honor of the republic, to sacrifice the most important rights of the nation, and jeopardize her independence. The Legislature therefore respectfully recommend to the General Government a vigorous prosecution of the war, as the only means of humbling the pride of the enemy, producing an honorable peace, and transmitting to posterity, unimpaired, the blessings of freedom and independence.</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor, transmit a copy of these Resolutions to the President of the United States.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 23d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law></part>

<page id="GA1814.1.P76" />

<part><title>RESOLUTIONS<br set="CENTER">WHICH ORIGINATED IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES.<br set="CENTER" /></br></title><law id="R1814V1N076"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Friday, 21st October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Thomas Dawson, Esquire be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Greene, for the year 1815.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N077"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Monday, 24th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Charles Howard be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Chatham.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N078"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Friday, 21st October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Issac Crews, Esquire, be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Camden.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N079"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Friday, 21st October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Thomas W. Grimes be, and he is hereby appointed Vendue Master for the town of Greensborough in the county of Greene, for the year 1815.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N080"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Friday, 21st October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That James Langley be, and he is hereby appointed Vendue Master for the town of Eatonton and county of Putnam for the year, 1815.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N081"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Friday, 21st October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Robert Sallet and Scott Cray be, and they are hereby appointed Vendue Masters for the town of Darien and the county of M'Intosh, for the year 1815.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1814.1.P77" no="GA1814.1.79" />

<law id="R1814V1N082" initial.page="79"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, 20th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Thomas Barret, Fraser and Campbell be, and they are hereby appointed Vendue Masters for the city of Augusta, for the year 1815.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N083" initial.page="79"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Monday, 24th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Scott Cray be, and he is hereby appointed Lumber Measurer for the town of Darien.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N084" initial.page="79"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, 20th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the Executive appointment of Robert R. Reed, Esquire, as a trustee of the Richmond Academy be, and the same is hereby confirmed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N085" initial.page="79"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Monday, 24th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the Executive appointments of Michael Shelman and William N. Harman as Commissioners of the Louisville academy, (the former in the room of Abner Hammond, removed, and the latter in the room of Walter Robinson, deceased) be, and the same are hereby confirmed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 28th October, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N086" initial.page="79"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Saturday, 29th October, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That William Harris be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Madison.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 9th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N087" initial.page="79"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Saturday, 5th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That James Watson be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public in and for the county of Glynn.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 15th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N088" initial.page="79"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives.</i> Thursday, 3d November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That John H. Pope be, and he is hereby appointed

<page id="GA1814.1.P78" no="GA1814.1.80" />

a commissioner of the academy and town of Washington in the place of Thomas Terrell, resigned.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 15th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N089" initial.page="80"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Monday, 7th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The joint committee on Finance, to whom was referred the petition of John M. Patrick, beg leave to recommend the following resolutionResolved, that the prayer of the petitioner is reasonable and ought to be granted, and that the sum of eighty dollars be allowed the said John M. Patrick.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 15th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N090" initial.page="80"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, 10th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorised to negotiate a loan with the banks of this state, or either of them, for a sum of twenty thousand dollars, and that the same be advanced by him to the Quarter Master's Department on account of the United States, as a temporary aid to enable the detachment of militia destined for the South West to march without delay.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 15th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N091" initial.page="80"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Wednesday, 2d November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved unanimously,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to procure a sword suitable to the rank and grade of Lieutenant James M'Intosh of the rifle corps, a native of the state of Georgia; and that he cause the same to be presented to that meritorious officer as a testimony of the high estimation in which he is held by the Legislature of his native state, for his gallantry and intrepidity, displayed in the late actions at Sandy creek and Conjocketa creek near Black Rock; the first conducted by Lieut. Col. Appling and the latter by the deceased Major Morgan.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 15th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N092" initial.page="80"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Tuesday, 15th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That both branches of the General Assembly will convene in the Representative chamber at two o'clock

<page id="GA1814.1.P79" no="GA1814.1.81" />

on Wednesday next, for the purpose of electing a Pay. Master General for this state, and also two Directors, on the part of the state for the Planters Bank at Savannah.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 16th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N093" initial.page="81"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Saturday, 12th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Job Weston be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Elbert and village of Elberton.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 19th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N094" initial.page="81"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Monday, 14th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Charles Dewit, Jun. be, and he is hereby appointed Vendue Master for the town of Darien in addition to those already appointed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 19th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N095" initial.page="81"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Saturday, 12th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>WHEREAS the Tax Collector of Twiggs county, having been prevented by the unexpected adjournment of the Court at the last term, from laying before the Grand Jury of said county a list of insolvent debtors for taxes:</p><p>Be it therefore resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is resolved by the authority of the same, that the said Tax Collector shall be, and he is hereby authorised and required to lay before the Grand Jury of the county aforesaid, at the next term of the Superior Court, the insolvent list aforesaid; and the said Tax-Collector is hereby indulged until the next Court for the purposes aforesaid, provided he shall pay over to the Treasurer all taxes collected by him agreeably to law.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 19th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N096" initial.page="81"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Saturday, 12th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>WHEREAS many of the citizens of this state without regard to existing treaties between the friendly Indians and the United States, and contrary to the interest and good policy of this state, have gone and frequently are going over and settling and cultivating the lands allotted to the

<page id="GA1814.1.P80" no="GA1814.1.82" />

friendly Indians for their hunting ground, by which means the state is not only deprived of their services in the army but considerable feuds are engendered between us and our friendly neighboring Indians</p><p>Resolved therefore by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia in General Assembly met, that his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to take the necessary means to have all intruders removed off the Indian lands and that proper steps be taken to prevent future aggressions.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 19th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N097" initial.page="82"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Tuesday, 15th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The committee to whom was referred the petition of Nehemiah Dunn as parent and natural guardian of [Illegible Text] Dunn and Benajah Dunn, minors.</p><p><i>Report,</i> That they have examined the vouchers accompanying the same, wherein it appears that Daniel Wallicon in the year 1783, purchased of the Commissioners of confiscated property a certain tract of land containing four hundred and fifty acres originally granted to William Jackson, on the third day of October one thousand seven hundred and sixty nine, situate and being in the parish of Saint Paul, (now Columbia county) which said tract of land was sold as the property of William Mansonand whereas the aforesaid Daniel Wallicon, did by his last will and testament bearing date the fifth day of September, 1789, give and bequeath the same [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] Wood who did convey the same to the said [Illegible Text] and Benajah Dunn, by deed of conveyance bearing date the 22d day March 1803And whereas it appears that the bond given for the purchase money of the [Illegible Text] tract of land has been fully discharged and paid off by the said Wallicon, and that there has been no deed of conveyance heretofore made by the commissioners of confiscated property; in consideration whereof we deem the prayer of the petioner reasonable and ought to be granted; we therefore recommend the following resolution</p><p>Resolved by the Senate and House of Representatives of the state of Georgia, in General Assembly met, that the present Commissioners of confiscated property or a majority of

<page id="GA1814.1.P81" no="GA1814.1.83" />

them do make and execute titles for the said four hundred and fifty acres of land to [Illegible Text] Dunn.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 19th November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N098" initial.page="83"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, 17th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That James A. Rogers be, and he is hereby appointed a Notary Public for the county of Telfair.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N099" initial.page="83"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Monday, 14th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That James E. Morris, John J. Bullock and Isaac Russel be, and they are hereby appointed Notaries Public for the county of Chatham.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N100" initial.page="83"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, November 19th, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Doctor Thompson Bird be, and he is hereby appointed a commissioner of the Academy of Baldwin county in the room of Hubert Reynolds, deceased.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N101" initial.page="83"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, November 17th, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Samuel Sturges be, and he is hereby appointed a Commissioner of the Academy of Burke county, to fill the vacancy created by the resignation of John Whitehead, Esquire.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N102" initial.page="83"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, November 17, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That William A. Knight be, and he is hereby appointed a Commissioner of the academy of the county of Wayne, in place of Allen B. Powell, Esquire, removed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N103" initial.page="83"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Tuesday, 15th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>Be it resolved, that his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorised and required to cause the bond that was given by Zach. Sims principal, and E. Park, Thomas

<page id="GA1814.1.P82" no="GA1814.1.84" />

Ligon, Abram Heard and Robert Royston, securities for $3000 that was loaned the said Zach. Sims, be collected as soon as it may be practicable.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N104" initial.page="84"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Friday, 18th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to cause the numbers of Clayton's Digest to be distributed with the Laws and Journals of the present session throughout the different counties in this state, in proportion to the number that may have been received.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N105" initial.page="84"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, 17th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The select committee to whom was referred the petition of Benjamin Davies,</p><p><i>Report,</i> That they have had the same under consideration and are of opinion that the prayer of the petioner is reasonable and ought to be granted, and therefore recommend the following resolution</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor, be requested to order the suspension or stay of the execution, the state against Benjamin Davis, until the next term of the Superior Court in Richmond county.</p><p><i>And be it further resolved,</i> That if the said Benjamin Davis shall or do on the first day of next term of the Superior Court of Richmond county aforesaid, deliver to the said Court the body of Abraham Collins, or to the Sheriff in vacation, that then and in such case his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby authorised to discharge the judgment recovered against the said Benjamin Davis by the state as the security of the said Abraham Collins.</p><approvaldate>Approved, 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1814V1N106" initial.page="84"><shorttitle><i>In the House of Representatives,</i> Thursday, 17th November, 1814.</shorttitle><p>The joint committee on Finance to whom was refered the report of the Comptroller General from the House of Representatives, beg leave to recommend the following resolution;</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the report of the Comptroller General be published three several times in one of the Milledgeville

<page id="GA1814.1.P83" no="GA1814.1.85" />

Gazettes, with the exception of the names of Theodore Montford and Richard T. Keating, so far as relates to the year 1807, as to the latter who appear to have settled the amounts stated to be due by them with the Sheriffs of [Illegible Text] and Bryan counties.</p><approvaldate>Approved 22d November, 1814.</approvaldate></law></part></body>

<page id="GA1814.1.P84" />

<backmatter><index><title>INDEX.<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>A<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Apropriation<br /></title><indexentry>act for the political year 1815, <pagenbr>Page, 13</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Of monies for fortifying the city of Savannah and other places, <pagenbr>62</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Attachments<br /></title><indexentry>mode of recovery of debts by, prescribed, <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Augusta<br /></title><indexentry>encroachments in the streets and highways of, how prevented and removed, <pagenbr>36</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Three Vendue Masters appointed for, <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Academies<br /></title><indexentry>100 acres of Glebeland belonging to the Waynesboro academy, to be sold by the Inferior court of Burke county, for the benefit of said academy, <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Of Chatham county, commissioner of appointed, <pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Trustees of the Richmond academy appointed, <pagenbr>70</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One commissioner of the [Illegible Text] academy appointed, <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two commissioners of the Louisville academy appointed, <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One commissioner of the Wilkes academy appointed, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One commissioner of the [Illegible Text] academy appointed, <pagenbr>83</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One commissioner of the Burke academy appointed, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One commissioner of the Wayne academy appointed, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Aid-de-camps,<br /></title><indexentry>to Brigadier Generals, the appointment of, authorised, <pagenbr>44</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Appling, Daniel Lt. Col.<br /></title><indexentry>a sword to be presented to, <pagenbr>69</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>B<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Bridge<br /></title><indexentry>McKinne and Shultz secured in the bridge across Savannah river at Augusta, <pagenbr>20</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Races of toll for crossing thereon, <pagenbr>21</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>The exclusive right to cease and determine if said bridge is suffered to be and remain impassible for two years, <pagenbr>22</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Brunswick and Frederica<br /></title><indexentry>commissioners of the towns of, authorised to tax the lots in, to raise money to rebuild the court-house and Jail in the county of Glynn, <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of, appointed, <pagenbr>59</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Brigade Quarter-<br /></title><indexentry>Masters, appointment of, authorised, <pagenbr>44</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Bryan county<br /></title><indexentry>scite of the public buildings of, removed many miles to Canuchee river, <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Inf. courts of, to levy the county tax, authorised by law, annually till the public buildings, are finished, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Inferior court of, not to hire the clerks and sheriffs to accept and hold those appointments in future, <pagenbr>58</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Baldwin county<br /></title><indexentry>Inferior court of, authorised to levy an extra tax, not to exceed 1-4 of the general tax, <pagenbr>51</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Banks<br /></title><indexentry>the board of directors of the Planters' bank of the state of Georgia, [Illegible Text] to remove from the city of Savannah to any part of the state of Georgia and transact business, under certain circumstances, <pagenbr>56</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Loan of money from them, Governor authorised to request, <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Borland Abraham<br /></title><indexentry>Resolution in favor of, <pagenbr>70</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>71</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Burson Jesse<br /></title><indexentry>A lease for part of town common granted him, <pagenbr>73</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>C<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Courts of Law and Equity,<br /></title><indexentry>[Illegible Text] of, regulated, <pagenbr>3</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Superior, times of holding them in the middle circuit altered, <pagenbr>16</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Times of holding the Superior courts in Lincoln county altered, <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Jurisdiction given to those of Jasper county for the [Illegible Text] of crimes committed by white persons in the [Illegible Text] Territory of this state, <pagenbr>41</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Inferior court of Eurke county, authorised to sell 400 [Illegible Text] of the Glebe lands for the use of the [Illegible Text] academy, <pagenbr>42</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Court-house and Jail in the county of Glynn to be rebuilt by taxing the lots in the towns of Brunswick and [Illegible Text] <pagenbr>43</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Inf. courts of Columbia and Warrea counties, authorised to pay for running the dividing line between said counties <pagenbr>Page 69</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv>

<page id="GA1814.1.P85" no="GA1814.1.ii" />

<indexdiv><title>Crimes committed<br /></title><indexentry>without the present Jurisdictional limits of the counties of this state and within the Territorial limits of the same, recognizable in the courts of Jasper county, <pagenbr>41</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Columbia county<br /></title><indexentry>a transcribed copy of the Records of the Register of Probates of said county, made valid in any courts of law, <pagenbr>53</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Clerks<br /></title><indexentry>Clerks and Sheriffs in Bryan county not to be hired to accept those appointments in future, <pagenbr>58</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Constitution<br /></title><indexentry>amendment to the Constitution of the U.S. proposed, <pagenbr>71</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>72</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Chatham county<br /></title><indexentry>Notary Public appointed for, <pagenbr>78</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>83</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Camden county<br /></title><indexentry>a Notary Public appointed for, <pagenbr>78</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Comptroller-General's report<br /></title><indexentry>directed to be published 3 times, <pagenbr>84</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>D<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Division Inspectors and Quarter Masters,<br /></title><indexentry>appointments of, authorised <pagenbr>44</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Darien,<br /></title><indexentry>town of, Vendue Masters appointed for, <pagenbr>78</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>81</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>A Lumber Measurer appointed for, <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Dunn Nehemiah<br /></title><indexentry>Resolution in favor of, <pagenbr>82</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Digests of the Laws of Georgia<br /></title><indexentry>Resolution directing the distribution of, <pagenbr>84</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Davis Benjamin<br /></title><indexentry>a Resolution in favor of, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>E<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Executions<br /></title><indexentry>stay of, authorised by defendants giving good security within ten days after date of judgment, <pagenbr>4</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Issuing from Justices courts, when levied upon property, which is claimed by a person not a party in Execution, he shall make an oath, <pagenbr>60</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Emanuel county<br /></title><indexentry>scite of the public buildings of, established and two more commissioners of, appointed for, <pagenbr>6</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Echols Obadiah,<br /></title><indexentry>Reddick Sims and Francis [Illegible Text]suits instituted on their bonds discontinued, <pagenbr>72</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>73</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Eatonton<br /></title><indexentry>town of, a vendue master appointed for, <pagenbr>78</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Elbert county<br /></title><indexentry>a notary public appointed for, <pagenbr>81</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>F<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Fleuellen,<br /></title><indexentry>Alexander and Kezziah his wife divorced, and the matrimonial contract between them disolved, <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Ferries<br /></title><indexentry>Thomas H. Miller authorised to establiah one across the north river, <pagenbr>45</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Flour<br /></title><indexentry>Inspection of, regulated and established, <pagenbr>48</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>51</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Fees<br /></title><indexentry>health officer and harbour master's act regulating the fees of, amended, <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Fractional surveys<br /></title><indexentry>purchases of, who are in the service indulged, <pagenbr>73</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>G<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>General, Brigadier<br /></title><indexentry>hour for the election of one appointed <pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Quarter-Masterhour for his election appointed, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Grantland, S.  F.<br /></title><indexentry>contractors for printing Laws and Journals <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Governor<br /></title><indexentry>requested to procure for, and present to Lt. Col. D. Appling a sword, <pagenbr>69</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to have published an act to authorise the several Courts of Law  Equity in this state to grant remedies in certain cases, c. c. <pagenbr>74</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to cause measures to be adopted to collect the money due on bonds for Milledgeville lots, rent of fractions, and for the 20 acre lots on the Milledgeville common, c. <pagenbr>75</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to instruct the Attorney and Solicitors Generals to take the most speedy and effectual measures to insure the collection and payment into the Treasury the monies due for confiscated and reverted property, <pagenbr>75</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to negotiate a loan with the Banks, <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to procure a sword for Lieut. James M'Intosh, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requestsd to remove intruders on the Indian lands, <pagenbr>82</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1814.1.P86" no="GA1814.1.iii" />

<indexentry>Requested to cause to be put in suit the bond of Zachariah Simms and others, <pagenbr>83</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to have the Digests compiled by Clayton, distributed, <pagenbr>84</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>[Illegible Text] county<br /></title><indexentry>a Notary Public appointed for, <pagenbr>78</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Greensboro town of,<br /></title><indexentry>a Vendue Master appointed for, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Glynn county<br /></title><indexentry>a Notary Public appointed for, <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>H<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Howard Samuel<br /></title><indexentry>secured in the exclusive right to navigate all the waters of the state of Georgia by steam for the term of 20 years, <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Hodgens Eliab,<br /></title><indexentry>name of, altered to that on Jones, <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Health officer<br /></title><indexentry>hour for election of, for the [Illegible Text] of Savannah appointed, <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Act regulating fees of, amended, <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>I<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Interest<br /></title><indexentry>an uniform mode for calculating of, <pagenbr>33</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Jones Robert<br /></title><indexentry>and Rachael his wife divorced, <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Joseph B. a lease of 10 acres town common granted him, <pagenbr>71</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Juries<br /></title><indexentry>Grand and Petit for the next terms of the [Illegible Text] court in Telfair and Pulaski counties to be drawn and [Illegible Text] by the Inf. courts, Clerks of the Superior courts and Sheriffs of said counties, <pagenbr>39</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Jamison John M.<br /></title><indexentry>and [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] wife, divorced, <pagenbr>47</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Indians' land<br /></title><indexentry>intruders on to be removed <pagenbr>81</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>K<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Kennon John<br /></title><indexentry>An act for the relief of the heirs and representatives of <pagenbr>45</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>L<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Laws<br /></title><indexentry>operation of extended to the residents in Wafford's settlement, <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Lotteries<br /></title><indexentry>one granted to raise $ 7000 00 to enable Heald, Gregg and Pearman to erect a Woollen Factory, <pagenbr>23</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of, appointed, <pagenbr>24</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One authorised to raise 10,000 dollars, to open the Oconee river from Fishing creek to Barnett's Sheals, <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Land Lotteries, fortunate drawers in, may take out their grants till 10th November, 1814, <pagenbr>60</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Land Lotteries, fortunate drawers in, may take out their grants till the first day of April, 1815, <pagenbr>63</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>64</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Learning<br /></title><indexentry>public seat of, in this state, the 10th section of an act passed the 27th January, 1785, more fully to complete and establish the same, explained, <pagenbr>57</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Laws and Journals<br /></title><indexentry>contract for printing of, closed with the Messrs. Grantland's, <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>M<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Militia<br /></title><indexentry>detachments of, how to be officered and organized, <pagenbr>9</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>10</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Incomplete Volunteer companies may form voluntary associations, or be consolidated by the Governor, <pagenbr>10</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Captains may accept, at the place of [Illegible Text] substitutes, <pagenbr>11</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Regimental courts, to consist of 13 officers, shall convene to hear and determine on all applications for exemptions, <pagenbr>11</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>12</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Students at the University, declared liable to do militia duty and to be classed, <pagenbr>12</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Montgomery county<br /></title><indexentry>part of Tatnall added to <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>M'Kinne John and Henry Shultz,<br /></title><indexentry>secured in the exclusive right of erecting a bridge at, or near Augusta for the term of 20 years, <pagenbr>20</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Miller Thomas H.<br /></title><indexentry>authorised to establish a ferry across the North river, <pagenbr>45</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Madison town of,<br /></title><indexentry>in the county of Morgan, incorporated, <pagenbr>54</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of, how elected, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>A Notary Public appointed for the county of, <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Milledgeville<br /></title><indexentry>hour for the election of 5 state commissioners of, appointed, <pagenbr>70</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of authorised to lease to J. B. Jones for the term of 10 years, 10 acres town common, <pagenbr>71</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1814.1.P87" no="GA1814.1.iv" />

<indexentry>Commissioners of, authorised to lease to Jesse Burson part of the town common for seven years, <pagenbr>73</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>M'Intosh,<br /></title><indexentry>James Lieut. a sword to be presented to, <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>N<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Navigation<br /></title><indexentry>right of, aided by steam and by towing, secured to Samuel Howard for twenty years, <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Opening and improving the navigation of the Oconee river from the mouth of Fishing creek to Barnett's shoals, <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Negociations at Ghent<br /></title><indexentry>proposals of the British Commissioners now there, as the terms on which the British Government is willing to conclude a peace, declared to be inadmissible, and even insulting, <pagenbr>76</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>[Illegible Text] Public<br /></title><indexentry>one appointed for Greene county, <pagenbr>78</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>appointed for Chatham county, <pagenbr>78</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>83</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for Camden county, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for [Illegible Text] county, <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for Glynn county, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for [Illegible Text] county, <pagenbr>81</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for Telfair county, <pagenbr>83</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>O<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>O'Reily,<br /></title><indexentry>John and Elizabeth his wife, divorced, <pagenbr>38</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Office of,<br /></title><indexentry>Division Inspector, Division Quarter Master, Brigade Quarter Master, and aid-de-camp to Brigadier Generals, created <pagenbr>44</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>P<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Pay-Master-General<br /></title><indexentry>office of, created and established, <pagenbr>23</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Penitentiary<br /></title><indexentry>a commissioner of, appointed, <pagenbr>67</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of, required to report, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Patrick,<br /></title><indexentry>Jno. M. resolution in his [Illegible Text] <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Pay-Master General<br /></title><indexentry>hour for the election of, appointed, <pagenbr>80</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>81</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>R<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Rents<br /></title><indexentry>mode of recovery and collection of, for the city of Augusta and its prescincts, prescribed, <pagenbr>17</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Rogers,<br /></title><indexentry>Whitmel and Reddick, altered to that of Rutland, <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Roads<br /></title><indexentry>acts of 1811 and 1812 amended, <pagenbr>34</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Commissioners of, to hold their appointments one year, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>How they shall be proceeded against for a neglect of duty, <pagenbr>35</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Certain counties exempted from the operation of this act, <pagenbr>36</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>S<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Sheriffs<br /></title><indexentry>allowed 2 1-2 per cent on the amount of all Executions issued against delinquent Tax-Collectors to be paid by said Collectors in addition to the sum due the state, provided such Sheriffs pay the money into the proper office within the time specified in said Execution, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Sheriffs and Clerks in Bryan county, not to be hired to hold those appointments in future, <pagenbr>58</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Smith Charles,<br /></title><indexentry>of Wilkes county, an act for the relief of, <pagenbr>55</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Swords<br /></title><indexentry>one to be presented to Lt. Col. D. Appling, <pagenbr>69</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One to be presented to Lieut. James M'Intosh <pagenbr>80</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Shackleford Mordecai<br /></title><indexentry>a resolution in favor of, <pagenbr>72</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>T<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Tax<br /></title><indexentry>for support of Government for the political year, 1815, <pagenbr>6</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>The Governor requested to pay the states proportion of a direct tax to be imposed by the General Government, <pagenbr>7</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Fifty per cent on the General Tax of 1814, to be collected to reimburse the state in part, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Collectors of the General Tax for 1814, may or may not collect the 50 per cent tax, and in case of their refusal the Inf. courts shall appoint some fit and proper person to collect the same, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1814.1.P88" no="GA1814.1.v" />

<indexentry>No Tax-Collector's security shall be eligible to the appointment of Sheriff, till such collector shall have paid up at the proper office all monies collected by him, <pagenbr>8</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>All collectors must settle their accompts by the first Monday in December, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>In future no collector shall be allowed any insolvent list unless it be procured, prior to the day he is required to settle his accompt, unless he should be prevented by a failure of the courts, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Extra Tax allowed to Bryan county to be laid annually till their county buildings are completed, <pagenbr>46</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Direct Tax of 1814, to be paid by the state to the U. States, <pagenbr>72</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Collector for Twiggs county 1813, a resolution in favor of, <pagenbr>81</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Tatnall county<br /></title><indexentry>a part of, added to Montgomery, <pagenbr>19</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Tapley James<br /></title><indexentry>an act for the relief of, <pagenbr>40</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Territory<br /></title><indexentry>the unlocated Territory of this state, which lies without the limits of the present counties, added to the county of Jasper <pagenbr>41</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Telfair county<br /></title><indexentry>scite of the public buildings of, removed to lot N 340, in the 8th district Wilkinson, now Telfair county, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>A Notary Public appointed for, <pagenbr>83</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Thanks<br /></title><indexentry>resolution of, to the officers of the army and navy, <pagenbr>67</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>69</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Twiggs county<br /></title><indexentry>tax collector of, for 1813, a resolution in favor of, <pagenbr>81</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>U<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>University<br /></title><indexentry>students in, declared liable to perform Militia duty, <pagenbr>58</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>A Trustee of, appointed, <pagenbr>72</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>V<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Verdicts and Judgements<br /></title><indexentry>shall not be given or entered against any soldier or officer, while in the service of this or of the U. States, nor for six months after their return from any tour of duty, provided that within twenty days after their return they give security, <pagenbr>4</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>5</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Vendue Masters<br /></title><indexentry>one appointed for Greensboro, <pagenbr>78</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>One appointed for the town of Eatonton, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Two appointed for the town of Darien, <pagenbr>ib</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Three appointed for the city of Augusta, <pagenbr>79</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>W<br set="CENTER" /></title><indexdiv><title>Wafford's settlement<br /></title><indexentry>Law extended to the residents in, <pagenbr>15</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Womack,<br /></title><indexentry>John and Mary his wife, divorced, <pagenbr>22</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Waynesboro<br /></title><indexentry>the act confirming the titles of persons who have purchased lots in, from and under the authority of the commissioners of, explained, <pagenbr>57</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>Wilkinson Reuben<br /></title><indexentry>a resolution in his favor, <pagenbr>74</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv><indexdiv><title>War<br /></title><indexentry>a resolution requesting the General Government to prosecute the War with vigor, rather than to submit to the terms proposed by the British commissioners at Ghent, <pagenbr>76</pagenbr></indexentry></indexdiv></indexdiv></index></backmatter></document></galaw>
