<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<galaw><metadata><coretitle>Acts of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</coretitle><creator>Georgia</creator><subject>Law, Georgia</subject><description>Georgia. Acts and resolutions of the General Assembly of the State of Georgia</description><publisher>MILLEDGEVILLE: CAMAK  [Illegible Text].</publisher><contributors><contributor /></contributors><date>18250000</date><type /><format /><identifier /><source /><language>English</language><relation /><coverage /><rights /></metadata>
<document initial.page="1" type="INFERRED">
<page id="GA1825.2.P1" no="GA1825.2.1" type="INFERRED" />

<titlepage><title>ACTS<br set="CENTER">OF THE<br set="CENTER">GENERAL ASSEMBLY<br set="CENTER">OF<br set="CENTER"><b>The State of Georgia,</b><br set="CENTER"><i>Passed at Milledgeville,</i><br set="CENTER">AT AN<br set="CENTER"><b>EXTRA SESSION</b><br set="CENTER">IN MAY AND JUNE,<br set="CENTER"><b>1825</b>.<br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></br></title><sessiondate>18250500</sessiondate><sessiondate>18250600</sessiondate><pubinfo><p>PUBLISHED BY AUTHORITY.</p><p>MILLEDGEVILLE</p><p>PRINTED BY CAMAK  [Illegible Text].</p><p><b>1825.</b></p></pubinfo></titlepage>

<page id="GA1825.2.P2" no="GA1825.2.3" />

<body><part><preface><p><b>ACTS</b> OF THE <b>General Assembly</b> OF THE STATE OF GEORGIA, PASSED IN MAY AND JUNE, 1825.</p></preface><title><br set="CENTER" /></title><law id="L1825V2N001" initial.page="3"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To dispose of and distribute the lands lately acquired by the United States for the use of Georgia of the Creek Nation of Indians, by a Treaty made and concluded at the Indian Spring on the twelfth day of February, eighteen hundred and twenty-five.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the territory acquired of the Creek nation of Indians by the United States for the use of Georgia, as described in articles of a Treaty entered into and concluded between Commissioners on the part of the United States, and the Chiefs, Head Men and Warriors of the Creek nation of Indians at the Indian Spring on the twelfth day of February, eighteen hundred and twenty-five, shall form and be divided into five sections, as follows, to wit: All that part of said territory which lies south of a line commencing on the Flint river opposite where the line diyiding the counties of Houston and Dooly strikes said river, and running due west to the Chattahoochie, shall form what shall

<page id="GA1825.2.P3" no="GA1825.2.4" />

be called Section the First, and the criminal jurisdiction thereof shall be attached to the county of Dooly.All that part of said territory which lies north of the line aforesaid and south of the line commencing on Flint river opposite where the original line dividing the counties of Monroe and Houston and running due west to the Chattahoochie river, shall form the Second Section, and the criminal jurisdiction thereof be, and the same is hereby attached to the county of Houston. And all that part of said territory which lies north of the line last aforesaid, and south of a line commencing on the Flint river where the original line dividing the counties of Henry and Monroe strikes said river, and running due west until it strikes the Chattahoochie river shall be, and the same is hereby called the Third Section, and the criminal jurisdiction thereof attached to the county of Pike.And all that part of said territory which lies north of said line, and cast of the Chattahoochie river, shall form the Fourth Section, and the criminal jurisdiction thereof shall be attached to the county of Fayette.And all that part of said territory lying west of the Chattahoochie river, and east of the dividing line between this state and the state of Alabama, shall form the Fifth Section, and the criminal jurisdiction thereof, shall be attached to the county of Pike.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That each of the sections herein before laid out and described, shall be divided into districts of nine miles square as near as practicablethe district lines running parallel to the lines dividing sections, and crossed by other lines at right angles; and said districts so laid out, shall be again subdivided by lines to be run in like directions into square tracts containing each two hundred two and one half acres, marked and numbered according to the plan heretofore pursued under the instructions of the Surveyor General.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the fractional parts of surveys which may be created by the divisions and subdivisions aforesaid shall be reserved for public uses, and be disposed of as a future legislature may direct.</p><p>SEC. 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That one hundred district surveyors shall be appointed by joint ballot of the legislature in one general ticket; and the person having the highest number of votes shall be entitled to the first

<page id="GA1825.2.P4" no="GA1825.2.5" />

choice of districts and in the same order, agreeably to the number of votes each surveyor may receive; and in case of a tie between any number of surveyors, then preference in choice shall be decided by lot in presence of the Surveyor General.</p><p>SEC. 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That ten persons shall be appointed by joint ballot of the legislature, neither of whom shall be a district surveyor, to run and plainly mark the several district, reserve and sectional lines herein before directed, whose duties shall be apportioned by the surveyor general as nearly equal as practicableand that no ticket shall be counted unless it contains the names of ten persons.</p><p>SEC. 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That no ticket for district surveyors shall be counted unless it contains one hundred names. Any person elected a surveyor who shall fail to perform the duties of his office, as required by the provisions of this act, shall be considered as forfeiting his bond, and himself and his securities immediately liable therefor.</p><p>SEC. 7. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That, the surveyors respectively shall give bond in the sum of ten thousand dollars to the governor and his successors in office, with such security as he or a majority of the justices of the inferior court of the county in which such surveyor may reside shall approve, conditioned for the faithful performance of the duties required of them by this act, which bond shall be deposited in the executive office.</p><p>SEC. 8. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That, it shall be the duty of the surveyors appointed in pursuance of this act, to make the surveys of the sections reserves and districts to which they may be appointed, in their own proper person, to mark, or cause to be marked plainly and distinctly upon trees, if practicable, otherwise on posts, all stations and all lines which they may be required to run for the purpose of making the surveys of their respective sections, reserves and districts immediately upon being required so to do by the surveyor general, to cause all such lines to be measured with all possible exactness, with a half chain containing thirty-three feet, divided into fifty equal links, which shall be adjusted by the surveyor general, according to the standard in his office; to take as accurately as possible the meanders of all water courses

<page id="GA1825.2.P5" no="GA1825.2.6" />

which shall form natural boundaries to any of the surveys; to note in field books to be kept by them respectively, the names of the corner and station trees, which shall be marked and numbered under the direction of the surveyor-general; also all rivers, creeks and other water courses which may be touched upon or crossed in running any of the lines aforesaid, transcripts of which field books after being compared with the originals by the surveyor general, and certified and signed on every page by the surveyor returning the same, shall be deposited in the surveyor-general's office, and become a record; and the district surveyors shall make a return of their surveys and works within ninety days from the time they are notified to enter upon the discharge of their duties, containing a map of their district in which shall be correctly represented and numbered all lots and fractions of said district and waters therein delineated as the surveyor general may direct, and also return at the same time a detached plat of each lot and fraction which said district may contain, certified and signed by such surveyor, which plat shall be filed among the records of the surveyor-general's office, and from which copies shall be taken to be annexed to grants: and said surveyors shall conform to such instructions as they may receive from time to time from the surveyor-general during their continuance in office: <i>Provided,</i> The same do not militate against this act. And the surveyors appointed to lay out section, reserve and district lines shall make return of their work to the surveyor-general within sixty days from the time they shall be required to enter upon the duties of their office of all such surveys as shall have been made on the east side of Chattahoochie river; and as to the remainder of the territory within sixty days from the notification of the running of the line between this state and Alabama.</p><p>SEC. 9. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the district surveyors to be appointed by this act, shall receive three dollars for every mile that shall actually be run or surveyed as a full compensation for the duties required of them by this act, out of which they shall defray the whole of the expences incident to their offices; and his excellency the governor is hereby authorised and required to issue his warrant on the treasury in favor of each of the aforesaid surveyors, upon his being called into service to the

<page id="GA1825.2.P6" no="GA1825.2.7" />

amount of three hundred dollars, to enable him with the less delay to enter upon his duties, and the balance to which such surveyor may be entitled, shall be paid to him in like manner, upon his producing a certificate from the surveyor-general setting forth a performance of the work, and the amount due.</p><p>SEC. 10 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the surveyors who may be appointed to run section, reserve, and district lines, shall receive three dollars and fifty cents for each mile they may run and survey, as a full compensation for their service, out of which all incidental expenses shall be paid; and the governor is required to issue his warrant on the treasury in favor of each of said surveyors for the sum of three hundred dollars upon their being called into service and in like manner to pay any balance which may be due when the work is completed, and the surveyor general shall certify the same.</p><p>SEC. 11. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the territory acquired as aforesaid shall be disposed of and distributed in the following manner, to wit: After the surveying is completed and return made thereof, his excellency the governor shall cause tickets to be made out, whereby all the numbers of lots in the different districts intended to be drawn for shall be represented, which tickets shall be put into a wheel and constitute prizes. The following shall be the description and qualifications of persons entitled to give in their names for a draw or draws under this act: Every male white person of eighteen years of age and upwards, being a citizen of the United States, and an inhabitant within the organized limits of this state three years immediately preceeding the passage of this act, including such as have been absent on lawful business, shall be entitled to one draw; every male person of like description having a wife or legitimate male child or children under eighteen years of age, or unmarried female child or children, resident as aforesaid, or who were born and have ever since resided in this state shall have two draws; all widows with like residence shall be entitled to one draw; and wives and children in this state of persons who have been absent from this state three years, shall be on the same footing as to draws as if the said husband was dead, and the title to such lots as said females or children may draw be vested permanently in them as though they [Illegible Text]

<page id="GA1825.2.P7" no="GA1825.2.8" />

widows and orphans; all families of orphans resident as aforesaid, or who have resided in this state from their birth under the age of eighteen years, except such as may be entitled in their own right to a draw or draws, whose father is dead, shall have one draw; all families of orphans consisting of more than two shall have two drawsbut if not exceeding two, then such orphan or orphans shall be entitled to one draw, to be given in in the county and district where the eldest of said orphans, or where the guardian of the eldest resides: <i>Provided,</i> That should such guardian or such orphan or orphans, or the eldest of such orphans reside within the organized limits of this state, then such draw or draws shall be given in in the county in which such guardian may reside, or such orphan or orphans or the eldest of such orphans may reside: all widows of like residence, whose husbands were killed or died in the service of their country, or on their return march, in the late wars against Great Britain or the Indians, shall be entitled to a draw exclusive of that otherwise allowed by this act to widows; all orphans whose fathers were killed or died in the service of the country, or on their return march, in the late wars against Great Britain or the Indians, shall be entitled to a draw exclusive of that otherwise allowed by this act to orphans; and all men who have been wounded or disabled in the late war with Great Britain or the Indians, so they are not able to procure a competency for support in consequence of their wounds, be allowed one draw in addition, and they shall take the following oath in addition: I do solemnly swear that I was wounded in the late war with Great Britain and the Indians, and am so disabled by the same that it renders me unable to procure a support by my labor: <i>Provided,</i> That nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to entitle any person or persons to a draw or draws in the present contemplated land lottery, who may have been fortunate drawers in any previous land lottery, except such persons as have drawn land as one of a family of orphans and who have arrived at the age of eighteen, but such person shall be entitled to one draw, and the remainder of such families of orphans shall be entitled to one draw: <i>And provided,</i> That all widows of revolutionary soldiers shall have one draw in addition to those already contemplated by this act: and that all revolutionary soldiers who were not [Illegible Text]

<page id="GA1825.2.P8" no="GA1825.2.9" />

drawers as revolutionary soldiers in the late land lottery shall be entitled to two draws as revolutionary soldiers, and those who drew one tract of land in the former lottery as revolutionary soldiers, one draw: <i>Provided,</i> that the citizens of this state who come under this act as above contemplated, and who volunteered or were legally drafted in the late war against Great Britain or the Indians, and refused to serve a tour of duty either in person or by substitute, or who may have deserted from the service of this state or of the United States, shall not be entitled to the provisions of this act as above contemplated, nor any of those who illegally avoided a draft, by removal or otherwise; and that no person or persons who have removed from the organized limits of this state for the purpose of avoiding the laws of this state, or who have absconded for debt, shall in no wise be benefitted by this act, and who have not paid all taxes required of them. In case any land is drawn by minors the grant shall issue accordingly upon payment of the usual fees: <i>Provided also,</i> Nothing herein contained shall be construed to exclude such persons as by the provisions of this act are allowed a draw or draws.</p><p>SEC. 12. <i>And be it further enacted.</i> That any sale or transfer that any person entitled to a chance or chances in this land lottery may make of such chance or chances, or make of any lot or lots of land, such persons may draw before the grant or grants of the same are taken out, shall be void, and any bond or obligation or letter of attorney given by said person to make titles, shall not be binding on such person: <i>And further,</i> It shall be illegal for any magistrate or person authorised to administer an oath, to administer an oath to any person selling his chance or chances, lot or lots, contrary to the provisions of this section that he will make titles to the same.</p><p>SEC. 13. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to allow any convict in the Penitentiary, to give in for a draw in the present contemplated lottery: <i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That the child or children, who have resided in this state three years, of any [of] said convicts, shall be entitled to a draw or draws, in the same manner they would be entitled if they were orphans, and may be given in for by their mother or other person under whose care they may be, and the grant or grants shall issue accordingly to any land so

<page id="GA1825.2.P9" no="GA1825.2.10" />

drawn: <i>Provided,</i> No such convict has drawn in any of the former land lotteries of this state in his own name.</p><p>SEC. 14. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That lists of persons entitled to draws under this act, shall be made out by the Inferior court of each county, or such persons as they may appoint, (not exceeding two to each battalion) within two months from the publication of this act; and said Inferior court of the several counties of this state, or the persons they may appoint shall attend in each captain's district, at least twice, giving ten days notice of such attendance, for the purpose of taking the names of the persons entitled to draws; the names of the persons entitled, shall be entered by the Receivers in a book to be kept for that purpose, a transcript of which book, fairly made out, shall be transmitted to the Executive, and the original deposited with the clerk of the Superior court of the respective counties; and should the Inferior court of any county fail to take in such names themselves, or to make proper appointments by the first day of September next, then the clerk of the Superior court, (or his legal deputy in his absence) in such county, may make such appointmentsAnd said Receivers, before they enter upon their duties, shall take and subscribe the following oath: I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will not receive or register any name, except the person giving in shall first take the oath prescribed by this act. So help me God.Which oath any justice of the Inferior court, or justice of the peace, is hereby required to administer, and the person or persons taking in names as aforesaid, shall administer to all applicants for draws other than widows, guardians or next friends of orphans, the following oath, to wit: I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I am a citizen of the United States, and have resided in this state three years immediately preceding the passage of this act, except absent on lawful business, and am an inhabitant of the same; that I was eighteen years of age at the time of the passing of this act; that I have (or have not) a wife or child or children; that I have not given in my name for any draw or draws in the present contemplated land lottery in any other part of the state; that I have not drawn a tract of land in the former lotteries in my individual capacity, or as an individual orphan, and that I did not, directly or indirectly,

<page id="GA1825.2.P10" no="GA1825.2.11" />

evade the service of this state or of the United States, in the late wars against Great Britain or the Indians. And the widows of revolutionary soldiers shall take the following oath or affirmation, (as the case may be,) to the best of their knowledge and belief, viz: I do solemnly swear or affirm that I am the widow of a revolutionary soldier to the best of my knowledge and belief. So help me God. The following oath shall be administered to all married women entitled to draws on account of three years absence of their husbands, as contemplated by this act, to wit: I do solemnly swear or affirm that my husband has been absent from this state three years, that I have resided the three last years in this state, except absent on lawful business, and am now a resident in this district, that I have not put in my name for a draw in the approaching land lottery in any other part of the state, and that I have not drawn any tract of land in the former land lotteries, either in my individual capacity, or as an individual orphan, to the best of my knowledge and belief. So help me God. The following oath shall be administered to the mother or next friend of any minor or family of minors who may be entitled to a draw or draws on account of three years absence of their father as contemplated by this act, to wit: I do solemnly swear that the minor or family of minors whom I now return is or are entitled to a draw or draws under this act to the best of my knowledge. So help me God. The following oath shall be administered to all revolutionary soldiers who shall apply for draws under this act. I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I served as a soldier in the armies of the United States during the revolutionary war a tour or tours of duty and am entitled to a draw or draws according to the provisions of this act. So help me God. And all guardians or next friends of orphans, or children of convicts in the penitentiary, shall take the following oath: And that the orphan or family of orphans, or the child or children whom I now return, is (or are) entitled to a draw or draws under this act, to the best of my knowledge. So help me GodThe following oath shall be administered to all widows: I do solemnly swear (or affirm) I am a widow, that I have resided the three last years in this state, except absent on lawful business, and am now resident in this district; that I have not put in my name for a draw in the

<page id="GA1825.2.P11" no="GA1825.2.12" />

present lottery in any other part of the state, and that I have not drawn land in the former lotteries, to the best of my knowledge and belief. So help me God. That all idiots and lunatics entitled to a draw or draws by this act, shall be given in by their respective parents or guardians, or next friend, who shall take the following oath: I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that the person whose name I now give in, is an idiot or lunatic; that he is eighteen years of age or upwards at the time of the passage of this act, and entitled to a draw or draws under this act; that he has not drawn land in any of the former land lotteries of this state in his name, or as an individual orphan. So help me God.</p><p>SEC. 15. <i>And be it further enacted.</i> That immediately after the passage of this act, his Excellency the Governor shall cause the same to be published in such of the public gazettes of this state as he may think proper, and shall require all persons entitled to draws to give in their names to the persons authorised to receive them, and said persons taking in said names shall receive twenty five cents from each of said applicants for each draw.</p><p>SEC. 16 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That if any person entitled by this act, to a draw or draws, should by absence or other unavoidable causes fail to give in his name within the time herein prescribed, it shall and may be lawful for such person to make oath of the draw or draws to which he may be entitled, before any justice of the Inferior court of the county in which he may reside, and make return thereof to the Executive, at any time before the commencement of the drawing; and it shall and may be lawful, for any person or persons, entitled to a draw or draws in said lottery who are about leaving the state on lawful business, to take the oath prescribed by this act, and deposit the same in the Clerk's office of the county where such person or persons may reside, and their names shall be registered according to the provisions of this act: <i>Provided,</i> Such person shall swear that he intends to return and remain a citizen of this state.</p><p>SEC. 17. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That five persons shall be appointed by joint ballot of the Legislature, to superintend the drawing of the lottery, to be convened at Milledgeville, by the Governor, when necessary, and that wherever this act imposes duties on the Governor, Survey-or-General,

<page id="GA1825.2.P12" no="GA1825.2.13" />

Surveyors, Receivers of names, or Commissioners, such duties shall be severally performed with as little delay as possible, consistently with a due execution of this act.</p><p>SEC. 18. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That as soon as said lists are made out and returned, his Excellency the Governor, for the purpose of carrying the lottery into effect, shall cause the names of persons entitled to draws, together with other designating remarks of residence, c. to be placed on tickets as nearly similar as possible, which shall be deposited in one wheel, and the prizes on tickets of the like description, shall be deposited in another wheel, which prizes shall consist of all square lots in said territory, not herein reservedAnd from each wheel, as nearly at the same time as may be, a ticket shall be drawn and delivered to the Superintending Managers, and so on until the whole number of prizes are drawn out, and said Managers shall make due and particular entry of the names so drawn out, and the prizes corresponding therewith, said names and prizes being first thoroughly mixed in their respective wheels. And his Excellency the Governor is required to give three weeks notice of the commencement of the drawing.</p><p>SEC. 19. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That should there be more districts than are contemplated by this act, and Surveyors elected for, or in case the appointment of any Surveyor should become vacant by death, resignation, or otherwise, his Excellency the Governor is requested to fill said vacancy. And in case any Surveyor shall be found incompetent, or fail to execute the duties required of him by this act, his office shall be vacant, and his vacancy filled in like manner.</p><p>SEC. 20. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the [Illegible Text] to be appointed in pursuance of this act, shall, before they enter upon their duties, take and subscribe the following oath: I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I am twenty-one years of age, that I will well and faithfully, to the best of my skill and abilities, discharge the duties which may be required of me as Surveyor in the territory lately acquiredSo help me God. Which oath the Surveyor-General is required to administer. The oath to [Illegible Text] administered to Chainmen by their respective Surveyors, shall be as follows: I do solemnly swear

<page id="GA1825.2.P13" no="GA1825.2.14" />

(or affirm) that, to the best of my skill and judgment, I will measure all lines on which I may be employed as chain carrier, as accurately and with as little deviation from the course pointed out by the Surveyor as possible, and give a true account of the same to the Surveyor. So help me God. And similar oaths shall be administered by the said Surveyors to all axe men and markers.</p><p>SEC. 21. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the land to be distributed under the provisions of this act, shall be classed under the following heads, viz: First quality river land, second quality river land, first quality oak and hickory upland, second quality oak and hickory upland, first quality pine land, and pine land, and that it shall be the duty of Surveyors charged with the business of dividing the districts into lots, to note upon the separate plat of each lot which he is required to file in the Surveyor-General's office, the quality of each lot, according to the foregoing classes, and that all persons who may draw lands under this act shall be entitled to receive grants for the same conveying fee simple titles, on paying into the treasury of this state the sum of eighteen dollars; and any person drawing, and failing to take out his grant within two years from the date of said draw, shall forfeit his or her right to receive a grant to the land so drawn, and the same shall revert to the state, orphans, lunatics and idiots excepted. And all persons who shall draw lands in the lottery authorised by this act, shall whether the same be granted or not, pay taxes thereon, at the same rates as for other lands of similar qualities, until they shall relinquish the same to the use of the state, by writing to be filed in the office of the Secretary of State. That all returns made contrary to the true intent and meaning of this act are declared to be fraudulent; and all grants issued in consequence of any draw made in the contemplated lottery, on such fraudulent returns, are hereby declared to be null and void; and the lands so granted or drawn shall revert and become the property of the state; and the question of the fraud be tried upon scire facias, to be issued from under the hands of the clerk of the Superior courts of the county or counties in which the land lies, in the name of the Governor of said state for the time being, upon the application of any individual against the tenant in possession of the land alleged to be fraudulently drawn or against the drawer thereof, setting forth the circumstances

<page id="GA1825.2.P14" no="GA1825.2.15" />

of fraud in the said scire facias, specially, and upon the return of the said scire facias, with an entry thereon of service effected by any sheriff of any county of this state by leaving a copy thereof with the person named as defendant, or at his or her notorious place of abode, or by the return of said sheriff that the defendant is not to be found; upon which return the court is authorised to have service perfected by an, order for a three months publication in one or more of the public gazettes of this state; which rule, when duly published, shall be considered as sufficient service to authorise an issue to be made up under the direction of the court to try the question of fraud. And in case the jury shall find the return fraudulent, the court shall by judgment pronounce the grant issued on such return and draw to be void, and order it cancelled; which judgment, when transmitted to the Surveyor-General's office and Secretary of State's office, and entered of file there, shall be of sufficient authority to those officers to cancel the plats and grants for such fraudulent draws from their offices respectively. And the land when condemned, shall belong one half to the state and the other half to the informer, and subject to be laid off between the informer and the state by writ of partition, to be issued under the direction of the Superior court of the county in which the land lies; and [to] the proceedings of said writ of partition on behalf of the state, it shall be the duty of the Solicitors in the respective circuits to attend. And when the said lands are so laid off, the informer shall be entitled to a plat and grant for his share, upon the payment of the legal office fees: <i>Provided nevertheless,</i> That no return made by or on behalf of [any] orphan or orphans, shall be pronounced fraudulent until his her or their legal guardian shall have been made a party to the scire facias, or other discreet person appointed by the court in which the case is tried, to defend the case for the said orphan or orphans: <i>And provided also,</i> The proceedings under this section take place within four years from the date of the drawing.</p><p>SEC. 22. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That no case after being commenced as aforesaid, by scire facias, shall be settled or compromised by the informer, or otherwise disposed of to the prejudice of the state, and in case it is, said land shall be liable to be returned by any other [Illegible Text]

<page id="GA1825.2.P15" no="GA1825.2.16" />

in manner above prescribed, and division made thereof accordingly.</p><p>SEC. 23. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That no scire facias shall issue until the applicant shall have made and deposited in the clerk's office from whom the said scire facias shall issue, the following oath: I do solemnly swear that in making this information, I have no combination or understanding directly or indirectly with the drawer or any other person as the friend of, or on the part of the drawer.</p><p>SEC. 24. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That a quantity of land on the Flint river, opposite the old Agency, and equal in size to the reserve on the east side of the same; one mile square at Marshall's ferry on Flint river including the ferry; one mile square at McIntosh's on the Chattahoochie including the ferry, and a reserve of five miles square on the Chattahoochie river at the Coweta falls and including the samethe northern boundary to cross the river at a point one mile above the lower shoal, be and the same is hereby set apart for public purposes.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE.</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 9, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N002" initial.page="16"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorise the City Council of Augusta to negotiate a loan.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the City Council of Augusta be, and they are hereby authorised to negotiate a loan for a sum or sums of

<page id="GA1825.2.P16" no="GA1825.2.17" />

money not exceeding one hundred thousand dollars, and to give such security or securities for its redemption as the City Council of Augusta may deem best for the interest of the said city, and of the person or persons who may take the said loan.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N003" initial.page="17"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To establish Election Districts in the counties of Irwin, Appling, and Ware, and to punish those who may attempt to defeat the same.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of</i> R<i>epresentatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passage of this act all elections which may be held for state or county officers shall be held at the following places, to wit: In the county of Irwin at the court-houseat Sion Hall in the twelfth district in said countyand at the house of Thomas Gibbs in the second district in said county. In the counties of Ware and Appling at the several places of holding justices courts in the several company districts in said counties.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That if any person or persons shall vote at any election authorised by this act, contrary to and in violation of the laws of this state, he or they shall be subject to be fined in a sum not exceeding thirty dollars for each and every offence, one half to the

<page id="GA1825.2.P17" no="GA1825.2.18" />

use of the informer, and the other half to be appropriated to county purposes.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid.</i> That the elections authorised by this act shall be conducted and superintended by one justice of the inferior court, or one justice of the peace for the county in which the same may be held, assisted by two freeholders of the same county, not being candidatesthe said freeholders first taking the following oath, to wit: I, A. B. do solemnly swear that I will superintend this day's election and make a just and true return of the same, to the best of my abilities. So help me God.</p><p>SEC. 4. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the persons superintending said election in the county of Irwin shall receive and count out the votes at the place of holding such election on the day appointed for holding the same; and the said managers or one of them, shall meet on the second day after such election at the place of holding the Superior courts in the county aforesaid, and compare the several returns and certify the person or persons who may be elected agreeably to law.</p><p>SEC. 5. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the place and duties of the sheriff of said counties at said elections shall be supplied by any lawful constable of said counties respectively.</p><p>SEC. 6. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid,</i> That the persons superintending the said elections in the counties of Appling and Ware shall receive and count out the votes at each of the places of such elections on the day appointed for holding the same, and the said managers or one of them shall meet on the next day after such election at the places of holding the Superior courts in the county aforesaid, and compare the several returns and certify the person or persons who may be elected agreeable to law.</p><p><b>JOIN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P18" no="GA1825.2.19" />

<law id="L1825V2N004" initial.page="19"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorise James C. Terrell and Andrew J. Miller to plead and practise as Attornies and Solicitors in the several courts of law and equity in this state.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, James C. Terrell and Andrew J. Miller shall be permitted and allowed to plead and practice as Attornies and Solicitors in the several courts of law and equity in this state, on undergoing an examination, and being approved by the court, as required by law.</p><p><b>JOHN [Illegible Text]</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N005" initial.page="19"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorise the justices of the Inferior courts of the different counties in this state in certain cases to draw for and dispose of the dividends of the poor school fund to which their counties may respectively be entitled.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That in all the counties in this state where no trustees have been

<page id="GA1825.2.P19" no="GA1825.2.20" />

or may hereafter be appointed in conformity to the act passed on the twenty second day of December, eighteen hundred and twenty-three, for distributing a portion of the poor school fund, it shall and may be lawful for the justices of the Inferior courts of said counties respectively to draw for and dispose of the dividends to which their counties may respectively be entitled, in such manner as they may think will best promote the intention of the legislature any thing in said law to the contrary notwithstanding: <i>Provided however,</i> That the justices aforesaid shall make annual reports to the Senatus Academicus of their actings and doings in the premises, shewing the plans pursued by them respectively.</p><p><b>JOHN [Illegible Text]</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N006" initial.page="20"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorise a lottery for the benefit of Salem academy in Clark county.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That it shall and may be lawful for the commissioners hereinafter named to establish a lottery as soon as practicable after the passing of this act, to raise the sum of three thousand dollars, under such scheme and regulations as they, or a majority of them, may deem necessary and proper; which sum or any part thereof when so raised and received, shall be applied by the trustees of said academy

<page id="GA1825.2.P20" no="GA1825.2.21" />

or their successors in office, to the building of an academy edifice, and to any other purpose connected with the interest of the institution.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That Joseph Smith, Samuel Hester, John Foster, William P. Graham, John W. Graves, and James C. Branch, be and they are hereby appointed Commissioners to carry the aforesaid lottery into full effect.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N007" initial.page="21"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To exempt persons who are Ferrymen from performing militia duty in time of peace.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, all persons who are regularly employed as Ferrymen liable to perform militia duty shall for and during the period they are employed as aforesaid, be exempt from militia duty in times of peace.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P21" no="GA1825.2.22" />

<law id="L1825V2N008" initial.page="22"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To limit the time for the return of fraudulent draws under the land lottery acts of eighteen hundred and eighteen, and to alter and amend so much of the twentieth section of an act passed fifteenth day of May, eighteen hundred and twenty-one, as [Illegible Text] to the return of lots supposed to be fraudulently drawn in said lotteries.</fulltitle><p><i>[Illegible Text] it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the first day of July next, no scrie facias shall issue on any lot of land supposed to be fraudulently drawn in either of the land lotteries above recited, and that all laws or parts of laws militating against this act be and the same are hereby repealed.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented [Illegible Text] June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N009" initial.page="22"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorise the Board of Commissioners of the public roads for the county of Glynn to appropriate hands to work on Honey-gall creek, and to establish a public landing at the bluff, and appoint Commissioners for the same.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passage of this act, that

<page id="GA1825.2.P22" no="GA1825.2.23" />

the board of Commissioners of the public roads for the county of Glynn do appropriate hands to work on the Honey gall creek.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the common landing on said creek, be and it is hereby established as a public landing, free for all boats and rafts to go to or from said landing.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That James Powell, William Huston and David Pentan be, and they are hereby appointed Commissioners for the same, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N010" initial.page="23"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To incorporate the town of Thomaston, and to make permanent the seat of justice in the county of Upson.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the [Illegible Text] of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That Edward Hollaway, Robert [Illegible Text] Collier, James Walker, Sen. James Cooper and Joseph Rogers be, and they are hereby appointed commissioners of said town, and shall continue in office until their successors are appointed and qualified according to the provisions of this act.</p><p>SEC. 2 <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That on the first Monday in January, eighteen hundred and twenty-six, and on the first Monday in January in every year thereafter, all persons inhabitants of said town, entitled to vote

<page id="GA1825.2.P23" no="GA1825.2.24" />

for members of the General Assembly shall assemble at the court-house in said town, and by ballot elect five commissioners who shall continue in office one year and until their successors shall be elected and qualified, at which election any two justices of the inferior court, or any two of the justices of the peace of said [Illegible Text] not being themselves candidates shall preside, and if it shall so happen that said election shall not take place on the day herein appointed, any one or more of the justices of the inferior court or justices of the peace for said county, may afterwards by giving ten days public notice, hold the same in the manner herein prescribed; and in case of the death or removal of any of the said commissioners the remaining commissioners shall have power to fill such vacancy until the next annual election.</p><p>SEC. 8. <i>and be it further enacted,</i> That, it shall not be lawful for any of said commissioners so elected or appointed to enter on the duties of his office until they shall have taken and subscribed the following oath: <b>I. A. B.</b> do solemnly swear, (or affirm, as the case may be,) that I will well and truly perform the duties of a commissioner, by adopting such measures as shall in my judgment, be best calculated to promote the general good of the citizens of the town of Thomaston.</p><p>SEC. 4. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That, the said commissioners shall have full power and authority to make any bye-laws, ordinances or regulations, and power to enforce the same, that they may deem best calculated to promote the general good of the citizens of said town: <i>Provided always,</i> That no such law, ordinance or regulation shall be contrary to the constitution and laws of this state or of the United States.</p><p>SEC. 5. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said commissioners shall have jurisdiction within half a mile of the court-house in all directions.</p><p>SEC. 6. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the said town of Thomaston shall be the seat of justice of the county of Upson.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P24" no="GA1825.2.25" />

<law id="L1825V2N011" initial.page="25"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorise the trial of certain causes in Gwinnett Inferior Court.</fulltitle><p>Whereas, owing to the failure of the justices to attend the court on the second Monday in December, eighteen hundred and twenty four, the appearance docket of said court was not called.</p><p>And whereas, considerable inconvenience and delay will result from that causeFor remedy whereof,</p><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That all causes which were made returnable to December term, eighteen hundred and twenty four of said court shall be considered as standing regularly for trial, and that all pleas and answers which shall be filed on or before the first day of June term of said court, eighteen hundred and twenty-five shall be considered legal and valid.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives,</p><p><b>ALLEN B POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N012" initial.page="25"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To authorise the justices of the Inferior Court of the county of Gwinnett to remit a fine incurred by George Steen.</fulltitle><p>Whereas George Steen heretofore became bound for the appearance of Robert M. Hogg at the Superior court of

<page id="GA1825.2.P25" no="GA1825.2.26" />

Gwinnett county, at September term, eighteen hundred and twenty-four, and Robert M. Hogg failing to appear, his recognizance was forfeited for the sum of three hundred dollars.</p><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and after the passing of this act, the justices of the Inferior court of the county of Gwinnett be, and they are hereby authorised and empowered to remit the whole or any part of said fine so incurred by George Steen on the failure of Robert M. Hogg so to appear: <i>Provided,</i> That the said George Steen shall in no case be exhonerated until he shall have paid all costs that accured in said case.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted by the authority aforesaid.</i> That all laws or parts of laws militating against this act be and they are hereby repealed.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N013" initial.page="26"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To alter and amend an act entitled an act, to grant temporary relief to the purchasers of fractions, lots and islands, passed on the seventh day of December, eighteen hundred and twenty-four.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Sonate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the purchasers of fractions, lots and islands in the counties

<page id="GA1825.2.P26" no="GA1825.2.27" />

named in the before recited act, who have failed to take the relief therein granted, shall have it [Illegible Text]: <i>Provided,</i> They comply with the requisitions therein contained within sixty days from and after the passage of this act.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N014" initial.page="27"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To legitimate and change the names of Jesse D. George W. James D. and Lucinda Hall to that of Jesse D. George W. James D. and Lucinda Hardage.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of</i> R<i>epresentatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the names of Jesse D. George W. James D. and Lucinda Hall be and they are hereby changed to that of Jesse D. George W. James D. and Lucinda Hardage, and that they are hereby declared to be fully and completely legitimated and entitled to all the rights and legal privileges that they would have been had they been born in lawful wedlock, so far as respects the estate of their reputed father only, any law, usage or custom to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P27" no="GA1825.2.28" />

<law id="L1825V2N015" initial.page="28"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To alter and change the name of Matthew R. T. Harrison to that of Matthew [Illegible Text] Williams.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That from and immediately after the passing of this act the name of Matthew R. T. Harrison of Elbert county, be and the same is hereby altered and changed to that of Matthew Jouett Williams.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to prevent the said Matthew Jouett Williams from receiving or recovering any property to which he was entitled previous to the passage of this act, any law, resolution or decision to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives,</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N016" initial.page="28"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>To alter and change the name of Jesse G. Fuller to that of Jesse Gunn.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of</i> R<i>epresentatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That

<page id="GA1825.2.P28" no="GA1825.2.29" />

from and after the passage of this act the said Jesse G. Fuller shall be called and known by the name of Jesse Gunn, any law or usage to the contrary notwithstanding.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="L1825V2N017" initial.page="29"><lawtype>AN ACT</lawtype><fulltitle>Supplementary to and amendatory of an act passed the eighteenth of December, one thousand eight hundred and twenty-four, entitled an act to appropriate monies for the political year, eighteen hundred and twenty-five.</fulltitle><p><i>Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met, and it is hereby enacted by the authority of the same,</i> That the sum of one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, be and the same is hereby appropriated as a land fund, subject to the orders of the Governor.</p><p>SEC. 2. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the following sums of money be appropriated to the persons, and for the purposes herein after mentioned, viz: To the clerk of the committee on the state of the republic eighty dollarsand clerk of the committee on finance fifty dollars for additional services; and the sum of five hundred dollars be appropriated to William Triplett, comptroller-general for ascertaining the unsettled balances of accounts against the several defaulting tax collectors of this state, from the year eighteen hundred up to the time of his going into officethe sum of one hundred dollars for the compensation of Cicero Holt, Esq. solicitor-general of the western circuit,

<page id="GA1825.2.P29" no="GA1825.2.30" />

and twenty five dollars for the compensation of C. J. McDonald, solicitor general of the Flint circuit for services rendered in the trial of John Loving before the high court of impeachment; and the sum of three dollars per day be allowed to the witnesses who have attended upon subp[oelig]nas on prosecution of the state against John Loving, Samuel Jackson and Fleming F. Adrian, impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and those who have attended upon subp[oelig]nas and testified before the joint committee on the state of the republicand that the sum of three dollars be allowed to the same for every twenty miles they have travelled in going to and returning from the seat of government for that purpose; and the sum of four dollars for every twenty miles travelled be allowed to the messengers who have been employed in summoning witnesses; and the sum of four thousand dollars be appropriated to aid in erecting of monuments in the city of Savannah, to the memories of Greene and Pulaskiand that his excellency the Governor be authorised to draw on the treasury for the above sums, out of any monies not otherwise appropriated; to Wm. Y. Hansell two hundred dollars for his services as clerk to the high court of impeachment.</p><p>SEC. 3. <i>And be it further enacted,</i> That the sum of twenty thousand dollars be and the same is hereby appropriated as a military fund subject to be drawn for by the Executive; and to the surveyor-general the sum of twenty dollars for each map of districts transcribed by him, agreeable to a concurred resolution, to be paid quarter yearly as said maps are completed.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b></p><p>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b></p><p>President of the Senate.</p><p><b>G. M. TROUP,</b> Governor.</p><approvaldate>Assented to, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law></part>

<page id="GA1825.2.P30" no="GA1825.2.31" />

<part><title><b>Resolutions</b><br set="CENTER"><b>WHICH ORIGINATED IN SENATE.</b><br set="CENTER" /></br></title><law id="R1825V2N018" initial.page="31"><shorttitle><b>IN SENATE, May 28, 1825.</b></shorttitle><p>The committee to whom was referred the petition of Thomas S. Clay in behalf of the estate of Joseph Clay, deceased, have minutely examined the receiver's digest for the county of Bryan for the years eighteen hundred and twenty-three and eighteen hundred and twenty-four, and find that said estate has been over assessed the amount specified in the said petition, viz. forty dollars and thirty-three centstherefore recommend the following resolution.</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the tax collector of Bryan county for said years be, and he is hereby required to refund the said amount to the said Thomas S. Clayand that the comptroller general be authorised to settle with the said tax collector accordingly.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 9, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N019" initial.page="31"><shorttitle><b>IN SENATE, May 26, 1825.</b></shorttitle><p>Whereas a considerable portion of the documents accompanying the message of his excellency the Governor are of a nature highly interesting to the good people of this state</p>

<page id="GA1825.2.P31" no="GA1825.2.32" />

<p><i>It is therefore resolved,</i> That one thousand copies of said message together with the whole of such documents accompanying the same as are connected with the affairs of this state in relation to the [Illegible Text] and [Illegible Text] nations be printed.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 1, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N020" initial.page="32"><shorttitle><b>IN SENATE, June 4, 1825.</b></shorttitle><p>The committee of finance to whom was referred the memorial of the commissioners of a canal to be cut off from Piney island to Cat fish [Illegible Text] on the Alatamaha river report that they have performed the duty assigned them, and recommend the following resolution.</p><p>R<i>esolved,</i> That no more money be paid out until the work is completed, but that the time for the completion be extended to one year.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 9, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N021" initial.page="32"><shorttitle><b>IN SENATE, May 31, 1825.</b></shorttitle><p>The committee on the state of the republic to whom was referred so much of the Governor's message and the accompanying documents as relates to the boundary line between this state and Alabama, and this state and Florida Report</p><p>That they have had the same under consideration, and believe that the running of the line between this state and Florida not to be of sufficient importance to require any legislative interference before the regular session of the legislature. But the ascertaining the boundary line between this state and Alabama, your committee believe to be a [Illegible Text] of much greater importance, and one that requires

<page id="GA1825.2.P32" no="GA1825.2.33" />

the immediate attention of the legislature. If [Illegible Text] act should be passed at the present session, as is contemplated, to survey and dispose of the territory recently acquired from the Creek Indians, it will become essentially necessary to have the line between this state and Alabama ascertained; and it appearing from the documents in the possession of your committee that the government of Alabama and the United States have been consulted on this subject, and have declined any agency therein, your committee beg leave to submit the following resolution.</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the Governor be required as soon as practicable to procure the services of some competent person or persons to ascertain the boundary line between this state and Alabama, according to the terms of the compact entered into between this state and the United States in the year eighteen hundred and two, first giving to the governor of Alabama due notice thereof, so that commissioners on the part of that state may be appointed to co-operate with the commissioners appointed on the part of this state if the government of said state shall deem it necessary to do so.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N022" initial.page="33"><shorttitle><b>IN SENATE, June 9, 1825.</b></shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That Daniel Brinson, Ezekiel Clifton, [Illegible Text] Dasher, James Tilman, and Elijah Mattox, Jr. be and they are hereby appointed trustees for the Tattnall county academy.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N023" initial.page="33"><shorttitle><b>IN SENATE, June 9, 1825.</b></shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his excellency the Governor be requested to forward as soon as practicable the laws and journals of the present called session to each county.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P33" no="GA1825.2.34" />

<law id="R1825V2N024" initial.page="34"><shorttitle>IN SENATE, June 7, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his excellency the Governor be requested to purchase two portraits, one of Gen. George Washington, and one of Gen. Lafayette, and have the said portraits elegantly framed and placed conspicuously in the senate chamber; and that his excellency be further requested to procure portraits of Thomas Jefferson, Benjamin Franklin, and Gen. Oglethorpe, and have them framed in like manner, and that the two former be in like manner placed in some conspicuous part in the representative chamber, and the latter in the executive.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N025" initial.page="34"><shorttitle>IN SENATE, June 4, 1825.</shorttitle><p>It appearing by a letter of the surveyor-general in answer to a call of a committee of the senate, that among all the plans of districts in his office there are some so torn and mutilated as to be useless.</p><p><i>It is resolved,</i> That the surveyor-general do cause them to be transcribed, <i>Provided,</i> the expense of such transcripts do not exceed twenty dollars each: and that the said transcripts as well as all other plans of districts now in, and which may hereafter be brought into his office, be put on rollers and so put up in a case or cabinet to be provided by the surveyor general for that purpose, as to be most convenient for reference and not liable to mutilation or injury in future.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N026" initial.page="34"><shorttitle>IN SENATE, June 4, 1825.</shorttitle><p>The committee of finance to whom was referred so much of the Governor's communication as relates to the expenses incurred by the reception of Gen. Lafayette have performed the duties assigned them, and Report</p>

<page id="GA1825.2.P34" no="GA1825.2.35" />

<p>That the expenses incurred as aforesaid are reasonable when we take into consideration the circumstances and the occasion on which they were made.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 9, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N027" initial.page="35"><shorttitle>IN SENATE, June 7, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the commissioners of the Ocmulgee navigation be, and they are hereby authorised to enter on the bond such credit as they may on statement think justly due to James H. Hardaway, for the loss of the services of a negro who was drowned shortly after said Hardaway had hired him from said commissioners.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N028" initial.page="35"><shorttitle>IN SENATE, June 10, 1825.</shorttitle><p>The Joint Committee on the State of the Republic, to whom were referred the subject of the conduct of the Agent of Creek Indian Affairs in relation to the late treaty with that nation; and also in respect to the murder of General McIntosh and others of the Creek chiefs, have had those matters under their serious deliberation. They have not indeed investigated them to the extent that could have been wishedbut have given them all the attention which their other duties, and the length of time would allow. In addition to the documents accompanying his Excellency's messages at the opening of the session, and of the third instant, your committee in the exercise of the power given them by resolution, have collected such further evidence as has come to their knowledge and been within their [Illegible Text] In their view of the whole subject your committee have not considered themselves precluded from the consideration of that part of the evidence which has been before the President, because it is so supported and strengthened by what has been since disclosed that its own weight

<page id="GA1825.2.P35" no="GA1825.2.36" />

is greatly enhanced, its character is in a considerable measure changed, and in its turn it tends greatly to illustrate the latter. On the same principle your committee have of course received some evidence which is not now in point, and therefore has been allowed no weight in their deliberations. This may or may not be rendered applicable by evidence hereafter to be obtained; and will of consequence be used, or rejected accordingly in the final investigation.</p><p>That the Agent did not assist the United States Commissioners at the first negociations at Broken Arrow in December last, or even co-operate with them, is confessed by himself. The only apology we have heard offered for that conduct, was his ignorancethat he supposed he had nothing to do in the matter, but merely to assemble the chiefs and to attend to the rations. Now we deem it not too much to assume, that a man of the intelligence and sagacity of the Agent, who had been five years in the office, did well know, what the late Secretary of War condescended to tell him, that the paramount duty which he owed to the government obligated him on all occasions to give his hearty co-operation in effecting its views.And we further presume him to have been able to apprehend that the acquisition of territory was the object the government had in view in holding the treaty. But he was moreover expressly and repeatedly informed of those views, and of his duty in relation to them. The Secretary of War on the 16th of July, 1824, in announcing to the commissioners their recent appointment, instructed them among other things, first, that it was the desire of the Government, that the feelings and wishes of the state of Georgia should be particularly attended to, and the location and extent of the territory to be treated for, is therefore left at their discretion; and secondly, that the Agent was instructed to obey their orders <i>on all points</i> connected with the proposed treaty. Of this instruction the Agent acknowledges to the Secretary of War that he had a copy. Early in August the Commissioners informed the Agent that they were instructed to correspond with him respecting the treaty, and expressed their pleasure in the prospect of a free discussion of <i>all matters connected with the subject.</i> And on the 5th of September they again addressed him, informing him of the great concern felt for the negociation, and specially directed him <i>to prepare</i>

<page id="GA1825.2.P36" no="GA1825.2.37" />

<i>the nation for the issue desired.</i> The public interests were indeed confided to his charge; little if any less to him than to the commissioners themselves. Was it not for the letter of the 18th of January last from the late Secretary of War, your committee would express their astonishment at the effrontery of the Agent in pretending, if the ever did pretend, that he was ignorant either of the nature or the extent of his duties.</p><p>It remains next to be seen how he performed those duties so obvious in themselves, and moreover so anxiously and repeatedly enjoined upon him. It is natural to suppose that an officer in a high trust, knowing thus well his official obligations, if he intended treachery would act cautiously in an enterprise of such delicacy in the management, and so dangerous if detected. His obvious course would be to act as much as possible through the instrumentality of others, concealing himself as far as practicable behind the scenes. In the case before us, it accordingly turns out that most of the mischiefs have been wrought at second hand. While the Agent was professedly neutral the immediate ostensible actors in those scenes have been those persons nearest connected with him and, most in his confidence; and most if not all of them in some way dependent on him, or on his continuance in office. And although positive evidence is by no means wanting, yet perhaps the strongest and most satisfactory proof of his guilt is found in the character and situation of those immediate instruments of mischief; in their connexion with the Agent in various ways; and in a multitude of minor circumstancesparts of a system of measures which we think he instigated and countenanced, but dared not openly conduct. And if so, more strongly evincing his guilt by the desire of concealment.</p><p>In the month of May preceding the appointment of the commissioners a meeting had been held by the hostile chiefs at Tuckabatchie to resist the views of the United States. The result of their meeting was by the sub-agent reduced into a kind of written manifesto, declaring that they would not dispose of their lands. These transactions were notorious in the nation, but the Agent made no intimation of them either to his government or to its commissioners. When in July, 1824, the nation or a part of it had assembled at Broken Arrow to receive their annuity, a

<page id="GA1825.2.P37" no="GA1825.2.38" />

council was convoked at which the Agent was present, but retired with all other white persons except his sub-agent and Hambly his interpreter, that the former of these [Illegible Text] read a long communication from the Cherokees exhorting the Creeks not to dispose of a foot of their territory. Of this the agent gave no intimation of which your committee are apprised. Nor was any notice taken of a third meeting in November at the Pole Cat Spring, consisting wholly or principally of the red sticks of the late war, although the meeting was at the house of the sub-agent, who again acted as secretary, and published the proceedings. These proceedings amounted to a renewed declaration that no lands should be sold. During all this period and previously, from the fall of 1823, the committee have no doubt of there having been on foot an active, continued, and steady system of measures throughout that country by the emissaries of the agent, in concert with the hostile Indians, to forestall and defeat the views of the United States Government; and in doing so, to sacrifice the interests of Georgia, and even the safety and welfare of the Indians themselves. The constant and intimate intercourse that must, we suppose, necessarily exist between the Agent and his sub-agent, predisposes us to presume a concert of action between them. And when we see that the active and continued treachery of the latter is known to the former, and no measures are taken either to restrain such conduct, to make it known, or avert its tendencies, the presumption of their being confederates becomes almost irresistible. The Agent's conduct at the first treaty was in exact accordance with the views we impute to him. His assumed neutrality on that occasion, even if he was in fact neutral, was a wilful departure from duty; and if, as your committee believe, his neutrality was only assumed, it was superadding duplicity to crime. It appears that these facts, or most of them, were in due time made known to the government. A removal of the sub-agent was all the remedy that was applied. His place was soon filled and it is understood at the instance of the Agent) by the present incumbent, who had already earned the Agent's confidence by a similarity of views, and particularly by an opposition sufficiently violent to any present cession of territory. His predecessor doubtless remained there to continue his machinations in secret: so that the only effect of

<page id="GA1825.2.P38" no="GA1825.2.39" />

the measure, however well intended, is to add one more to the number of those petty [Illegible Text], who oppress and harrass the nation, or that part of it who have lavished their blood for the American people.</p><p>On receiving the renewed and still more peremptory orders of his government, the Agent was compelled apparently to co-operate with the Commissioners at the second treaty. But in his talk to the Indians, it is curious to observe with what art he keeps within the letter and out of the spirit of his instructions. He had acknowledged to Maj. Merriwether, that the proposal for their removal beyond the Mississippi would, if acceded to, be highly to their advantage; that they would be fools if they did not accept it. But when addressing the Indians, he draws himself carefully within the shell of his instructions, and nothing appears but what is rigidly official. He is instructed, he says, by the War Department to tell them so and so. That what the Commissioners had told them was all the talk of the President. That the President wished them to sell their lands and go beyond the Mississippi. That it was his wish also, because it was the President's wish. And that if he was continued Agent, <i>he would go with them</i> and be their friend. Perhaps it was impossible for human ingenuity to have suggested to the imaginations of that assembly a greater curse than his friendship, or a stronger argument against removal than the prospect of being accompanied by him. When, however, nothing could stem the current; when nothing that could be said or done in the council or out of it, could prevent that consummation so devoutly dreaded, and all or nearly all the chiefs had agreed to sign the treaty on the next day, and that instrument was actually preparing, no time was indeed to be lost. At that critical instant a desperate measure is resorted to. A considerable number of the chiefs are sent away that night! Hambly was the visible agent in this deed. The same man who the Commissioners informed the government was unworthy of confidence, but who remained, and we believe is still the confidential friend and interpreter of the Agent, was the bearer of this <i>order,</i> as it was called, and of the ridiculous falsehoods that induced them to obey it. We cannot doubt that this man Hambly, is the devoted, implicit instrument of the Agent. His situation of Interpreter itself

<page id="GA1825.2.P39" no="GA1825.2.40" />

implies it. But (to take one instance among many that are scattered through the evidence) when we hear this mere [Illegible Text] tell Col Williamson, that he (Hambly) was the proxy of the upper chiefs, and invested with the power to sell or retain their patrimonial territorya power that they denied to so many of their principal chiefs, whom they have even attempted to murder, and some of whom they have actually murdered, for executingwhen we hear him, moreover, boasting of having defeated the treaty at Broken Arrow, and darkly hinting to William son, that Crowell being continued in his agency or not would decide him (Hambly) how to wield this tremendous authority, two conclusions force themselves upon us [Illegible Text]. That he has neither any regard for truth, or [Illegible Text] in a lie: and secondly, that he is devoted body and soul to his patron. We see that he is formed of materials base enough for any deed of darkness, but that he has not the talent himself to contrive the means.</p><p>The treaty was however signed by those who remained, being fifty-two in number of the chiefs, head men and warriors of the nation; and [Illegible Text] among others by the Agent himself, and in his official capacity. It is well known that on the next day he denounced to his government, the Commissioners and the treaty; the former as having transcended their instructions; and the latter as being a [Illegible Text] for the want of the signatures of those very chiefs who had thus been sent away: and it is equally notorious that he followed on to Washington himself, at the heels of his protest, for the avowed purpose of preventing the ratification of the treaty. By those two acts alone he stands recorded in this dilemma. He has either officially sanctioned a pretended treaty, which is all a lie; or he has endeavored to defeat one that was legal in its form, and which in its substance provided for objects that he had previously acknowledged to be just and benevolent.</p><p>The motive of the Agent for such an obstinate opposition to the acquirement of territory by Georgia, <i>within this year and the last,</i> is believed to be almost universally understood in this community. In the evidence the committee find traces of it in the occasional insinuations, more or less distinct, of the confidential associates of the Agent. It is to be seen they think in the whole course of Walker's conduct while he was Sub-Agent; in that of Triplett before

<page id="GA1825.2.P40" no="GA1825.2.41" />

he was Sub-Agent, as proved by the testimony of [Illegible Text], and since he has been in that office as stated by twenty four of the chiefs and Indians at Newnan, in the violent declarations of Henry Crowell, who trades in the nation under licence of his brother, the Agent, as proved by Colonel James Blair and Harris Allen. Esq. as well as in the language held by Hambly, the interpreter to [Illegible Text]. Williamson. But as we have in this case the avowal of the Agent himself, we should not advert to these acts or sayings of his subalterns but for this purpose. That if an unity of purpose and concert in action between him and them should be here satisfactorily made out, he ought to be affected by their sayings and doings in instances where he has kept himself out of view. Otherwise it is plain that he ought not to be prejudiced by any thing that they may have said or done. His own avowal above alluded to, is found in the disclosures of the Commissioners in their recent examination. He had, it seems, during the administration of the preceding Governor, zealously bestirred himself, and had in fact obtained the consent of the Indians to a cession of a part of their territory. He did not then labour under any of those misconceptions of his duty. which are so indulgently imputed to him in the letter from the late Secretary of War. But the executive administration of this state having passed into hands that he did not approve, his maxims of office were suddenly changed. He instantly resolved to use the influence which his office gave him in preventing the present administration from being in any way concerned in, or indeed, from being cotemporary with so important a service. He had prepared the Indians, he said, to cede a part of their lands, he had the matter fixed for a cession of the lands, it was understood, below the Federal road, distinctly intimating however, (says Major Merriwether, in which he is corroborated by Colonel Campbell,) that as Troup had been elected Governor, he must not expect success to attend any application which might be made to the Indians, while he (Troup) was in office. Anticipating probably that repeated failures would effect a change in the politics of the state, and bring into the executive chair at the next election, a man of his own choice, he intended doubtless in that event to be more propitious. Accordingly we find it intimated to the chiefs who were sent away from the

<page id="GA1825.2.P41" no="GA1825.2.42" />

[Illegible Text] at Broken Arrow, that they were to meet there again in a few months. And in his protest against the treaty, he states to the late Secretary of War his belief, that <i>at no distant day</i> a treaty could be made to the entire satisfaction of the government. Your committee offer no comment on this! They trust there can be but one sentiment on this subject, from the foregoing very rapid view of the case, if it is a fair one, and we believe it is. Of this, however, a judgment may be formed from the evidence itself. That part of it which the committee have collected, is herewith reported, so that the whole of it is before the house Your committee allow no weight (for certainly none ought to be allowed) to any evidence that is not as yet brought home, at least by fair presumption to the Agent. Those numerous collateral circumstances that are scattered through it, will be taken, it is hoped, at their true weight, and no more; recollecting on the one hand that they generally tend to corroborate and support what they do not distinctly prove; and on the other hand, that such of it as has been collected by the committee is necessarily <i>ex parte;</i> and that it cannot be now know how much of it the Agent may be able to controvert or explain.</p><p>Taking the evidence collected by the committee with these cautions and deductions, which can however hardly tend to impair the effect of the [Illegible Text] your committee think they see enough evidence, which they deem incontrovible, to satisfy the General Government on the question of the Agent's longer continuance in office; whether considered either as a question merely of justice to him, or policy to the country.Whatever doubts may heretofore have existed in the mind of the executive, we trust will shortly be dispelled. And that a clemency that has been over indulgent and mistaken in its extent, and which has in its operation been cruelty to the Indians, and that has operated as an unkindness, next to insult to Georgia, will no longer be suffered to be thus abused.</p><p>On the second branch of the reference, that which relates to the conduct of the Agent, in respect to the death of General McIntosh and others, your committee will premise the notoriety of the fact, that there had existed for some years, a deep and rooted enmity between them.This state of feeling is indicated in the Agent's letter to [Illegible Text] of the 22d August, 1823. We find it asserted

<page id="GA1825.2.P42" no="GA1825.2.43" />

in a letter from Samuel Hawkins to the Governor, that the Agent advised the Indians to assemble, and burn down the houses and destroy the property of McIntosh. Jesse Cox testifies, that on the 20th of April, the Agent in speaking of the Indians, used the following wordsdamned cowards, I always hated them; I still hate them worse and worse. Any people that would suffer one man to sell their nation, ought to die and go to hell. I once put that fellow (meaning McIntosh,) down, where he ought to remain; but the Big Warrior and Little Prince reinstated him. I hope the Big Warrior is now in hell for it, and that the Little Prince may soon follow him. Abraham Miles swears that on the 27th of April, the Agent told him that McIntosh would certainly be killed by the Indians opposed to the treaty, and on the 30th of that month he was murdered. We are informed in a letter of his wives, of the 3d of May, that the leaders in that transaction declared they were supported and encouraged in the murder by the Agent and the Chiefs; and it appears by the affidavit of Francis Flournoy, that one of those wives gave him the same account on the morning of the murder. Another of the party told Flournoy, that the chiefs were sincere when they sent their peaceful answer to the Governor, (by Colonel [Illegible Text]) but that the Agent had altered it, and told the council that the only way to get the land back and keep it, was to kill all that had been concerned in selling it. In giving their reasons for the act to Hawkins' widow, she says, they included the name of Walker the former sub-agent, as having also given them this advice. Kennedy testifies that a rather dark complectioned man whom they called Col. Crowell, in speaking of the Indians on the Sunday before, (the 28th May,) said damn them I wish more of them had been killed, for the balance would have been more easily managed. This witness has since seen the Agent, and has since told some of the members of the committee that he is now satisfied as to the identity of his person. These are imposing factsbut your committee would again remark, that the evidence being <i>ex parte,</i> should be received with much allowance. On the whole, your committee does not see in the evidence, sufficient proof to justify them in presuming that the Agent ordered, contrived, or instigated the murder of General McIntosh; but until the contrary shall be made to appear,

<page id="GA1825.2.P43" no="GA1825.2.44" />

they must fully believe that he knew of the approaching event, and could have prevented it: and hence, as well as from the general tenor of the testimony, they are compelled to infer that it had his approbation.</p><p>The Indians probably derived encouragement and confidence from their <i>belief</i> of the Agent's approbation, which they would naturally infer from his silence and inactivity. It is believed that if the Agent had been removed from office last January, General McIntosh would have now been in life.</p><p>Before dismissing the subject, it is proper to notice an insinuation of the Agent (for he does not positively assert it) to the Department of War, that the intended survey of the lately acquired territory was the immediate cause of the late troubles in the nation, and of the death of Gen. McIntosh and his friends. The committee hardly need to advert to the testimony of Miles and of Flournoy, to prove the contrary. All the evidence connected with the subject, within the recollection of the committee, and even a certificate of certain Indians lately published for another purpose by the Agent, concur to disprove his charge. We submit the import of the whole to be, that it was said by the hostiles, and we believe by the Agent himself, that the chiefs were killed in pursuance of a law which they pretended was made at the Pole Cat Spring; and which they resolved to put in execution on hearing of the ratification of the treaty.</p><p>The total effect that should be allowed to all the evidence must, and will of course be estimated variously.But without going beyond what is found on the files of the War Department; in the Agent's own acts, in the official correspondence, and in his own distinct avowals, your committee feel assured of the conclusions that are embodied in the following resolution, and which they therefore recommend to the consideration of the House.</p><p><i>Resolved by the Senate and House of</i> R<i>epresentatives of the State of Georgia, in General Assembly met, and it is hereby resolved as the sense of the same,</i> That the present Agent of Indian Affairs for the Creek nation has heretofore, at least since the fall of 1823, been regardless alike of his duties to the General Government and of the well being of the Indians under his charge. That the

<page id="GA1825.2.P44" no="GA1825.2.45" />

very considerable power in his hands of affecting the interest of this state has been prostituted to purposes unworthy in themselves and foreign from the objects of his appointment. That in the opinion of this Legislature, objects of private interest, and purposes arising in the strife of state politics have mainly influenced and governed his conduct, and that he has hence been either the advocate or the opponent of the rights of this state, as those rights have happened from time to time, to coincide with, or stand opposed to, the private advantage of him or his friends, and his political predilections; to which in the opinion of this Legislature he has long been, and now is willing to sacrifice the interests of the general government and the happiness and safety of the Creek Indians. That his continuance in office hitherto has been, and hereafter will be greatly to the injury of this state, and that the confidence of a large part of the Creek nation is now so irrecoverably alienated from him that it would hereafter be impossible for him to administer and superintend their affairs to their advantage and comfort, even if he was disposed so to do. And that this Legislature do request of the President of the United States to remove the said Agent from office. And to the end that all due and proper proof of his delinquency may be made.</p><p><i>Be it further resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor do appoint two or more fit and proper persons to collect and receive evidence therein, and that such persons when so appointed by his Excellency the Governor, shall be invested with all the power of sending for persons and papers, and of examining witnesses, that is vested in either or both houses of this Legislature.</p><p><i>And be it further resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to transmit to the President of the United States a copy of this report, resolution, and the accompanying documents, or such parts thereof as are not now in possession of the President.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P45" no="GA1825.2.46" />

<law id="R1825V2N029" initial.page="46"><shorttitle><b>IN SENATE,</b> June 9, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That both branches of the General Assembly will convene in the Representative Chamber this day at 4 o'clock, for the purpose of electing a brigadier-general to fill the vacancy occasioned by the resignation of brigadier-general Edmund Shackleford of the first brigade of the third division.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 9, 1825.</approvaldate></law></part>

<page id="GA1825.2.P46" no="GA1825.2.47" type="INFERRED" />

<part><title><b>Resolutions</b><br set="CENTER">WHICH ORIGINATED<br set="CENTER">ON THE<br set="CENTER"><b>HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES.</b><br set="CENTER" /></br></br></br></title><law id="R1825V2N030" initial.page="47" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 6, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be and he is hereby authorised and requested to take forthwith efficient measures to protect the Georgia frontier against the depredations or encroachments of the Greek Indians by calling out a sufficient military force for that purpose if found necessary.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 8, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N031" initial.page="47" type="INFERRED"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 6, 1825.</shorttitle><p>The committee to whom was referred the report of two of the commissioners of the Ocmulgee Navigation Company have had the same under consideration, and are of opinion that from the want of testimony they are not enabled to make satisfactory enquiry into the conduct of the commissioners or any member thereof.</p><p>Your committee therefore beg leave to recommend the following resolution, viz:</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the commissioners of the Ocmulgee Navigation Company do make a full and complete report to the next annual session of the Legislature of all their

<page id="GA1825.2.P47" no="GA1825.2.48" />

actings and doings, and particularly the situation of the river, their progress in clearing out the same, their disbursements of the public money, the expenses incident thereto, what money in hand, what due, and also if any fraud has been practised by any individual as to the public money, by whom, in what way, and to what extent.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N032" initial.page="48"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 2, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be authorised to purchase for the use of the militia of this state six hundred copies of Scott's Military Discipline, or such other code of military tactics as may be deemed best suited to the militia system.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N033" initial.page="48"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 6, 1825.</shorttitle><p>Whereas, it was a practice among the inhabitants of the colony and province of Georgia, to publish from time to time, authentic accounts of their condition:</p><p>And whereas, it would be highly expedient to revive a custom, which would result in benefits not to present residents of the state only, but even perhaps to their most remote posterity. Therefore</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the justices of the Inferior courts be, and they are hereby requested to furnish his Excellency the Governor for the use of the citizen appointed to collate the historical documents, on or before the first Monday in November next, with information generally respecting their several counties, and particularly as to the following points:</p>

<page id="GA1825.2.P48" no="GA1825.2.49" />

<p><list><item><p>1. The soiltogether with the nature, quality and quantity of its produce.</p></item><item><p>2. Trade and manufactures.</p></item><item><p>3. Natural historyin a comprehensive sense.</p></item><item><p>4. Natural and artificial curiosities.</p></item><item><p>5. Internal Improvements from one period of time to another</p></item><item><p>6. Peculiar settlements, their origin and subsequent history.</p></item><item><p>7. Academies and other schools; together with the state of learning generally.</p></item><item><p>8. Various sects of religionremoved or existing.</p></item><item><p>9. Manners, habits and amusements of the people.</p></item></list></p><p><i>Resolved also,</i> That the justices aforesaid be, and they are hereby requested to associate with them, in their respective counties, such distinguished citizens as they may deem proper.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 18, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N034" initial.page="49"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> May 28, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the treasurer of this state be required to receive Darien money in payment of all debts due the public, and in fulfilment of all contracts to which the state may be a party:and that in disbursements, there be paid out an equal proportion of Darien money and other current bills.</p><approvaldate>Approved, May 31, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N035" initial.page="49"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> May 30, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That both branches of the Legislature meet in the Representative Chamber to morrow at 12 o'clock, to elect a brigadier general to fill the vacancy in the first brigade, second division Georgia militia, occasioned by the promotion of Gen. W. W. Montgomery.</p><approvaldate>Approved, May 31, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P49" no="GA1825.2.50" />

<law id="R1825V2N036" initial.page="50"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 8, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That our thanks be tendered to his Excellency the Governor and the United States commissioners Col. D. G. Campbell and Major J. Merriwether, for the firmness, perseverance, zeal and patriotism which they have displayed in procuring a session of territory, so favorable to the interest of Georgia. Our thanks are also endered to his excellency the Governor for his active and patriotic efforts in expediting the settlement of said territory</p><p><i>Resolved further,</i> That copies of this resolution be transmitted to Messrs. Campbell and Merriwether.</p><p><b>JOHN ABERCROMBIE,</b> <i>Speaker.</i></p><p><b>IN SENATE,</b> 8th June, 1825.</p><p>Read and concurred in.</p><p><b>ALLEN B. POWELL,</b> <i>President.</i></p><approvaldate /></law><law id="R1825V2N037" initial.page="50"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 6, 1825.</shorttitle><p>The committee of finance to whom has been referred the petition of William Triplett, comptroller general, make the following Report:</p><p>After carefully examining the additional duties enjoined on him by a resolution of the last General Assembly requiring a final adjustment of tax collectors' accounts from the year eighteen hundred up to that time, believe him entitled to adequate compensation. Therefore offer the following resolution:</p><p><i>Resolved,</i> That the sum of five hundred dollars be, and is hereby appropriated and set apart for that purpose and paid to the comptroller out of any monies now in the treasury unappropriated.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P50" no="GA1825.2.51" />

<law id="R1825V2N038" initial.page="51"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 7, 1825.</shorttitle><p>Whereas it appears by the examination of the report of the person appointed by the late Executive to make a numerical book of the drawing of the land lottery of eighteen hundred and twenty, that there are a number of cases where two persons appear to have drawn the same lot, and it being probable from the same report that one of said persons drew a different lot, reported to be blank, and afterwards improperly disposed of by the lottery of eighteen hundred and twenty one; and it further appearing that all such cases were intended to be provided for by the resolution of the eleventh of May, eighteen hundred and twenty one. For remedy whereof,</p><p><i>Be it resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor appoint some fit person to examine into all such cases and report the same in order that all such drawers may have a chance in the approaching land lottery who may thus have been deprived of the lots to which they were justly entitled.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N039" initial.page="51"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 10, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved,</i> That five hundred copies of the report and the evidence on which it is founded be published for the use of the members of the General Assembly, and that the same be distributed among them in proportion to the representation from the different counties.</p><p><i>And be it further resolved,</i> That his Excellency the Governor be requested to furnish the Special Agent of the General Government with a copy of said report together with authenticated copies of the various documents and testimony accompanying the same, to be laid before his Government.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P51" no="GA1825.2.52" />

<law id="R1825V2N040" initial.page="52"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 11, 1825.</shorttitle><p>R<i>esolved.</i> That the joint committee on printing cause to be forwarded by mail to each member of the legislature four copies of the documents ordered to be printed for the use of the legislature, which may not be delivered before the adjournment of this session, and the Governor is hereby requested to pay the expense of transmission out of the contingent fund.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N041" initial.page="52"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 8, 1825.</shorttitle><p><i>Resolved by the Senate and House of</i> R<i>epresentatives of the State of Georgia in General Assembly met,</i> That his excellency the Governor be requested to employ some suitable person to examine a route for a canal and road, or either to connect the waters of the Gulf of Mexico and the waters of the Atlantic, and to report on the practicability of the same to the next session of the legislature, the advantages and probable expenses.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N042" initial.page="52"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 8, 1825.</shorttitle><p>Whereas from the petition of Mansel Smith and Nancy Smith, widow of the late Thomas Smith, it appears that Mansel Smith became security for Thomas Smith to answer in the Superior court of Walton county to a charge of perjury. And it appearing from the documents accompanying the petition that the said Thomas Smith departed this life before the decision of said case so that his appearance at court was rendered impracticable, netwithstanding which the court suffered a judgment to be entered up against the survivor Mansel Smith, who is now likely to be distressed by the levying of an execution on his property. To prevent so great an injustice, it is hereby</p>

<page id="GA1825.2.P52" no="GA1825.2.53" />

<p><i>Resolved,</i> That his excellency the Governor be, and he is hereby directed to cause full satisfaction to be entered on the judgment or execution aforesaid, so that the said Mansel Smith may be entirely relieved from the penalty arising from said judgment.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N043" initial.page="53"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> May 27, 1825.</shorttitle><p>R<i>esolved,</i> That both branches of the General Assembly will convene in the Representative Chamber at 3 o'clock, this day, for the purpose of holding an election to fill the vacancy occasioned by the resignation of Major General V. Walker of the second division of Georgia militia.</p><approvaldate>Approved, May 27, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N044" initial.page="53"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HSOUE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 8, 1825.</shorttitle><p>R<i>esolved,</i> That the Senate and House of Representatives do convene in the representative chamber on to-morrow morning at 9 o'clock, for the purpose of electing a judge of the middle [Illegible Text] in lieu of the Hon; Robert Walker, resigned; a judge of the southern circuit in lieu of the Hon. Thomas W. Harris, resigned; and a solicitor-general of the southern circuit, in lieu of Thaddeus G. Holt, Esq. promoted.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 9, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N045" initial.page="53"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June, 9, 1825.</shorttitle><p>R<i>esolved,</i> That both branches of the General Assembly convene in the representative chamber on to-morrow morning at 8 o'clock for the purpose of electing one hundred district surveyors, and ten sectional surveyors in conformity to the provisions of the act disposing of and distributing the late acquired territory.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 10, 1825.</approvaldate></law>

<page id="GA1825.2.P53" no="GA1825.2.54" />

<law id="R1825V2N046" initial.page="54"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 9, 1825.</shorttitle><p>R<i>esolved,</i> That both branches of the General Assembly convene in the representative chamber at 8 o'clock, A. M. on to morrow for the purpose of electing five commissioners to superintend the drawing of the approaching land lottery.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 10, 1825.</approvaldate></law><law id="R1825V2N047" initial.page="54"><shorttitle><b>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES,</b> June 11, 1825.</shorttitle><p>Whereas it appears that Elihu Atwater became security to Wm Scott, tax collector of the county of Camden, for the collection and payment to the state of the taxes for said county for the years 1808, 1809, 1810, 1812,and further, that he became also bound for the collection of the taxes for 1813 and 1814.</p><p>And whereas it further appears that said Elihu did cause to be paid to the sheriff the sum of $1,109 92, which has been placed to his credit on the executions of the years 1808, 1809, 1810, 1812, issued against said collector and his said security which draw no interest, instead of the executions of 1813 and 1814 which draw interest, in consequence of which said Elihu is left liable to pay interest for an amount not otherwise drawing interest; and it being desirable that persons paying the state money on security should not be denied the most favorable terms allowable by law</p><p><i>Be it resolved,</i> That the comptroller-general do place the amount paid the state as aforesaid by Elihu Atwater to his credit on executions bearing interest.</p><p><i>And be it further resolved,</i> That the said Elihu Atwater be allowed by the comptroller general an extension of the time of said executions to the first day of January, 1827, on his giving such additional security as may [Illegible Text] necessary to the comptroller-general, and on his placing all the amount now due on interest from this date.</p><approvaldate>Approved, June 11, 1825.</approvaldate></law></part></body>

<page id="GA1825.2.P54" no="GA1825.2.52" type="INFERRED" />

<backmatter><index><title><b>INDEX.</b><br set="CENTER" /></title><indexentry><i>Augusta</i>city council of, authorised to negotiate a loan, <pagenbr>16</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Appling</i> countyelection districts in, established, <pagenbr>17</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Academy</i> Salemlottery for the benefit of the, authorised, <pagenbr>20</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> Act, <pagenbr>29</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Alabama</i> and Georgiaconcerning their boundary line. <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> of [Illegible Text] countycommissioners for the, appointed, <pagenbr>33</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> for Indian Affairsreport on his conduct, <pagenbr>35</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> Elihuresolution in his favor, <pagenbr>54</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text] General</i>resolution for the election of, <pagenbr>46</pagenbr>, <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Bank Bills</i>resolution concerning their reception and disbursement at the treasury, <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> Thomas S.resolution in favor of, <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i>on Alatamaha, resolution concerning, <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> Johnreport of the committee on the state of the republic concerning, <pagenbr>35</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Counties</i>information concerning all the, to be collected by the Inferior Court, <pagenbr>48</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Commissioners</i> of Indian Treaty, thanks of the legislature to, <pagenbr>50</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Comptroller general</i>resolution in favor of <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text] and Road</i>between Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Drows</i>fraudulent, <pagenbr>22</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Documents</i>authorised to be printed, <pagenbr>31</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Darien Bills</i>to be received at the treasury, <pagenbr>49</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Drows</i> in the late land lottery, resolution concerning, <pagenbr>51</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Documents</i>to be distributed by mail to members, <pagenbr>51</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Election districts</i> in Appling and Irwin counties established, <pagenbr>17</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i>incurred in the reception of Lafayette, resolution concerning, <pagenbr>34</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i>exempted from militia duty, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text] draws</i>time of returning limited, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text],</i> c.purchasers of relieved, <pagenbr>26</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i>name of, changed to Gunn, <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> and Georgiaconcerning their boundary line, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> countyconcerning the roads in, <pagenbr>22</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i>causes in the inferior court of, authorised to be tried, <pagenbr>25</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>[Illegible Text] Interior court of, authorised to remit a fine, <pagenbr>25</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text],</i> Alabama and Floridaconcerning their boundary lines, <pagenbr>32</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i>authorised to purchase portraits <pagenbr>34</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to make arrangements for the defence of the frontier, <pagenbr>47</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Requested to procure copies of Scott's Military Discipline, <pagenbr>18</pagenbr></indexentry>

<page id="GA1825.2.P55" no="GA1825.2.26" />

<indexentry><i>Governor</i>Thanks of the legislature to, <pagenbr>50</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Authorised to employ persons to examine the route for a canal and road between the Atlantic and Gulf of Mexico. <pagenbr>52</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Hall</i>name of persons so called changed to Hardage, <pagenbr>27</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Harrison</i>name changed to Williams, <pagenbr>28</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Irwin</i> countyelection districts in, established, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Inferior</i> court of Gwinnett countyauthorised to try [Illegible Text] causes, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Authorised to remit a fine, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Indian</i> Affairsreport of the committee on the state of [Illegible Text] on, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Report, c. to be printed and circulated, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Inferior</i> courtsrequired to perform certain duties, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Land Lottery</i> Act, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Lottery</i> for Salem academy, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Land lotteries</i>time limited for the return of [Illegible Text] [Illegible Text] in the, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Line</i>between Florida, Alabama and Georgia, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Laws and Journals</i>to be distributed as soon as possible, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Lafayette</i>resolution concerning the expenses of the reception [Illegible Text] <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Land lottery</i> of 1820resolution concerning draws in, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> Andrew J.authorised to plead and practice law, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i> dutyferrymen excused from performing, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Maps</i> in surveyor general's office to be copied, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Merriwether and Campbell</i>thanks presented to, as U. S. Commissioners, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Names</i> of certain persons changed, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Ocmulgee</i> Navigationcommissioners of, authorised to [Illegible Text] with Hardiman, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry>Navigationcommissioners of, required to report to [Illegible Text] legislature, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Poor School Fund</i>Inferior courts authorised to draw for <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Purchasers</i> of fractions c. an act for their relief, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Printing</i> of documents authorised, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Portraits</i> to be purchased, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Printing</i> of report and evidence in Crowell's case authorised, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Roads.</i> in Glynn countyan act concerning, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Steen</i> Geo.a fine incurred by, authorised to be remitter <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Surveyor general</i>authorised to copy maps of districts, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Smith</i> Manselresolution in favor of <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>Terrell</i> James C. authorised to plead and practise law <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry><indexentry><i>[Illegible Text]</i>an act to incorporate, <pagenbr>[Illegible Text]</pagenbr></indexentry></index></backmatter></document></galaw>
